The American Diabetes Association plays a crucial role in shaping diabetes care worldwide.
It's standards of care set the gold standard for diabetes treatment and technology recommendations,
influencing insurance coverage here in the US and providing essential guidance for both physicians and patients.
These guidelines help ensure that the latest advancements in diabetes management are
Accessibles to those who need it most. Welcome to the show. I'm just and I have type 1 diabetes and on here.
I talk off things diabetes tech news and management. Now, one of the most exciting
Recommendations that has come out of the ADA standards of care most recently is a recommendation that all people with type 2 diabetes
Regardless of insulin use should have access to continuous glucose monitors. This shift could have a massive impact on diabetes care
Expanding access to a tool that has already transformed management for so many people of diabetes.
Today, I'm joined by Dr. Gracia Aleppo, a professor of medicine at Northwestern
Universities Division of Endocrinology, Metabolism and Molecular Medicine.
With over 23 years as an adult endocrinologist, she has dedicated her career to diabetes care,
especially in the realm of diabetes technology. In this episode, we dive into her work at the ADA,
how an idea moves through the organization from conception to the standards of care. The rating system
behind each new recommendation, we also get into the ADA's recent recommendation that health care providers
support patients who are considering DIY. Uncleared algorithms, like those I've talked about on this show,
whether it be trio DIY loop or Android APS. Dr. Aleppo is just as passionate about diabetes
technology as I am. Maybe even more, and you'll hear that through her voice. Keep in mind that
anything you hear on this show or any of my pages is not medical advice and it's for educational purposes
only always consult with a physician before making changes to your health care. Now for the conversation.
Gracia, welcome to the show. It's so good to have you here. Thank you so much, Justin,
for having me here today. I'm excited to be here with you today. So I'm Gracia Leipop,
I'm a professor of medicine, a division of endocrinology, metabolism, molecular medicine,
and Northwestern University in Chicago. I've been working as adult endocrinologists for about 23 years now
and I dedicate my career to diabetes, particular diabetes, and technology. For the last three years,
I've been working with the ADA professional practice committee to work on the standards of care.
And I was assigned to be the lead, the chair of the diabetes technology section which is chapter 7.
The ADA is something I hear about all the time, but I don't actually know that much about it. So when
the opportunity came about to have you on the show to talk about not just the ADA, but the