Hey guys, welcome to my Apple iPad keyboard review and comparison video.
So if I've had this keyboard since Christmas and I absolutely love it,
I'm also going to be comparing that keyboard to the Logitech keyboards,
the rugged folio, and the slim folio.
For the purposes of this video, I'm using my iPad 10.2 inch,
but Apple and Logitech make keyboards for all of the different iPads.
I'm going to be sure to put links to all of these products in the description below.
Alright, let's do this.
The iPad keyboard is sleek, compact, and light.
It connects via the smart connector on your iPad,
meaning there's no need to connect via Bluetooth or charge the keyboard.
It's instantly powered by and connected to the iPad.
The keyboard doubles as a smart cover, and magnetically folds and covers your iPad,
creating a slim ultra portable package.
The keyboard's made of a plastic material, and it's supposedly water resistant.
But Apple doesn't market it as such.
It should be fine if it gets a little wet.
It only comes in this great color, which is a bit of a bummer.
I'd love some cute color options.
The keyboard keys are small, but after just a few minutes of getting used to, they feel comfortable.
The keys have a great tactile response and are extremely quiet.
So like I said, the keyboard's really quiet.
And I just want to show you how quiet the keyboard actually is.
I'm going to use these fingers.
I'm going to turn here.
I'm going to type them on the keyboard right here.
So there you go.
I will say occasionally the space part doesn't react,
and that's because it needs a bit of a more forceful push.
This hasn't really been a big issue for me since my iPad corrects my grammar anyway.
You can also prop up the iPad in a steeper position for watching video,
or using the iPad as a second display for your laptop.
While I'm on that topic, I just posted a video on how to use your iPad as a second display,
to watch that just click that link right up there in the top corner.
The lack of a trackpad isn't really an issue here.
I don't find that I need it for my iPad workflow, but if I really need a mouse, I can connect one V of
Bluetooth. I like how little room the keyboard takes up, and I feel comfortable using it in a small space.
The keyboard seems to be meant for mainly using on surfaces.
I've used it on my laptop a bit, and while it's not horrible, the iPad is a bit shaky,
and it's not ideal.
Oh, and on the complete opposite side of the spectrum, if you're using it on a metal table,
that keyboard is going to be very secure.
So secure that you can't easily move it, which I actually found helpful as soon as I found a good position for it.
And this is a huge plus for me, because I live in Los Angeles where the big earthquake can hit
at any time, and I'm going to be set because if I'm using that iPad keyboard on a metal table,
it won't go anywhere. Thanks Apple!
And lastly, I'm going to tell you now this keyboard isn't cheap. It's $159 on Apple's website,
and I found it for $143 on Amazon, so I threw that link in the description below.
Now let's get into the keyboard abilities.
To my surprise, all of the hot keys that you're used to on Mac are present here on the iPad.
So to figure out what hot keys you can use, you just hold down a command on any app or the home screen,
and it shows you what you can do. So right here, it's showing me what I can do. I can do command spacebar,
and I can search for apps. I can go to pages, let's say, and I hold down command, and it shows me
all of the hot keys I can use here. And then when I click in, it'll show me more. Right there, bold,
command, I as I tell it. And then if I want to switch between apps, I just do command tab,
then I'm switching between apps. So let me go into Safari. I can do command T for a new tab,
out. That hot key, burn me, top. Okay, back to this command H, we'll take me home, and in mail,
I can do command N, and I can do a new draft. If I go to I message, I can do command I, and sorry,
command N, and it's a new message. So hot keys are really awesome here. I find this to be a key feature,
pun intended. These hot keys make using the keyboard, and I've had a super enjoyable and productive
experience. Also, I just want to take a second to say how incredibly amazed I am by my iPad workflow.
Like this thing has completely changed my coffee shop work sessions. Yes, I am that guy that's in Starbucks,
or some sort of trendy cute coffee shop for hours. And you know what, I am not sorry about it,
because things can get super lonely here. My office literally has me. But if you want to be my
assistant for free, let me know right in the comments. Anyway, I can quickly swap between apps,
use apps side by side, and type out reviews, just like this one. And side note, I did type this entire
review on my iPad keyboard. If I wasn't a video editor, I could easily see myself using this as my
main computer. I'm able to complete most of my work tasks and write reviews, update logs and
Google sheets, and docs, and work on social media. I highly recommend the iPad and keyboard combo.
It's going to change your life. Now let's talk about the competing keyboards. The main
competitors in my view are the Logitech keyboards. Each keyboard has their own pros and cons, and it's
going to be up to you to decide which one suits your lifestyle most. Also, all those hot keys I showed
you earlier, any keyboard you connect to your iPad will have them. First, there's the rugged
folio, which goes for $140. The keyboard is water and dirt resistant, and the case is shock absorbent.
Hence the name, rugged. The keyboard connects via the smart connectors well, so it is instantly powered
and connected to your iPad. The keyboard keys are slightly larger than apples, and feel closer to a
laptop keyboard. There's less of a tactile response, but I personally like it. The keys are quiet, soft,
and a little more flat. We're back for another session of tech ASMR. All right here. We have
the Logitech rocket folio. There's a row of short cut keys on top, which make it super easy to
adjust settings. These are missed on Apple's keyboard. The only issue I have is with the Logitech.
I keep on accidentally pushing it when I'm trying to hit delete, it's really annoying. I wish there
was a way to just turn this off because I don't even find it necessary. The case has a kick stand that
allows for a bunch of different setups, but it does take up more room, and you can't use it on your lab.
It weighs much more than the Apple keyboard, and it's three times as thick. As someone who already
carries a laptop, I don't personally really need another heavy-duty piece of equipment on me.
But don't get me wrong. This is a great case. Next is the slim folio, which goes for $99. This keyboard
runs via Bluetooth, so you'll need to connect it to your iPad, and for the most part it should connect
whenever you turn it on. Logitech says the battery will last you four years until you need to replace it.
When typing the keys feel and sound much closer to a laptop.
Hey, I know you thought you got rid of me, but I'm back for one more session with these.
It's much more like a keyboard. You've also got that row of shortcut keys. Most notably, they
aren't water or dirt resistance, like the other two. So perhaps this is a buy-it-nice or buy-it twice
kind of moment. The case feels much cheaper and only has one setup. I find that the angle of the iPad
isn't ideal, but you can use it on your lap. There's also a dangling piece of fabric for an apple
pencil. So if you have an apple pencil, that's great. If you don't, not so great. The case is lighter
than the rugged, but more bulky and heavier than the apple keyboard. For me, it truly comes down to
the apple keyboard or logitech's rugged folio. If you're looking for a super lightweight keyboard
that also doubles as a protective case, then go with the apple keyboard. It feels great to type on
is versatile, sleek, and super compact, and you can easily fit it anywhere, just like in my
backpack's iPad slot. Oh, and if you like this backpack, I did a whole review on it and you should
check it out because it literally is amazing. So click that right there to see it. Now if you want to
heavy-duty case with lots of different angles and it's a little bulky, but you don't mind that,
then go with the rugged folio. Just know, the case is going to double the weight and triple the thickness
of your iPad. What it comes down to is I recommend you having a keyboard for your iPad,
what started out as an iPad keyboard review in comparison really turned out to be like an iPad
workflow recommendation. I love the way that the iPad's transform my workflow and just the ability to
have a super lightweight workstation with me, and I truly believe that anyone who only needs a limited
amount of apps and abilities on their laptop can really get away with using an iPad. And yeah,
the only downside here is price. They're a little expensive, but I think that they are a great investment
and what I'll do is I'm going to be updating the links down in the description over time as they get
cheaper in price. So be sure to check those out. There you guys have it. That is my iPad keyboard
review in comparison video. I hope you guys enjoyed it. If you guys have any keyboards that you love,
let me know in the comments below. I want to try them out. Anyway, I've got a lot more videos coming
away. How do you stay tuned for those? Subscribe right down there. Click the bell for alerts. And if you
like this video, give it a like. Right down there. I'm Justin. Oh my god, I'll take you later.
Is the zoom right? Yeah, tell me zoom in. Movie magic. I'm not this tall.
All right, let's get the next shot.