Hey everyone, it's Justin and I am obsessed with my Oculus Quest and you're going to be also
So here are the top five things that you have to try as soon as you open up that box
First things first subscribe to this channel. I have a ton more VR content coming out
And you don't want to miss it also follow me on social media. I have a cute face and I smile a lot
You won't want to miss the smiles. Oh, and I have giveaways first thing
There are a ton of free demos that you can try on this thing right out of the box the first one
And you have to do it. It's beat saver. This game is literally DDR meets Star Wars because you're holding two light savers
And you're moving around to the beat of the music and you are going up down to the sides dodging these walls
It is so much freaking fun and sort of great work out. I definitely bought the full game and it is really really great
It's $30 so definitely check that out another demo that is awesome is the space pirate trainer
This is like a shooter where you're shooting a bunch of drones in the air and you can change your weapons on each gun
And it's really really cool. I also got that full game and you'll probably want to as well
And it's $15 and the other demo that I think you really have to try out is called sports scramble
And I like to call this we sports on steroids this game gave me that same feeling that we sports gave me the first time I tried my
We sports cram was basically a bunch of different sports
But scramble you're playing tennis with a ping pong racket or a crooked thing of a jigger or a baseball bat
Also, it's really cool about sports cram is you could play online with it
I will be coming out with more videos on all of these games so stay tuned for that
All right the second thing this one comes from you guys and it's definitely true
I just left it out of one of my videos and it is VR adult content
It's actually really cool and
Life like you can put this thing on and believe that you are in a real-life
Sexy trust me actually if you don't believe me watch my friend Toby tried out for the first time
Oh my god
Whoa
There is already a ton of VR adult content available on the browser
You just have to google it so put like VR blank porn and a ton will come up
Literally next you'll have to check out these video content on this thing
Oculus is definitely pushing for people to watch movies and TV shows
They've added a TV icon which takes you to a home theater that basically acts as a hub for all of your TV apps and
Displace all the shows you're watching. There's also YouTube VR. There are a ton of YouTube videos that are 360 videos
I watched this solar clips and I felt like I was flying. It was amazing. Okay
The next thing you have to try out are multiplayer games. The Oculus quest is all about
Multiplayer and being social surprisingly because you're putting something over your face and
Leaving this world. There's a built-in mic and you can talk to people
There are a bunch of multiplayer games already available on the quest which I definitely plan on examining in another video
But real quick here's some fun ones
I already mentioned it, but sports crambles a ton of fun online. There's also rack of fury
Which is a super fun table tennis game, which I'm gonna be doing a video on soon and also having a giveaway on so stay tuned for that
There's also some social media experiences like big screen where you literally socialize with people around the world in a virtual reality chat room
Here you can see I went to a screening of John Wick 2 with a few other people
It was surreal
Skyrim and chair like kind of feels like a primitive ready player one and I am gonna recommend one game
And that is a Vader immortal. It's a Star Wars game
And this is a really cool game because you're set into a Star Wars story
It's kind of short. It's about like a 30 minute game, which yeah is super short
But you also get these really cool dojo training levels that get really difficult
And you're using a lightsaber in the whole time and defeating drones and droids. It's a lot of fun
And you also unlock levels and lightsabers along the way
So those are the top five things you have to try, but there is so much more. So that's why I'm creating so much more content
Stay tuned for that by subscribe to this channel follow me on social media for giveaways and just
Me being a goof. Please comment below with anything that you think that I need to try out because I need some good ideas
I already have some, but I want some more
Tell me and other than that. I'm Justin. I'll take you later