Why should people care about funding for the NIH, the National Institute of Health?
Pretty much everything we know about the disease and how to improve outcomes for patients
and families affected by type 1 has come through scientific discovery, much of which has been funded by
the National Institutes of Health and specifically one of the branches that's called the NIDDK,
which involves diabetes, kidneys, and digestive diseases.
Without that funding in partnership with the commercial world, we're not going to ever see
the things that people are hoping for, which is a cure and better treatments.
Yeah, and I just hear this family member in my head saying, well, let the rest of the world do it.
Why is the NIH specifically important in this? Why can't the rest of the world in their organizations do it?
Well, I think the reality is the many places in the world don't have the same expertise
and don't have the network set up to do it and don't have the wherewithal or the desire or the capital,
that it's even a possibility.
But I would come back to say, if you live with type 1 diabetes and you want things to be better for you or your family,
you need to support this kind of work because it's not going to get done.
Not everything has a direct, you know, profit-driven company-driven line.
Sometimes you just have to do the science for the sake of science.
And that's, I haven't even spoken about the basic science work.
You know, all the stuff that happens in the lab before something comes to me to be able to even offer to a patient and a research study,
let alone a commercially available drug, almost all that work is funded by the NIH.
And if it doesn't happen, all those opportunities for improving outcomes at the end of the day are going to go away,
and patients are going to suffer.
The problems as we have in the United States, we are blessed to be an incredible country that can do these things if we choose to do them.
It's just a matter of just turning where we're going to put our resources.
You need to support this kind of work because it's not going to get done.
Our government should be investing in our health.
We should want our dollars to go towards something like that.