The American Diabetes Association plays a crucial role in shaping diabetes care worldwide.
It's standards of care set the gold standard for diabetes treatment and technology recommendations,
influencing insurance coverage here in the US, and providing essential guidance for both physicians and patients.
These guidelines help ensure that the latest advancements in diabetes management are
accessible to those who need it most. Welcome to the show. I'm just and I have
typed one diabetes in on here. I tuck off things diabetes tech news and management. Now,
one of the most exciting recommendations that has come out of the ADA standards of care most recently
is a recommendation that all people with type 2 diabetes were guardless of insulin use
should have access to continuous glucose monitors. This shift could have a massive impact on
diabetes care, expanding access to a tool that has already transformed management for so many
people with diabetes. Today, I'm joined by Dr. Gracia Aleppo, a professor of medicine at
Northwestern University's Division of Endocrinology, Metabolism, and Molecular Medicine.
With over 23 years as an adult endocrinologist, she has dedicated her career to diabetes care,
especially in the realm of diabetes technology. In this episode, we dive into her work at the ADA,
how an idea moves through the organization from conception to the standards of care. The rating
system behind each new recommendation, we also get into the ADA's recent recommendation that health care
providers support patients who are considering DIY. Uncleared algorithms, like those I've talked about
on the show, whether it be trio DIY loop or Android APS. Dr. Aleppo is just as passionate about
diabetes technology as I am. Maybe even more, and you'll hear that through her voice. Keep in mind that
anything you hear on the show or any of my pages is not medical advice and it's for educational
purposes, only always consult with a physician before making changes to your health care. Now for the
conversation. Gratia, welcome to the show. It's so good to have you here. Thank you so much, Justin
for having me here today. I'm excited to be here with you today. So I'm Gratia Leipop, my professor of medicine
at the Division of Endocrinology Metabolism Molecular Medicine and Northwestern University in Chicago.
I've been working as adult endocrinologists for about 23 years now, and I dedicated my career to diabetes,
particular diabetes and technology. For the last three years, I've been working with the ADA Professional
Practice Committee to work on the standards of care, and I was assigned to be the lead
the chair of the diabetes technology section, which is chapter seven. The ADA is something I hear about
all the time, but I don't actually know that much about it. So when the opportunity came about to have
you on the show to talk about not just the ADA, but the standards of care, I got super excited and
I'm so happy to have you here. So let's start with the biggest news that's come out from the ADA,
which is the addition in the 2025 ADA standards of care. It now includes a recommendation for the
consideration of continuous glucose monitors for adults with type 2 diabetes, whether they're using
insulin or not. Tell us about what led to this addition. Not only that is there was a new recommendation
last year for type 2 people and adults that should use CGM when they use basal insulin, but we also decided
to look into people with type 2 diabetes, not on insulin. And so the newest recommendation is 7.16,
that says consider using CGM in adults with type 2 diabetes, not using insulin or on glucose
laboratory medication other than insulin. And this is a level of evidence great beat. So let me explain to
what that means. First of all, we felt that we should sort of put together and accumulate the
recommendation for CGM for people using insulin with a type 1 type 2 kids adults didn't matter.
So that is important because the data is so strong so we want to put that aside in just one and sort of
combine a few recommendations. And then we thought we need to do one for type 2, not using insulin. So we
had to look in the literature and there is growing evidence that there are benefits for people with type 2 using
CGM, not using insulin. And so we had to look into the growing research and growing papers
and they were able to say now we feel comfortable that it is efficient evidence to state that yes,
we should consider. Now why do we not use recommend? Because right now we don't have large randomized
control trials, we have some randomized control trial, a lot of retrospective information and some
perspectives. So we needed to make sure we use the right level of recommendation to mirror the
evidence that we have. And that's how we came up with the work consider and the evidence level B.
So how long were you considering this addition before you actually implemented it? How many trials and studies
did you need to see to be like okay we're confident that we're going to recommend to all people
with type 2 diabetes on insulin or not? So the challenge is that with the standards of care we have a
huge responsibility because it's not just for the US, this recommendation and the guidance I've read by
people all over the world. So when you make a statement you need to make sure you can support it with the
literature behind it. So I've been looking for the literature for the last two years and I'll remember
we prepared their guidelines the year before. So they're published December of let's say 2020,
4 for 2020, 5 but we start in March and so we need to accumulate evidence that has been already published
or can be published by let's say the deadline whatever changes every year. So we might not get to use it
because it was after the deadline. So you need to keep in mind that if you have an idea about what should
be put as a new recommendation to start gathering information sometimes it's a year before and so we want to
make sure that we wanted to put this recommendation out people need to understand that it doesn't take two days
to get this idea this year. So we need to have enough publication that make the recommendation solid.
So that's why it takes so long to put a recommendation. And within the standards of care you said like
at 16.7 there's a line that says this 7.16. Okay 7.16 okay I remember that oh I was close. So if I wanted to
learn more about how that got there is there a way to like click in there and then it shows you all
of the studies that were considered or that. Actually the studies are cited. So if you go to
the chapter 7 of the standards of care is diabetes technology you can see that every is the recommendation
isn't the in the in the in the pink and said but then in the text it tells you exactly what the studies
were the supported. So you can go to the reference the biography at the end of the chapter and see which studies
were used to make this statement. And there were several we had to sue the come up because again
that having two or three large randomized controlled trials we used everything available within the 12 to
maybe 12 months or so 18 months or so to bring their recommendation to life. So you need to really
dig into the literature and find the as much as possible but also as to be recent it cannot be five
years ago obviously. Okay so once these recommendations go into the standards of care what kind of
happens next with those who is that signaling how are people hearing about this who is keeping their ears
open for something like this. So there is a great amount of um tripidation expectation in December when
the guidelines get published online everybody weighs for the days what is doing we try to go
through the pages right but also the message is there to for other people's other people to read and we are
hoping that by putting the recommendation in the standards of care then there will be a follow-up of payers
because you see the job of the recommendation is to put it there is the literature supports it so it's a true
statement it's not because when they are woke up or someone's teaching for everybody and I just want to
do I can't do that within working at the ADA volunteering that is. So once the evidence is there then we are
hoping that they will transform into coverage for example. When there was the recommendation for type two
on basal instantly from the mobile trial few years ago that then became that made the care that it
covered in CGM for basal instantly instead of you know multiple that injection for type two and then
that followed by the insurance the payers. So it starts someplace but you need to again go back to the evidence.
So now that we have the evidence and we have put this recommendation we're hoping that with time the
payers will read this and understand that they should extend consider like we said the use of CGM and people
without taking in so because many people today are able to come off of insulin when they use GLP for
example and then they're using the CGM when they are on insulin and GLP whatever the medication is and then
when they're off they're faced with the fact that they might not be able to afford there anymore and they
becomes really difficult because they really want to see that information so that's my clinical experience.
On the guidelines part we are hoping that when we put the information as a new recommendation there will be some
sort of a awareness and hopefully coverage in the future. So you mentioned GLP ones in there and I just
want to stick with that for a second is that making your recommendations for type two a little more tricky
just because of how that's affecting people with type two and how they may not need insulin or CGMs
because of that no okay but remember when people are treated today they should receive GLP because it's
such a great medication for many benefits cardiovascular unaymen or say but often what happens is that a
patient is an insulin that studies in CGM the glucose gets better and they might be able to come off of
insulin because it's not just a GLP it's a combination of GLP and CGM and the literature supports that so the
combination of those two enhances the benefits so in fact when you add CGM to GLP you make the glucose even better
so having that information that immediate feedback enhances their ability to self-manage.
When you're adding these recommendations are they always based off of what drugs are indicated for and what I mean
by that is many people with type one diabetes are finding success with GLP ones because it stabilizes their
blood sugar levels and they have much better control but it's not indicated for that doctors can't
prescribe it for type one would the ADA look into that now that's beyond this code it's not
part of what the standards of care are they are a way for us to research the literature and bring up
new recommendation based on the literature weight now sometimes this my results in approval systems or
indication of medication but it's not the role of a DA to promote that totally that makes sense
this episode is sponsored by OmniPod as someone with T1D and with an incredibly active lifestyle it's
important for me not to get tied up especially with tubes on my insulin pump I love to go swimming
lift weights and play kickball with friends and with OmniPod 5 I never have to worry about tubes getting
in the way plus not having to disconnect helps me to stay in range during all of my favorite physical
activities that includes sexy time too see if you're eligible for a 30 day trial by visiting OmniPod.com
slash dive tech on there you'll see full safety and risk information and trial terms that's OmniPod.com slash
dive tech you mentioned that the ADA has had an impact on coverage can you kind of tell me about that a
little more have you seen direct influence on the CGM world with coverage so it's yes and no so the
ADA puts out the information that is available in the literature and by doing so hopes that there will be
an impact and some recognition from the payers who then are able to accept that those guidelines are
strong enough support enough the literature that there are benefits and therefore patients can take
they have benefits of using these tools and they can cover them so they don't specifically drive that but
definitely the fact that the guidelines are out there and there are supportive of such a very strict
method of vetting the literature shows that if a recommendation isn't the guidelines as merits to consider
the coverage from the payers we want to also make the providers aware because you see providers
do so much for patients so when you see that there are more evidence there is more information about a specific
to in this case CGM and they provide the reads that they are more encouraged than use these systems and by
doing so they give more information they give more knowledge so it's not just for payers the ADA guidelines
to help people who practice medicine to do better for their patients is ADA leading any type of
charge or is anyone to get not just people in the diabetes space like endos and diabetes educators to read this
but but primary care because you know my primary care misdiagnosed me for six months with type two
diabetes is is there any form of you know education through the ADA to educate people outside there who can
also get involved even with insulin pumps right just for their their patients who don't have the ADA is not for
endocrinology it is for every person in medicine who wants to understand diabetes and improve their knowledge
and in fact the mission is to improve the care prevent and hopefully cure when they diabetes
but also expand and others to everybody people with diabetes provider is clinicians nurses medical assistance
anyone primary care and especially primary care because there are many more people with diabetes especially
type two that they see compared to endocrinologists because there are a few of us so the ADA
mission it really expand the knowledge and to take care of people with diabetes so there are a bunch of
volunteers that in the families and caregivers and healthcare professionals and also professionals
as well but the idea is a family is not just a book that comes once a year truly is an entity that supports the
people who have diabetes you mentioned before you use the word volunteering is the work you do at the
ADA are you volunteering that time? Absolutely. Strictive volunteers so it is a great privilege to be
invited to be in the professional practice committee because the ADA chooses he clinician and so that you get
invited is a huge honor because you are a huge responsibility so it's all on a volunteer basis and you
spend many months and I did this for three years I was so privileged to be able to do that and offer
whatever knowledge I had but also to look for papers, literature, think about new recommendation and to
sort of expand the thing that was assigned to which was the chapter seven so yes that's why it's so
important because being a volunteer you really have to be engaged and wanted to do it because you
to meet over and over again to make sure that these guidelines are voted on that we sort of a
wordsmith we adjust every word there is okay it's not a chance that there is a word there that is written
because we just didn't realize we had to pick and choose everything the word so that the message is very clear
so we have to go through 80% debt to represent the agreement and the voting every single recommendation
gets through voting more than one sign one more the one cycle excuse me so it's truly a coming together
of the minds and the people who have expertise and then looking into make recommendation to improve the
life of a person with diabetes and then the health wow well thank you for all the time you spend on this
the ADA standards of care are considered the gold standard why is that because first of all there are
really objective there is no industry support it's only funded by the ADA the work is done by volunteers
we have to declare a conflict of interest and so when you have so much strict sort of criteria
you're not putting a recommendation because you want to help a company or the other it's nothing
like that you want to make sure that the data they're available some of the people that done with the
this industry government funded NIH fund the studies or foundation like GDRF or breakthrough type one
has validation when we have this so much strict criteria that we can say we feel comfortable the
we have set truthful information that it can be vetted look up and so there is no it feels like
it's really a transparent what would you say are some other pivotal endeavors that the ADA has led
up until now things that the ADA has done that you that you're proud of they do so much advocacy
it is incredible so much advocacy for just about everything diabetes but also a lot of things
programs for the person with diabetes and not just a provider so there are two different components
professional ADA component and the person with diabetes if you go to ADA or G they be the
store or G excuse me so diabetes that work you see recommendations information resources for people
with diabetes and the professional component as well so the ADA doesn't just want to write
recommendation for physicians or clinicians it was to write information and support the
person with diabetes it even has information on counselors psychologists he has a time and range
information to understand what time and range is it tells you about food exam I exam so many things that are
for the person with diabetes they also a component of diabetes education that is very important where
specific criteria by which a center can have accreditation from the ADA for diabetes education
or institution has an accreditation center and it's a specific benchmarks and so it's got a lot of
and a lot of work that surrounds the person with diabetes it sort of 360 wraps around the person
I can I can just feel and see your passion and your enthusiasm for this and it's it's fun to work on
something that you feel so passionate about tell us a little bit about your background what kind of
lead to this and how did you get involved so I've been practicing for more than 20 years in Chicago
Northwestern University and I have a passion for diabetes that was started when I was a fellow and so I
really felt that diabetes technology was the answer and to me when I was a fellow when CGM was initially
brought to them at 25 years ago was brought to the market and I thought this is the tool that is
going to change the way we treat people with diabetes and I feel that the CGM is the next
important thing after insulin discovery because without CGM we wouldn't have anything else like
AID system automation integration and nothing like that so that made me truly become so engaged with
the person with diabetes the technology in those days they were not even covered my patients
would pay before 2008 before the in JDRF study patients would pay because the aha moment
the fact that they could reduce hypoglycemia was so important and so and my practice grew because
I really was just engaging with with technology from day one and so then I got much more experience
I started with some clinical trials I did a lot of clinical trials that really shaped CGM the
replace BG was the trial that allowed CGM to become non-agent so you don't have to break your finger anymore
and we had to prove that so we did decide to say we know that it's safe we need to prove it to everyone so
there was an important study and that in many more studies on other I did the mobile study for CGM and
without multiple injections and so forth AID studies so I've gathered some expertise and then the
ADA invited me and I thought it was the greatest thing so I thought I felt so honored to be able to participate
it's a big responsibility because these guidelines are right by so many people and yet to make sure again
it's not just that your way is a lot of the world or whatever you say it's also can be done not just in America
but also all the countries so you want to be really smart and you have to be really attended to what you say
what would you say is one of your greatest achievements at the ADA
that I was able to really work with them for the chapter seven they believe technology and expanded
and the people before me did a great job they basically started from scratch and then I felt
that my role was to grab the literature now and expand the recommendations so we did over the
last three years we've added many recommendations we made many much stronger recommendation and stronger
sort of statements to truly say this is here to stay for example AID system now they become preferred
because the data is so strong for therapy we type one for example where you know that the amount of
diabetes I'm sort of glycemic well nice is so much better with the ADA then we let's say stand
upon so multiple the injection but this is because there have been so much data generated so we've
been able to grab it and expand it we also what I'm very happy about this past year the this year should
say recommendation is the one about the Open APS so used to call it the YI but we call it Open APS so
there are these systems that are not necessarily FDA approved but they're out there for people with
joined is we're not waiting movement and so now there's more and more evidence that shows that these
systems help the patients so even though the algorithm is not approved the other components of the
pump and the sensor are approved and it's our job to support the patient into their journey and if they choose
to be on a system that needs their needs then my job is to also support them and today we have
evidence that is growing it says yeah these systems are actually safe and so some have been approved
hopefully more will be approved in the future but nevertheless there was one thing that are so happy to put
in this 2025 guidelines that say think about the patient already comes to us with an Open APS know the
literature which we explain in the in the narrative and say yeah this can be used you need to support
the person with diabetes and that they come with the two pieces there are the sensor and the pump are
approved the piece in the middle is not but there are you know safety measure in place you work with your
patient and you support the patient to meet them where they're at. Yeah that's very cool and I do a lot of
work in the DIY space open APS throughout my channels I talk about it a lot I've I've used many of them
and they are they're fantastic and a lot of people swear by them can you tell me more about what has just
gone in in that realm they're you're saying there are recommendations for this like what is what is what has
the ADA said when it comes to these systems and are they encapsulating like say DIY loop trio
AAPS Android APS like all of these are they encapsulated. Well we're not giving names we just
say no names what we can't right so what we're trying to say is in the recommendation to support
the patient with diabetes they use this this systems because that is growing evidence in the literature that
these are safe so it's about supporting the recommendation is to A be aware and be to support the
patient and use system so it's really again about the human with diabetes it makes sense yeah
we can't say recommend because they're not if they are approved but we need to support the patient
who uses them and that's where the recommendation is all about. Yeah and that's what the community wants
it's what the patients want the patients when they go into their office talking to their
doctor about this system they don't want to just be told no not with me goodbye they want at least be
spoken to about it right at least for it to be considered and a lot of people are just shut down
well there is a challenge there so some some provider might be familiar with the system so we need to
also understand and that's why also there is information and the narrative because once you read the
guidelines you have the narrative that tells you this is what the study shows so you have plenty of
opportunity to become educated so you want to do with the providers so I can't respect the somebody
as infill comfortable because they are not aware or they're not familiar with the system and they
will be one of the situation it's so we're hoping that in the future there will be more knowledge and that's
why we say support the patient that is there are these tools and sometimes a provider is interested in
to try to learn more sometimes they might feel uneasy and you cannot judge the provider either because they
feel that the license might be a risk and yet to sort of going to this gray area but if you if you
a clinician is comfortable with these systems they're willing to work with the patient that is wonderful
that's when they are supporting the patient okay I'm going to put the standards of care in the show
notes for this so people can go and find it if they were to go in there where can they find this literature
about open APS so in the narrative so in chapter seven with the recommendations a bit about the end
after during the AID sub chapters sort of a subsection you read the description of the study that we use to
make this statement and there is the references the references you go to the the back of the chapter
and you look all the papers that we use to generate the recommendation and to generate the language and
explain what this system's Duke now this is not the certification on the open APS because it's within
AID cgm it connect the pencil it can just write such a long thing but the paper that were utilized
they had the better the basic evidence are reported very so you can go and look at them if you want to
look more about it I want to as well so that was just as much for my audience as it was for me because
I'd like to to read up on you know what people are reporting about these systems but we also
expanded the AID portion because since last year there have been so many more tools that have been approved
and more literature available we had to make sure that it was really about what this system do so it's very
detail so that's why it's an educational basically a document because you want to learn more about
AID system you go to the chapter you have a lot of information on what the studies for what they showed
what the results were the population that was what these tools do and don't do and and even we put that
that is you know one tool that was approved for type 2 diabetes of course we don't say the name because we don't
want to be you know we cannot make specific branding name but we know that before the end of the year one brand was
approved for type 2 diabetes of AID and other two so we're trying to again be as up to date as possible to say
this is what they are you can educate yourself and learn about how to take care of patients
one to use an AID even if you imprimity care why not it's good to know
today's episode is sponsored by T1D Exchange you can directly make an impact on diabetes health care
treatments and technology by participating in the T1D Exchange registry it starts with the simple
survey about your life with T1D and it only takes about 15 minutes after that you'll have a personal portal
with ongoing T1D study and survey opportunities plus some of these studies even offer compensation
signing up with the link in the show notes help support my channel and it allows me to continue putting
out free content you can sign up at t1dxchange.org slash diabetic or click that link in today's show notes
who exactly is on the decision making side of the AIDA you were brought on who else is being brought
on to this so we have board well it's a different layer so the professional practice committee has several
key leader clinicians okay clinicians with a lot of expertise either in diabetes, in hypertension
pharmacology, in kidney disease in different areas of the guidelines we all get to pediatrics and adults
both in geriatrics all these people get together and we are assigned needed to be the lead of a section
or the in the subcommittee for other chapters so we don't just do one thing we do four or five and then
we meet very often I'm saying for each chapter that we have assigned and we go over the previous
literature we look at the new literature we come up with new recommendations or we say and then we have
to vote on this in different stages we vote first as a preliminary vote to see if they can go through
if they're my new like a minimal changes then we vote on the minimal changes but the ones that are new
need to be presented a yearly meeting so we meet together to the meeting in the AIDA headquarters
where we go through the entire new recommendation one by one it's what takes two days and then we have
the voting which is the professional practice committee they two chairs people help us with the literature
evidence to understand by the evidence epidemiologists and then these go to peer review
and then they go to the board so that we get feedback and then well that's happening we need to work on the
narrative to report and so in a narrative fashion right what we put into the recommendation and
sort of support what we say in the recommendation the values article the support the recommendation
with the way to update hundreds and hundreds of references every year then it goes to production
they give us the proof we have to go one more time to read them all make sure there is no confusion in the
editing and then finally goes to diabetes care for proof proof proof in there for how does a recommendation
get you know put on the pedestal is it someone just like you or anyone else that's like I think that
this should be something that we start looking at and then it you know goes up the chain how is that
starting what depends what you're talking about right so if this it's a new medication you're
recommendation for a particular medication it's okay it's time for this new topic to be placed in
the guidelines we're proposing so when we meet together for our chapter or section assigned to us we say
because we basically know what's going on in the particular area we feel okay this is time to start
thinking about this topic and how should we go about it can it actually become a recommendation many times
we don't get them they don't make it to the recommendation because it's the premature the restoring
of supporting literature it may be controversial it's not ready so we wait and we be waiting for some
things like the type two neurons we had to wait to get more literature for example and so and then we
present the new recommendation to the entire committee and they can say yes and they can start by vote we
need an 80% vote to pass that's a proposal you recommendation need to present it present the papers that I
actually chose discuss the papers so I'm not just these are the papers explain what they are
what level evidence what kind of side of the are the rocker and the mice and the retrospective
perspective so to explain with the entire team what this is about and then we go through the writing of it
towards smitting and then the level of evidence we need to decide what what are we going to assign to it
and then it goes to voting and sometimes something has to be changed even after it because they might say
I approve the language but not the level of evidence so you need to go back and forth to say
it's a B is a C it's a B is a A what is it so we need to tell me more about that and you mentioned it earlier
the the CGMs for people with type two diabetes without insulin got a B rating and there's an A B and C
rating can you kind of walk us through what the differences are between those three so evidence A is the highest one
it is from well conducted large randomized control trial can be 20 people it's to be a bigger number
and you have to have two arms yet to have the control and the intention right and the experimental
arm otherwise there is no it's biased so then B is evidence from less regular study smaller study and then
C is observational so retrospective perspective there is no intervention just observe what happened if you
put somewhere on CGM this is what happened right but for the for the CGM for people with type two without
into there were a couple of randomized control study not big smaller and a lot more small study with less
rigorous methods so this is where the B came in do you think that there has been enough studies in the last year
to to move it to an A or is there still a lot of work left they don't know they're not published yet right so I don't know
that when do they publish we don't know so we are going to ATTD conference in Amsterdam next week
they will be ADA so I hope to see more information at those two conferences and so there will be a great place
to say okay there is more movement more studies have been done and so once the studies are done and they're
published then they can be considered okay okay are you and the other people in the ADA are you going to
these conferences and searching out for these new studies and saying oh this one could be used
for that and we could maybe get it to an A or you know you're kind of pulling this information out looking at
all that stuff yes I go to the conference quite often but that is not sufficient because a conference
usually has an abstract okay so that abstract needs to become a publication because if it doesn't go
from abstract to publication you can think what happened did they have enough information to be published
in peer view journals sometimes you go to a discomfort they present a result and there's a paper that
gets released at the same time so you can see there is more information and so we go to the conference we see
what's out there we get information about what the what the new things are we hope to see those
presentation become manuscript published in the literature so we can then read them and say
are they go standard a recommendation studies or not okay is there like an ADA certificate you know
how you buy a piece of food and it's like USDA certified or whatever it is like is there a stamp of
approval that the ADA gives no no no no no this is again what the standards of care are truly to
engage with the clinician to improve their knowledge and by doing so improve the care they deliver to
people with diabetes there is no stamp but the guidelines and a live but it would be a cute stamp
but you see the guidance and a live document they get updated if so let's say something important
happens between now and December there's a live update because you don't want to wait another year to
put another update it makes sense so the beauty of the guidance it's a continually it's a dynamic
document that's in stay there petrified for years age changes every single year that's a lot of work to
change 300 pages of documents be if there are important updates we put them out as a live update so that is also
how involved you need to be an up to date to make sure that if some becomes your attention say
hey we need to change it because what was said six months ago now is the long goodbye I need to do
something else so we updated to make it more current okay okay what are you hearing may come next for the
standards of care are there some talkings of upcoming stuff that you think will be exciting
so the thing that excites me the most is that I'm waiting for the next version of the guidelines
based on what I might see at the conference so there is so much out there but again so much can be
just a femurus it happens when they never becomes anything else so once it becomes part of the the
guidelines the standards of care that we know that whatever was seen in conference on papers and literature
was strong enough to give people the confidence that can become a recommendation we are waiting for so
much more stuff miniaturization of systems more data for type 2 diabetes and AID I'm hoping to see more
data of this kind of studies because type 2 patients really can use AID system but it's successful and so
I'm looking forward to see some presentation at the ATTD they will be presented for a study that was done
so I'm looking forward to see what they're going to say and if they will influence the guidelines I don't know
but it would be nice to see more data on people with type 2 using technology yeah I was that was my next
question was if AIDs for people with type 2 would kind of be next on the docket a lot of pump companies are
already pushing their pumps to support that but I'm sure the ADA coming out with a recommendation for that would
really push it but but we need the data just as these companies say our products work for these people
doesn't necessarily mean that these people need it or it's recommended right the beauty of this is that
once you do a study and you publish it they study is be looked at with the fine tooth comb but a bunch of
reviewers and not just get published because you wanted to be published it goes back and forth so if there is a
publication that really supports strongly but something is that good then the ADA will look at
it say hey maybe we should put this in the guidelines because the study was done so well so we're looking so the
companies can say whatever they like of course they support their products but we need to at the publication
the support their statements as it makes sense so people with type 2 they have been at some point they need
insulin and a lot of challenges with multiple that injection because they forget to take four to five
injections per day and the absorption can be maybe not super good because they take a lot of insulin but the
ADA system some of them do phenomenal for these patients will the literature support it will find out soon
we go to the conference next week well so my I'll see you there and this episode I think is releasing on the
Monday of next week so we should meet up and be like go watch our episode so I know a lot of
tech companies CGM pump companies they put out research they fund research do you
scrutinize that any differently than if it were just some research lab do you or do you you know
you look at the data that they're providing and it's you know you verify it so if I participate or
I'm invited to participate in a study sponsored by an industry a manufacturer I want to make sure
the study when I read the protocol that is done the protocol has some weight and if it doesn't I give my
feedback but once I participate my job is to do the best that I came to conduct the study in the most
rigorous ways when the results are published they are real they're not fake they're real and they make a
difference otherwise what why do they study spend so much money because it's not cheap and so I've done and I feel
privileged because I get to see firsthand the challenges the things that can become problematic but also work on
engaging with the participant and then it's such a beautiful thing the person who does the study the clinical
the person that's participating in the study the patient with the partner type too they engage with you
for those for many months they are so enthusiastic they are at least in what I practice they're they're
they're looking for to say that one of the study with you because they get to try these things first hand I think it's
wonderful and so you have a component of yes in the industry sponsor but they make the money the the
machine I can't get myself right but then the patient we the participant we use and we engage with them
they get so much benefit out of it and I learn the pros and cons and that is presented and that is published
and then we can say okay and also depends on what it's published and it makes a big difference because
some journalists have a higher standard than other ones right so if you get exposure in a pretty
renowned journalist you think okay it was done with the right criteria and you can really sort of
look at the data and be comforted what is written it's really what happened the FDA recently released guidance
for AI artificial intelligence you have Dexcom who's implemented AI into their stelo cgm for people
a type two diabetes is AI something the ADA is already looking at as something you know that could
kind of fall into your laps I can't speak to that really what I'm looking forward to seeing is results from
study using AI and how we can that help the patient with diabetes in a easier life so my in my in this moment
my response would be okay see what's going on are there studies do using AI to help people recognize food for
example meal so carbs containing so I'm sorry I should say carbs recognition and it's a taking a picture
I'm just making an example if that then is published and there are reports the support the beneficial
to patient then the ADA role is to say let's look at the literature so we can do with this to make the
patient's life easier you mentioned that you've been doing this for at least 25 years and you said that you've
seen cgm grow and become so integral in treatment if the last 25 years of your careers indication of where we may
go in the next 10 to 25 years how are you feeling about the future of diabetes treatment and technology
so I really see in the birth of technology and the development has been so fantastic to see so many changes
I'm thinking about the patient most of all how to make this tool easy to use for people with diabetes of any age
you know that's very important we're seeing people with diabetes age beautifully because the survive
56 years with diabetes can they still use this system can we make him sample for them to use can we allow them to
use when they're getting older so are they smaller do they require more dexterity or less dexterity can
they be more automated without they need for intervention so I see as I've seen this moving along the hopefully
the decrease of the burden of the person with diabetes in their daily life if you were things to think about
if you were buttons to push if you were thoughts about having diabetes because the technology is taking
care of that component yeah well you can sign me up for that gratia thank you so much for coming
on the show this was such a cool view into a side of diabetes that I never really knew about and it's
cool to hear about all of the work that's going on to make this information about treatment and
education more accessible to the physicians that then can help you know patients like me so it's very
cool I so happy that you invited me to be part of your your podcast and I follow you too so
they I'm going to describe to you anyway amazing amazing awesome well thank you so much thank you so much again
what are your thoughts on the standards of care is there something that you believe should be on there that
isn't let us know in the comments be sure to follow our blog and newsletter with the link in the
show notes I've got articles going up there every week a newsletter going out twice a month thanks for
listening today show be sure to subscribe on YouTube and give the video a like if you're also watching on
YouTube I'm Justin and I'll see you next week