Diabetic has an app on iPhone.
Look at that, it's me.
We have a new blog post every week
and a newsletter twice a month.
And now with this app,
it will get sent directly to your phone as a notification.
Here's how you set it up.
First go to diabetic.info.
From there, click login and enter your email address.
Next, open the email on your phone
and tap get access.
Once the website opens up, click the share button.
Scroll down to add to home screen.
Then name it whatever you want.
And voila, now you have an app for diabetic.info.
Now with this app, you'll get push notifications
when we release our blog post every week
and send out our newsletter twice a month.
You can adjust those notifications
as you like in the settings on your phone.
Now go ahead over to diabetic.info,
set up the app on your phone and enjoy reading.