Huge news in diabetes tech has arrived for the first time ever an implantable continuous glucose monitor will
integrate with an insulin pump to provide automated insulin delivery. Here's what you need to know.
Sequel MedTech has announced that the EverSense 365 1 year CGM will integrate with its twist
insulin pump. The twist pump is releasing right now with people already starting to use it.
The EverSense 365 joins its initial CGM partner, the Libre3 Plus. Here's how EverSense works.
There is an implantable CGM put under the skin through a short procedure. Then the user wears an
exterior transmitter that has on-board vibrational arts. The transmitter can be removed whenever you want.
You just won't get readings while it's off. Twist is a tube insulin pump. It uses advanced
occlusion technology and it's the only FDA cleared system to support Apple Watch control. If you want to
learn more about this partnership and both devices, make sure you head over to my blog,
dieofettech.info or you can access that with the link in the bio and follow this page for more
diabetes tech tips and news.