Hey guys, so it's a bit of a different video for my channel.
I normally don't make videos that kind of show my personal side, I normally and just
very professional, telling you about some cool technology, whatever, and I love doing that.
I also really love that you guys have been on that journey with me.
I wanted to kind of catch up with you guys, tell you kind of some ways that I'm
socializing with friends and some technology I'm using that is just making each day a little more fun
or a little more social. So yeah, let's do it.
First and foremost, connecting with friends and family. The ways I've been doing that is I've been
doing a lot of face timing and I've also been using my portal TV. I love it because I'm able to put
all of my friends and family right on the big screen. They don't even have to have a portal TV,
as long as they have face book messenger or what's up and I chat with them and then the camera falls
me. So I really love that. I've been using that a lot. I can have up to six people up there and we're actually
going to have a party in my apartment later. Me and my roommate. We're having a long island mother dress up party.
I think it's happy and I think we all need to just find things that are fun to do inside that
make us happy and make us laugh. I think that's key. Laughing and making others laugh and happy.
I'm getting emotional. I'm going to have a Google Hangouts with a few of my friends. We're going to have a
happy hour tomorrow and we're going to play Quip Lash. Quip Lash is a great party game that you can play with
up to eight others. Everyone connects to the game with their phones. It's kind of like cards against
humanity, but it pits two people against each other for each question and is way better in my opinion.
So here's how you can play over Google Hangouts. First you'll need to install steam by going to their
website, the links below. Once you download steam and create an account, you can buy the game.
Quip Lash is 10 bucks, but I recommend buying the party pack three because it comes with more games
and it's only $14 more. Next you'll need to invite everyone to a Google Hangout. So using a Gmail account
go to hangouts.google.com and from there start a video call. Then I suggest you copy that link and
send it to your friends. They could join in from their hangouts app on their computer or other devices,
but they will need their phone for the game. All right, last step, you as the owner of the game
will need to share your screen to everyone so they can watch the game in action. Right up in that corner.
Unfortunately, they won't be able to see you, but you can see everyone. And then it's time to play.
Have everyone go to jackbox.tv on their phones and to the four digit code and they're in the game.
Another thing, I can play on a lot of VR. I've been playing a lot of Star Trek Bridge Crew with
you can play with up to three other friends. This is a VR game, but what's really cool is if you have a PS4 or PC,
you can also join in. And I'm on this spaceship with three other people. We all have our different areas and
different jobs and we have to complete missions. It's been a lot of fun. Get that game right now. I love
VR so much. And I think that this is like a really incredible time for it. And then I think one of the most
important things having a schedule. What I do every morning, I make my coffee and then I go on a walk.
It's my morning routine and it just allows me to get excited for something. I literally like going
in bed at night, I'm excited to wake up in the morning so I can make my eyes coffee and go on a walk.
Something that's also been really helpful for me is using my Phillips Hue bulbs to set the lights
based off the day. So right now, you see that light right there, that set to a very light light.
It has like blue in it and it's the setting is energized. So right now I have it on energized, but
watch if I do this, the set of home lights to relax right there. That's what I'll do in the evening.
So I use the lighting around my home to tell my mental clock with time it is. Set home lights to
energize. I don't know how to set home to that set. Of course. The set living room lights to energize.
Sorry, I didn't find a device named living room lamp. I'll do that manually. There's energize right there.
Oh, okay. And now I'm trying to set it on my phone, but I put my phone on every play mode and took it off Wi-Fi so that
I wasn't distracted during this video. Anyway, that is what I've been doing. I still have a lot of cool products. I want to show
you guys. I'm going to be starting a pump spring smart home series. It's going to be like a six part series all about building the
coolest smart home top of the line gear and I think you guys are really going to love it. Also, what are you guys doing?
What is making you smile? What is making you laugh? Let's start a conversation for fun things that we
can all do. I think that it's more important than ever now to give each other ideas of fun things to do.
Anyway, we're going to be fine. We're going to get through this. Let's go to take some time.
And I hope that I can bring a little happiness to you during this time. And I hope you guys can
bring a little happiness to me. So I hope you guys enjoyed this video. I would love for you guys to share
to your friends and family. So they have these ideas. And I'm definitely going to be making more videos that
help all of us have fun. So I want you guys to subscribe to my channel right down there. Click that
bell for alerts. And if you enjoyed this, it'll help other people see it if you give it a like. It's like
all I got for you guys today. I'm Justin. I'll take you later.