Hey guys, I had to make a first impressions video of the Oculus Quest because this device is honestly mind-boggling to me.
It's literally ready player one. It's the first untethered virtual reality device that you don't need a PC for.
So you're going to get virtual reality moving around having depth, perception, and spatial computing, right?
So I can create a play field in this entire room with this device because of these cameras right on here.
There are four cameras right there and there, and those allow this to understand your surroundings and then allow you to move around.
So my goal is to at least have a few of my friends buy this device so that we can play online together.
There's a ton of multiplayer games and I'm feeling kind of lonely at the moment.
Something that's also really cool about this is that I can past what I'm seeing here to my phone or to a Chromecast onto a TV.
That way my friends who are hanging out with me can actually be a part of the experience now.
And it makes it a lot more fun. Also, what's really cool is just the way you create your play field.
So what I do is I put my headset on and I can actually see my surroundings because of these cameras and I actually draw a play field.
And then that's where I can play around and that's where it knows to show me walls.
So when I go to those outer limits, a wall up here and then I know to not go any further or I'll hit a wall like my friend Toby did the other day.
There's someone here, so that is what Toby is saying.
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Did you just watch my walls?
Did you hit it really that hard?
I mean I hurt my finger.
Oh good.
I think good.
At least it wasn't not, you know, my controller, right?
So enough of me talking, why don't I show you a game?
How about beat saber? I'll play the demo, I haven't bought the game yet, but I'm going to go with you.
And you should too.
Here it goes.
Okay, so first thing I have to do when I put this thing on is I have to create a guardian, right?
I can still see my entire apartment look.
That's my counter, this is my table.
Do you want to next sandwich?
And now I'm going to draw my play area.
Beat saber demo.
I'm going to play demo level.
Here I go.
And this is a pretty easy level, but I can only imagine how hard it gets.
So I have to watch out for those walls.
And I have to do the blue ones with the blue ones in the direction that it shows me.
And the red ones with the red ones.
So I'm this one.
This is actually I hear like a really good workout.
I want to, especially when it gets really intense, but it's, this is literally DDR.
Meet Star Wars in VR.
Now, because in the Oculus Quest you can play actual VR anywhere.
I'm like, I'm so impressed with this device.
And then there we go.
I can cross my swords and I can actually feel like a vibration.
All right.
Just in.
Let's see how I did this time.
All right.
Now let's go to the last time.
I'm a little distracted.
That was just the demo.
It's 29.99.
If you want the full game.
And I do want the full game.
And I'm going to get the full game.
I have a bunch more games that are really cool.
I have Vader immortal, which is who Star Wars experience created by I.L.M.
The X-Lab.
It's actually the same company that did the Star Wars experience that I tried out at the void.
They created one for the Oculus Quest.
It really shows you the true potential of this device.
The graphics are amazing.
It's a little short, but the fact that I can use a lightsaber and dual against robots is kind of amazing.
Okay, fine.
I'll play it for a hot second.
Let's do it.
Do lightsaber, dojo.
It's my fingers.
Okay.
So, there's mine.
All right, here I go.
These things are really annoying.
Okay.
Ah.
Oh my god, I'm failing.
All right, I've got to block this.
Got him.
He's coming after me.
Shoot.
Got him.
This is challenging.
This is like level eight, but I think it's like 45 levels or something.
In this game.
Got him.
Oh, nope, maybe not.
Oh, shit.
All right, this dive.
So, that's just a quick tease into what the Oculus Quest can do.
Get one.
Or you know what?
Subscribe to this channel so that you can see all the games that I'm going to be covering.
I'm going to be covering multiplayer games, free things to do and all the things you have to try on this device.
I'll also be having some giveaways for games on the Oculus Quest who definitely keep an eye on my Instagram and my Twitter for those contests.
Also, real quick, this one's the 128 gigabyte, which goes for $4.99.
There's also a 64 gigabyte set goes for $3.99.
I definitely recommend going with the higher one if you have the money.
You just want to try it out.
Go for this smaller one.
It's fine.
Quick tip what I did.
You don't need headphones for this thing.
But I happen to have headphones where the cord actually detaches from the headphones.
It's a pair of bows.
So what I did was I wrapped this right around here and then I have this click right into my headphones.
And it's really convenient and easy.
And then if I just want to use, you know, speak to the speakers, then I just attach it.
That way my friends can hear it.
I'm going to go back to the virtual reality world.
Actually, I have to go edit this video now.
I barely been able to play this because I'm editing these videos for you.
Anyway, I'm going to edit this video real quick and then I'm going to go back to the virtual reality world and make more videos.
Until then, I'm Justin and I'll see you in the VR world.