Hey everyone, a few months ago I came out with a video comparing life expulps with Philips
Hue, and since then there has been a bunch of updates in my experience and in new products,
so I thought I would come up with a new video, kind of updating you on my thoughts on the
bulbs.
By last video I showed how life expulps created way better colors, and I thought that the
Philips Hue bulbs should be called lack of Hue, because they just don't reach the same colors
as life expulps.
Since then, there have been new products released, and my experience with life expulps hasn't
been as amazing as it was, so I needed me to explain why I'm now kind of leaning toward
Philips Hue.
Here are five reasons.
First reason, connectivity issues.
Lately with my life expulps, I have been having the worst connectivity issues.
Every other day, a bulb is going offline, and sometimes it's super simple, I turn
the bulb on and off, and it connects other times, it doesn't.
When it comes down to it, life should be simple, and they should work.
Number two, there is still no serious functionality for life expulps.
They promised this does late last year, and nothing.
There is Philips Hue, they've been doing it for months.
I can use my Amazon Alexa with life expulps, but if the bulbs are disconnecting, then
Alexa can't do shit.
Number three, this is the big one.
Hue is coming out with new life bulbs.
Again, third generation life bulbs, and it's going to make the blues in the greens richer.
This is literally addressing my number one concern with Philips Hue.
Number four, the Philips Hue family is growing.
On top of the new color life bulbs, you can get motion sensors, light strips, hue blue.
They have cheap ass white light bulbs for $15.
Lifex starts at 30 for those, and this leads me to my fifth and final note.
Philips Hue has light switches, and lifex does not.
You can buy a third party flick buttons, but that runs on blue tooth, and you have to have
a connected blue tooth device with that with the app running within range.
Too many components, with you, you can turn on your light bulbs like you've been doing
for the last 100 years with the flip of the switch.
My effects, just isn't keeping up with Philips, because they're backed by this multi-billion-dollar
company, and they continue to come out with new products, and they work, basic.
Thanks for tuning into this episode of Just In Tech, as always, please subscribe right
below.
I will see you later.