Hey everyone, it's Justin Tech, and I just got back from this festival, it's a little
festival.
I'm not sure if you've heard of it, but it's called Coachella.
Now I've got a few tech tips to get you through this year's festival, hashtag TechChella.
Probably the most important tip out there is time stamp your text, because service is horrible
out there.
And those time stamps that you already have on your phones, they're going to be wrong because
your message won't get delivered or received after correct time.
So always put the time that you're sending that text that you're going to you
attend back right, go in the main stage, far left, S3, 24601, who knows, anyway, put a time
stamp on your text.
It will come in handy.
People will know that at 654, you were headed over there, and that at 655, they can
head over there now too.
Make your wallpaper on your phone, the set list, then you can also set up circles right on your wallpaper,
that way you have them all circled, and you can kind of see what your day looks like.
You can even send it to a friend, that way you can kind of compare what your schedules look
like.
It is the best, what I'm going to do is I'm going to put the PDFs for those wallpapers right in
a link below.
Feel free to download them, use them, I want you to use them.
Also, next year I'll put a new link, this one is very important.
It's called the Over the Shoulder Text folder.
Now what is that you might ask?
Let's see you have a set that's coming up real soon, and you need to get there with your
friend, but you also need to let their group know that you're going, and you don't really
have much time.
What you do is, you put your shoulder over your friend, they text your friends, and you guide them.
Get through the crowd and message at the same time.
This one is very, very, very important if you want good pictures.
So what you do is you tell your friend to go over there, where you want the picture, your
frame it, really well, and you tell his person, oh, thank you so much.
You might just holding that right there and pressing that button, I don't need you to do anything
else.
No need to use your creative freedom, use mine, thank you so much, thank you so much, thank you so
much.
Anyway, take that phone, take that right there, I love the headspace, and then you go in the
picture, and bought a big, bought a boom, you got a picture, and it's great.
Now another option, if you feel like being bossy, you can just go up to a random group and be like,
hey, who in this group takes the best pictures, be honest, who is the most followers, hashtag
Chek Shella.
Alrighty guys, next tip is that you must, must, where a smart watch or a fit fit have mine right
here.
I highly recommend wearing a smart watch because then what you can do is you can set reminders,
eye call events that will go off on your wrist, that way when you're literally messed up.
Now you have nothing to think about unless your wrist goes off, you're also going to get text
and phone calls through your wrist, and you'll know who to answer or ignore.
Those are all the tech tips I have for Coachella or basically any festival, I hope they
help you guys out, like they did with me and my friends, anyway, as always, subscribe to my channel
on YouTube, that would be fan free contestic.
Also, I've gotten an Instagram, I've got a Facebook, it's just an underscored tech, follow me,
subscribe, help me out, everything helps, please help me, I'm poor, peace out, chah.