Hey, VR enthusiasts, it's Justin Tech, and today I'm at the void, and you know what?
My Spidey senses are tingling, and that's because I'm about to head in there and play Avengers damage control.
Let's get in there and suit up.
I have my armored suit on, I'm gonna go meet up with the team.
In Avengers damage control, you're recruited by Sherry to test out her latest prototype design.
powerful suits that combine Wakangan and stark industries technology.
There are no physical weapons, in this game you'll use your arms and hands to shoot beams and create a shield.
I had some difficulty getting the controls down and known what to do, because I was so overwhelmed and taken aback by the fact that I was a part of the Marvel universe.
So if I had one piece of advice, try and listen.
There is plenty of new gameplay here, including flying a plane and walking down what felt like a never ending ramp.
In the experience, you'll meet a bunch of the Avengers, and the witty dialogue from the movies absolutely shines through.
I thought, was it a glow circle right into the middle of our date?
Scott, popcorn on the couch and reruns of Golden Girls is not a date.
At the end of the experience, there's a score screen, so be sure to strategically shoot your enemies if you want to come out.
If you want to come out on top.
Avengers is a really cool game, but it's definitely a different experience that you're going to get from wreck it Ralph or Star Wars.
This is a very cinematic experience.
You're going to meet all the Avengers and, man, Hulk, Dr. Strange to actually kind of have a one-way chat with them.
There were a bunch of new sensory effects that you're going to love.
And I got to say, my favorite part was when you smell something.
I'm not going to say what you smell, but that's got to be my favorite part.
The Void VR offers the best story-driven VR I've tried.
And with each new experience, they get better and better.
If you're a fan of VR or Marvel, you need to try this game out.
It isn't going to come cheap, though.
It's 40 bucks, but luckily, it's their longest experience, running at about 20 minutes.
And I always recommend playing with the maximum players for people.
I've got a lot more VR coming your way.
Stay tuned for a video on Sandbox VR coming next week.
That place had some awesome esports VR, and I can't wait to show you that.
Also, I have a huge announcement coming out on Wednesday, and you are going to be so into it.
Stay tuned for that.
So there you have it, Avengers at the Void.
You guys have to check it out.
Go to your local Void terminal and play this thing.
And if you're not around you, yet they are opening a bunch around the country.
And for my European friends, they're coming to you as well, so you'll have to check it out.
For more VR videos and for Jemange, when that comes out, I'm definitely trying it out.
Why don't you subscribe right down there?
And hit the bell for alerts, that way you know when the video comes out.
Also, if you guys liked this video, why don't you give me a liked right down there?
Because that helps people find this video.
I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.
I will say my arms are a little tired now, so I guess you get a little workout.
Alright, I'll take it.