This is the Colido 2 Insulin Pump, and it was just unveiled at ATTTD, and I want to tell you everything about it.
The Colido has been known to be a colorful pump, and this one isn't any different.
There are six colors to choose from, and I think they're a bit more mature. There's more of a matte finish on these.
I kind of like this better. The Colido Pump is a two pump, and it can be worn in a few different ways.
You can either have a long tube and put Colido in your pocket, or you can adhere to your body and use a short five-centimeter tubing,
and infusion site that goes in right next to it.
The original Colido was already small, but this one is even smaller, about 10% smaller,
and it is the smallest rechargeable hybrid closed loop pump.
Colido 2 uses the same infusion set as Colido 1. There are a couple new sensors in here.
There's an accelerometer, which could theoretically be used to track activity,
and there's also a temperature sensor. So maybe that means it will be able to let a user know
if the insulin could be getting too warm. Another improvement has come to its charger.
It now uses USB-C. Love it. This pump is still in development, and the company hopes to submit
CE Marks of Mission next year, and is aiming for the pump to release early 2027. In Europe.
After that, the company's main focus is getting this pump to the United States,
and getting FDA clearance. I'll definitely be keeping my eye on this pump, and as I hear updates,
you'll find out on my page. So follow this page for more diabetes tech tips and news.