Diabetes is a lot to take in, especially after diagnosis.
The flood of new terms, tech, and lifestyle changes can feel totally overwhelming.
It's like being dropped into a game with a complicated tutorial.
And you're expected to beat the boss battle on day one.
But what if I told you there was a fun and intuitive tutorial available right now to help
with diagnosis?
Well, a new smartphone app called Level 1 is aiming to be just that.
A fun game-ified way to make Type 1 diabetes education easier to understand for newly diagnosed
patients and their families.
Welcome to the show.
I'm Justin.
I have Type 1 diabetes in on here.
I talk all things.
Diabetes tech, news, and research, and I am a gamer.
So I got super excited when I heard about this app, and I played it myself.
Today I'm joined by Sam Glassenberg, a veteran video game developer, and father of a child
with Type 1.
And that's what inspired him to make this game.
He created Level 1 to help others navigate the early stages of diabetes management through interactive
levels that teach everything from insulin to car ratios to how exercise and fatty foods affect
blood sugar.
Health care providers and patients are already raving about this app, and now it is available
to everyone on the app store, whether it's Google or Apple.
And after playing about 10 levels myself, I can confidently say that I wish I had this app when
I was first diagnosed.
Keep in mind that this show is not medical advice and it's for educational purposes only.
Always consult with a physician before making changes to your health care.
All right.
Let's get into it.
Sam, welcome to the show.
It's good to have you here.
No.
Great to be here.
Thank you for having me.
So little thing about me that you may not know is that I almost went to school for video
game design at Northeastern, but it was a last minute decision to not, and I'm glad I didn't
because then I probably wouldn't be where I am today.
But I love video games.
I'm a gamer.
I'm playing last of us part one right now, which I'm really enjoying on my PlayStation portal.
Yeah.
Gamer to gamer.
I want to hear all about the work that you've done, but before we get into Level 1, tell
me a little bit about your background and how you, you know, I guess your background
in video game design.
Sure.
So I've spent my career in video games.
My first job was out of college was at LucasArts.
I was hired as an animator.
I flew spaceships for cutscene animations in PlayStation to Star Wars games.
After that, I used to run a game technology team at Microsoft.
I built a company that did games for Hollywood movies, Hunger Games, Mission Impossible,
Rocky.
And for the last 10 years, I've built a company called Level X, which actually makes video games
for doctors.
Very cool.
I think what I love about video games so much is that they test you, they push you, you need
to use critical thinking to get through puzzles.
It's not as relaxing or as simple as watching a movie, right?
They put you to the test.
So I guess why would you say video games are a good tool for teaching and learning?
They are the best tool for teaching and learning.
Humans have evolved to learn this way.
I mean, think about it, when you get a phone or anything, you don't read the manual.
I don't even think they've even come with manuals anymore.
You go, I need to play with this.
Why is this?
We have evolved to learn through play.
And in the video games industry, we have kind of figured out that neurochemical recipe.
For exactly what you describe.
How do you hit the right balance of reward and frustration, challenge and skill to keep you
in the flow state and literally maximize the release of neurochemicals in the brain to maximize
fun, but also maximize learning.
Happy to like, I have a lot of examples, sort of the neuroscience of angry birds and things
like that sort of explain.
Give us that example.
That's a cool one.
I love angry birds.
Oh, yeah.
So if you've ever wondered why angry birds are so addicted, I mean, people, the game came out
10 years ago.
I still see people playing it on airplanes today.
We've evolved to play angry birds.
What do I mean by that?
So just a thing back to the first time you play angry birds probably a while ago.
What happened?
Angry birds hops in the slingshot.
You aim at the tower of pigs.
You fired.
What happened the first time you played?
I killed some pigs.
Not the first time.
The first time you missed.
Yes.
And what happens when you miss the piggy's laugh at you?
Why?
This totally gratuitous.
This makes you frustrated.
Second bird hops in.
You aim a little better.
You fire.
You get closer to the tower.
But you still miss.
And you get more frustrated.
Third bird.
There's glorious.
There's explosions and animations and the pigs go flying in the music changes.
All of this, all of this, was deliberately designed to trigger a dopamine release in your
brain that reinforces those neural connections used on that last successful fire.
This is why.
An hour later, you're firing that bird between two narrow obstacles at 50 meters.
And like 80 hours later, you're still playing the game.
Now, we didn't invent this, we didn't invent this in our mechanic in the games industry.
It's existed in the mammalian neuron for tens of millions of years.
This is how our ancestors learned how to throw a spear.
Miss, miss, miss, frustration, frustration, hit, dopamine.
Okay, what are the neural connections we used on that last successful throw?
We want to make those thicker.
We're going to want to use those again.
In video games, like what's Angry Birds doing?
It's training your brain, how to predict the flight, the parabolic flight of an angry bird.
What's seem city doing?
It's training your brain to understand how a city works.
It's level one doing.
It's training your brain, how to manage diabetes.
Yeah, yeah.
I've played Angry Birds in so many different forms from iPhone, back in maybe that was 2014.
And then I played in VR and I even played in augmented reality with the magic leap headset,
which was a really cool way to experience it because it's like you put an Angry Birds game
on your table and you're playing Angry Birds in your space, which is cool.
Box would fall off the table and hit the floor.
This was really high tech stuff.
And I actually talked all about that on just in tech, which was my, what I was doing before
diet, that tech, which was all technology and it was a lot of fun and I love tech.
I love gaming and that's now a more private part of my life, which is nice.
It's not my work.
I get to do diabetes, which is my work now.
For me, I'm very lucky.
It's both.
Yeah, right.
Right.
It was amazing.
We actually, back, you know, level X for, for, for doctors, we have like, we built some
bunch of the launch medical content for magic leap and AR core and AR kid and a bunch of these
things.
So we have, you know, you can, you can do spine surgery, you know, on a spine that's floating
and you can actually just do it with the controllers.
It's crazy stuff.
Yeah.
If anyone is interested in seeing, I did a whole five part series with magic leap and talked
about all the cool experiences and apps for it were, and the technology still holds
up.
Like it was very advanced at the time, so it's kind of like now is when it's all kind of happening
especially with the Apple Vision Pro.
So I'll throw that in the show notes.
Your company level X, you, you design games for doctors, tell me a little bit about what those
games are and who they're for.
So look, the, like, what level X does is they said, make games for medical professionals.
So if you think about, so imagine we would really have millions of medical professionals playing
video games to, you know, they're earning continuing medical education credit toward renewing
their medical license.
They play games.
We have, when you think about diagnosing rare disease, that's a puzzle game.
When you think about managing a complex patient with multiple comorbidities, that's a strategy game.
And so we basically bring in the top game developers, designers, artists who worked on everything
from mortal combat to diner dash, we team them up with hundreds of physician advisors across
every major therapeutic area in medicine to, we say, advance the practice of medicine through
play.
To use video game tech and video game design to help accelerate the adoption of new techniques,
new products, and that's, that's what we do.
Now we, with diabetes, have expanded also into games for patients.
Yeah, you told me you had to convince your parent company to let you do this.
Tell me why, why, why that was so important to you.
So this is the, this is sort of the story of how level one came about.
In the middle of, you know, I'm halfway into the level X journeys, five years ago, my at the time,
five year old daughter was diagnosed with type one.
And the onboarding experience was not great.
And so on Friday, your life is normal.
And then within 24 hours, oh, hey, Sam, you thought your job was running video game companies.
Oh, that's your second job.
Yeah, primary job is you're now a pancreas and you need to inject what is a lethal drug in
insulin into your kid and to precise don't precise doses, you know, dozen times a day.
I call it like this one sheet, I call it the guide to not killing your own kid.
We're out of the hospital in 48 hours, because my wife's a pediatrician, she caught it early.
And we're out of the hospital.
They give us a, here's this thing.
It's got scribbled out carb ratios, insulin sensitivity factors, you know, all this guidance on how to
prebull, it took me a year and it took us a year to actually develop a mental model to understand
how to manage this disease.
Finally, after you're like, oh, I get it.
Yeah, insulin curves and action curves and digestion speeds.
And, okay, now my brain knows where that curve is going to go.
And I was like, well, this is stupid.
Like, why should you have to do this?
We're learning, we're learning how to manage diabetes through play.
But the play is trial and error on your own kid, or for many other people, it's on themselves.
This is terrible.
So we fixed it.
I put together a design and at the time, so level actually been acquired by a major medical device company
and, you know, called BrainLab, they do, you know, all the cool, like, neurosurgery hardware
and software.
But they also do a lot of philanthropic efforts in health care worldwide.
And I was like, hey, this is super important to me.
I want to get this game done and they fund it to their credit.
And so we built it and launched it two weeks ago.
This episode is sponsored by OmniPod.
As someone with T1D and with an incredibly active lifestyle, it's important for me not to get tied up,
especially with tubes on my insulin pump.
I love to go swimming, lift weights, and play kickball with friends.
And with OmniPod 5, I never have to worry about tubes getting in the way.
Plus, not having to disconnect helps me to stay in range during all of my favorite physical activities.
That includes sexy time too.
See if you're eligible for a 30 day trial by visiting OmniPod.com slash dive tech.
On there, you'll see full safety and risk information and trial terms.
That's OmniPod.com slash dive tech.
So I can imagine as a parent, like, it must be really stressful to have to learn all of this new information
when your child's diagnosed and have to manage their pancreas.
I mean for me, it was so overwhelming.
It really did take that full year to feel like I got all of these different areas of diabetes down.
And I've always looked at my diabetes as a really annoying game.
It really is a game of, like, add a little of this.
Reduce a little of this to keep you in this range.
Like, like, flappy bird, right?
Or that this helicopter game I used to play, which was essentially flappy bird.
And I can just imagine someone like you, you were immediately as you were taking all this information,
like, game of fighting in your brain a little bit.
Tell me a little bit about these early days of when you were doing this.
How you were thinking about all of this.
I mean, I'm sure it was so stressful, but like, were you already kind of toying around with things like,
Oh, this is like, game of fighting in your head.
So not yet at the very beginning.
What's interesting is, so first off, I hardly remember the beginning,
because you don't sleep much when you're the parent.
But what I did was actually wrote it down, and I wrote a little bit of a diary,
because what was interesting was not like thinking about it from the perspective of like,
how would I make a game to solve this?
I wasn't there yet.
But what was interesting for me is coming from video games.
We've gotten extremely good at, there are all these rules around video game design.
How do you make a game fun?
How do you bring people into a video game and introduce them to the game such that,
because obviously there's a thousands of games launching in the app store like every month.
So how do you make it?
So your game stands out.
So people start playing it immediately.
They start having a good time, and they get into it.
And it's engaging.
And there's all this neuroscience and design to do this.
What I realized was the experience of type one diabetes takes all of those rules around how to make a fun and
thralling, captivating video game, and flips them all in their head to make the most punishing experience possible.
Little things like, there's rules and video games.
You always want to give the player an early win.
So you notice when you play a new game.
Usually there's some little thing you do, and it's like, oh, congratulations.
You just beat a boss.
There's some early win.
Diabetes, the exact opposite.
Also in video games, it's very important that player understands what they're being scored on,
and what that score means.
So type one diabetes.
You start already you're losing.
If you're, you know, luckily we're in in D.K.A.
But like, you know, blood sugar is 550.
You don't even know what that means.
Like, keep a little bit of anyone's, you don't know what that means.
All you know is you have a score.
Your score is bad.
And the score is really important for gameplay.
And then from there, it's just all downhill.
Like the, you know, whether it's the instruction manual, which is terrible.
Whether it's the, you know, all the different we call the loops of
fingerpokes and injections.
And it's all, you know, so I actually wrote a blog that I, you know, eventually posted,
called worstgameever.org that literally just goes through this sort of day by day as a game,
you know, from a game design perspective on why the onboarding experience is terrible.
I wrote it because it was therapeutic for me, but a lot of other parents have been reading it
like early on.
And they're just like, well, it's great to know that others were sufferers.
Other sufferer like you do.
Yeah.
You know, I'm a pretty competitive person, not a sore loser, but I like to get super competitive
about games and I like games where you can, there's like real strategy to being good at it.
And yes, diabetes, yes, their strategy.
Yes, there's different features and modes you can turn on and adjustments and
preparation you can do, but no matter how good you are at the game of diabetes,
it will always school you in a way you don't expect.
You cannot perfections impossible.
It just is.
We, because we move and we eat and we breathe.
You know, it was like doing what there was something like doing the same thing,
the eating the exact same thing and doing the exact same thing for three days
and getting completely different results, that's what type one diabetes.
And so in video games, that breaks the rules because in video games you always
want the player to know how their actions correlate to their score in the game.
And you want it to be consistent and diabetes is not that.
So even when we designed level one, like one thing that was very important is you can
three star any level without a perfect score without being in range the whole time.
Because it's very important that first few days to really internalize like
perfection is impossible.
Don't try it if you try it, you will actually just stress yourself out because you can't.
As long as you're within range 90% of the time, you're happy.
You can three star every level and level one because our whole thing is do not like,
you know, how do we literally create a game that trains your brain like,
no, no, no, you don't want it.
You don't need to be perfect relax.
So it's a really pretty looking game.
I know that you were inspired by different art types of games.
Tell me a little bit about, you know, the inspiration behind the style of the game and
what the game style is.
Yep.
So the, there's the mechanics and the visuals.
The mechanics, we call like the gameplay.
Super simple.
You play the whole game just with one thumb.
One handed one thumb.
We don't want you to have to spend an hour learning out of play the game.
We want you to know how to play the game intuitively and spend your time learning how to manage diabetes.
The game is a particle, fundamentally a particle puzzle.
It's a particle game.
If you've ever played feed meat oil, where's my water,
a world of goo?
Like, these games are played by a billion people.
They're super fun.
You have thousands of particles on screen that interact in interesting ways.
It's gorgeous.
Our brain delights in it.
That's why we love playing with sand.
And that's why humans love playing with water and magnetic sand and things.
Because we delight in complex particle interactions.
So the game is just gorgeous.
And what you're doing is in the game.
You're also, it's also a rhythm game.
So if you're familiar with like, I think,
guitar hero is that genre.
So what is dosing diabetes?
It's, you know, making sure to time your doses with whatever's going on with the food with your current,
with your current blood glucose level.
And so the game is just like it's super simple to play.
All you're doing is tapping with your thumb, dosing insulin.
Once a while if you go low, you move your thumb a centimeter to the left and you dose some juice.
And the game just represents everything.
So there's 60 levels.
There's food that's just moving in on a conveyor belt.
Dropping into your digestive system.
Getting broken down to these gorgeous glucose particles.
You inject insulin.
It comes in off the side.
Activates the cells and just sucks in the sucks in the glucose.
It's gorgeous.
It's captivating.
The visual style is super light and casual.
Kind of think candy crush.
Because we really wanted to make something that was going to be,
you know, a visual style, like everyone plays candy crush.
So we picked visual styles that are like very casual, very friendly.
You're usually already under a lot of stress when you're trying to learn about this.
So the whole theme is just very the soundtrack is very zen.
And you just play the game for two hours.
And you've mastered every major topic that you need for the first six months of MDI.
Yeah.
It's a really pretty looking game.
And somewhat relaxing playing it.
Like you can take in all of this information and enjoy yourself and not feel like two stressed.
Sam.
So during development, how are you making sure that what you were doing was correct?
Like were you working with other people, doctors, HCPs to play levels and things like that
to make sure that the information you were putting out was correct?
Yes.
So this is level X is what we do all the time.
Right.
So we work with hundreds of physician advisors and contributors.
We have biomedical engineers and MDs on staff.
So because obviously you're making games for doctors, it's going to be.
So we know how to make really games that are accurate and that are peer reviewed and so forth.
We started out, you know, with obviously all the publications, the peer review papers,
around, you know, insulin action curves and glucose and, you know, all the glucose dynamics.
So it's modeled after real science.
But then, of course, we ran a beta for, I think, over a year, we're not a year, where we had hundreds of endocrinologists,
diabetes, educators, camp counselors, newly diagnosed parents, everybody.
And we're just internalizing all the feedback on the game.
Just like you would in any game, you know, make sure it's balance but also make sure that it's that it's not only,
like, medically accurate in terms of the glucose behavior.
But even just making sure that, like, all the messaging and all the, you know, we weren't doing anything.