the newest recommendation is 7.16 that says consider using CGM in adults with type 2 diabetes,
not using insulin or glucose laboratory medication other than insulin.
So we had to look in the literature and there is growing evidence that there are benefits
for people with type 2 using CGM, not using insulin.
And so we had to look into the growing research and growing papers and they were able to say,
now we feel comfortable that it is sufficient evidence to state that yes, we should consider.
Now, why do we not use recommend?
Because right now we don't have large randomized control trials.
We have some randomized control trial, a lot of retrospective information and some perspectives.
We needed to make sure we use the right level of recommendation to mirror the evidence that we have.