Hey everyone, I know that a lot of you right now in this weird time are setting up home offices
as am I actually, this is my setup right now, there is a lot that I can do and you guys can too,
and that is why I'm making this video. I'm going to tell you guys a bunch of different ways you can
make your home offices more comfortable and more productive. Now I also know Amazon is only sending out
essential products right now, so I'm going to be providing links in the description with places that
are still shipping products. All right, here we go.
First thing let's start with some tools that you'll want to have at your new home office,
mice, keyboards and some webcams, so the company that I truly love and this is not sponsored at
all is Logitech, so let me start with their mice. What I really like about Logitech,
mice is that they have Bluetooth connectivity and they also have the ability to switch between
three different devices. They also have a really nice feeling in your hand, a very nice build. The
more professional one is the MX Master 3, this one's really nice, I've used this and a few of my friends
have it and we all really love it. Then the other one is the MX anywhere to S. Well, I know you're not really
going anywhere, but you could in the future and this one's also really great. This one's a little smaller
but it has all the same functionality and it's 20 bucks cheaper. Next keyboard, so the one that I have
is the wireless solar keyboard K750. It's only 60 bucks and this one's really great because you can just
throw it in the sun and charge it up and it will last a really long time. The only downside is you need to
plug in a tiny USB receiver to your computer. I edit with it a lot and highly recommend that one. The other
one I would recommend is the MX Keys. This one's got Bluetooth. What I like about this over the solar
one is that it pays backlit. This keyboard lasts you 10 days or five months without using the backlight
and it's only $99. $30 cheaper than apples, which isn't even backlit. Lastly, for logic tech
devices, webcam. So I know a lot of us are using Zoom Google Hangout, things like that. I have the
HD one. This one was like 70 bucks but they also have some really high end ones. There's a 4k one called
the Brio Ultra HD Pro webcam and then there's also the Logitech Streamcam. This one's really built
for streaming like video games and things like that. It has a camera and a microphone attached to it.
But I know a lot of them are sold out on the website and I know this one is sold out. Next is sound.
So I know a lot of you are probably stuck at home working with your roommates and you're probably going
to want to block out some of the sound in your home. Here are a couple of options. The first one
are the AirPods Pro. Love these things. What's so great about them is that they have active noise
cancellation. I actually reviewed these and I'll put that video in the description. I am so happy with
these. The active noise cancellation is incredible especially for the size and what's so great about
these is that you could run with them. You could work out and then you could also use them in your home
office. You can also easily switch between your iPhone, iPad and Mac with these. You're not a
Mac user then maybe you should look at something else. So I have another option. The Bose noise canceling
headphones. They're obviously bigger than the AirPods Pro. Mine are this big. This is like a couple
years old. The newer ones are nice. The newer ones are also wireless. These are amazing on the plane
if we can go on one anytime soon. But they're also just really great. So if you don't mind something
a little bigger, go with the Bose noise canceling headphones. Next up, if you guys are using a laptop,
you definitely want to get a laptop stand. Right now if you're looking at your laptop, you're kind of
hunched over looking down. It's very low. So you're going to get hunched over. You're going to get bad
posture. So in order to fix that, you can get a laptop stand and you'll basically breathe bringing your
screen higher. Also while on that subject, I recommend having a second display. That way you have
more service area. When you're looking for second displays, you want to make sure you're getting
a refresh rate of about 120 Hertz. That's what I recommend. I'll throw a few of the recommendations
in the description. While on that subject, I made a video on how to use your iPad as a second display.
I'll throw that video in the description too. Okay, I got two more things for you. First is an iPad
keyboard. So if you guys are using an iPad or if you have one like around and you want just a lightweight
tool to use around your home, get the iPad keyboard. I just reviewed it. I reviewed a couple of
logistic keyboards and the Apple one. I highly recommend having a keyboard with your iPad. Also Apple
is introducing mouse support for your iPad. So just watch that video and then imagine also using a mouse.
It's going to be incredible. Okay, lastly, I don't have this here. I need it. It's a standing desk.
So I have a couple companies that people have recommended. My friend Toby who actually lives here. He has
the uplift and then another friend of mine has the fully. I'll put links to those right down there.
So price-wise, there are about the same. I'd say anywhere from like $5 to $700. They have basically
these really nice standing desks that you can personalize and have settings so that your number one is
for sitting number two is for standing number three is like somewhere in the middle and then also they have
things that you can put on top of your basic desk that you can just lift up and then it creates like a
standing situation. You can even make treadmills that you can put down there and walk so
those are options too. That's everything I have for you guys today. Please let me know if there's anything
that you guys have added to your home office in the comments below. I want everyone to get some ideas.
I want more ideas. Also, if you have any questions on anything that I brought up, let me know in the
comments. I'm here to help. We all need to get through this together. That's the only way we're going to do it.
I've got a lot more coming your way. Stay tuned for a smart home series coming in this house
and pump springs. Sponsored by Philips, you, oh my god, I'm so excited and I've got more magically
videos. AR really cool. Can't wait. How do you guys see these? Subscribe right down there. Click a like if you
enjoyed it. That's what I've got through now. I'm Justin. I'm not like a waiter.
I hope that the video looks okay. This is what it looks like. I'm a little like I'm a little oily. I really
like this, but whatever. It's like, do whatever I can.