Oh my god, girls, I'm over here.
Hi, come on over!
Girlfriend, it's so good to see you.
Oh my god, it's so great to meet you as well.
Jackie's told me so much about you.
The food is so good here.
And they have a salad bar.
Jackie told me you were diabetic.
I made sure this whole place was diabetic,
friendly.
I got to you, girl.
So do you think we should tell them she has diabetes,
so we can sit down faster?
Are you sure you can have that?
They have pasta, too.
You're having the bullies.
Girl, you mean the bull nays?
I can't read either.
She'll have the pasta.
Hold on.
You need whatever you want.
Lucky?
Oh my god, does that make you the good diabetic?
Oh, person with diabetes.
Oh my god, that's so cute.
I love that.
Wait, did I just become an ally?
Oh, so yummy.
Are you okay over there?
How are your levels?
Can we be so full of salad?
What was that?
You're low, insulin.
Does anyone have insulin?
Don't worry, guys.
I've used an epipen.
I'm not afraid to use it.
It's a lint.
We should be get some.
Oh, I don't know if they're going to have anything
without sugar, though.
We could go somewhere after for you.
I'm going to ask, hold on.
Hi, I'm here with a person with the good diabetes.
Do you have any good options for people like that?