I just got some new Diabetes Tech that I've never used before.
Let's open this thing up.
It is a tandem mobile.
Look at that.
It doesn't have a screen on it.
It is all controlled from the phone.
And I'm trying it out for 90 days.
Very exciting.
I've got a package of 10 adhesive sleeves.
So what you can do with the mobile is you can adhere it to your skin
with the infusion set kind of coming out with these little sleeves.
You actually have to pay for these separately.
Five of these big boxes of two milliliter cartridges.
So this little cartridge goes into the pump and holds up to 200 units of insulin.
You've got five boxes of auto soft, XC infusion sets.
Here's what they look like.
The cool thing about wearing a tube pump will be the ability for me to un-latch
from this infusion set.
That's on me.
If I'm going to shower, we're going to swim.
I've never had a tube before.
It will be very interesting.
I love the tubeless life.
Let's open up the little mobile and check that out.
Wow.
Look at that.
There it is.
This thing is super, super small.
There is the charger.
The wireless cheat charger.
So you put the pump onto there.
I'm excited for this 90 day journey.
Be sure to comment with any questions.
Whether it be on my YouTube, my podcast or on social media or my newsletter and blog
follow for more diabetes tech news and updates on mobile.