Hey guys, Justin Tech here, and today I've got a bunch of gadgets that are going to help you
upgrade your at home shooting setup, whether you're a TikTok star, you need to hold that
camera easily, light yourself, or get some good audio, or maybe you're an actor being asked
to film yourself, this stuff is going to upgrade your audio, lighting, and shooting. Here it is.
Hello everyone, I've got a nice tripod that you can mount your phone on from my friends at
Movo Photo. Get some good audio with this boom mic, and it's got a leveler that way you know
your shot is always leveled. You can also pick up this tripod and do some solo action,
or even just walk around and shoot other things. And for your TikTok stars, you can set it down like this
or pick it up. Now what's really great about this as well is it comes with this extension.
So when you're stationary for zoom calls or interviews, you can set it to an ideal height.
This entire setup you're seeing right here is $100 and of course it comes with a connector that's
going to allow you to connect the microphone to your phone, both Android and iPhone. I'm going to test
out this mic so let's switch over to that. And this is the microphone. Hey, boom mic, how are you? So
this is the Movo Photo, boom mic, and I think it sounds pretty good. You tell me in the comments.
If you want to add in some more lighting, they have an LED light that has three different
settings and this is a shoe bracket. This will allow you to put both the microphone and the LED light right
on top. Oh, and I almost forgot it comes with a cute little carrying case so you can take it nowhere.
Movo Photo also sells a bunch of other setups. This is just my favorite. They have a bunch of setups
for holding on your hand. Some other lighting and some other mics. I will have links to all
this in the description. Oh my god Chelsea, you're so funny. Who's Chelsea? There is no Chelsea.
Also, can we just talk about how cute their labeling is. Look at this. Look at this. If you're happy
you read this side and if you're sad, you read this side. All of this has a two year warranty. Next up is
the moment lens. The moment lens is lens that you can attach to your phone using their
moment phone case. This right here is the 18 millimeter wide lens and what I love about this is it
allows me to create a much wider shot from my phone through video or photos. I could see real
tours dancers or just any creatives getting some great wide photos and videos with this. And they
also sell a bunch of different lens. This is my favorite though. The starter kit is $115.
Ta-da. Next up, if you're looking for a little bit of a nicer camera, I highly recommend the
Osmo Pocket. It has a three axis stabilizer. So when you're shooting with this thing and you're doing
cool moves, this thing is going to slowly move and keep it stable. We're actually using a stabilizer
on this camera right here. We've grown in SC which is basically a much bigger version of this
right there. So you see as that camera moves, that's kind of what's happening with this camera. It also
connects to your phone with an adapter. It's going to work with iPhones and also Android. It'll connect
right like that. The cheapest I found in the Osmo Pocket right now is 330 on Amazon and that length
is in the description. Cool thing about this thing. If you tap the button three times.
Do a selfie. Hi, come see my home. No, that's a different video. Oh, and it's also got facial
tracking and a bunch of other user friendly abilities. And if you want to get a stabilizer but you just
don't want to pay that much, they do sell one for your phones called the DJI Osmo Mobile 3. So basically
creates that stabilizer for your phone and that goes for $89. Next, I want to show you guys the
LED lights that I'm using to light up my set. They're pretty inexpensive and they're pretty cool. So here
they are. These are the newer LED lights spelled with two ease. And what's great about these is they do
take batteries but they're also plug in and then you can control the light you want. So if you want very
white light or if you want yellow light, you can control that and dim and brighten them. These are four
two of them. You get the stand and the light for 179. Well guys, I hope that this video made you
happy and it didn't make you sad. Anyway, I hope you guys found this video helpful for more tech tips and
recommendations. Also, a smart home series coming your way soon. Subscribe to my channel right down there
and click the bell for alerts. And if you enjoyed this video, please give it a like that really helps me out.
And again, all of the links to everything I talked to in this video, those are in the description and
their affiliate links. So when you use those, you really help support my channel. I'm Justin. I'll take it later.
Yeah, I'll just be like, I'm going to come right now. I'll come right over here. Hey! Okay, so I'll do.