Sernova is one of the many companies working on a cure for type 1 diabetes.
Its unique approach in plants insulin producing cells into a bio-engineered cell pouch,
and in early studies, has helped some people with diabetes achieve full insulin independence
for years.
But with challenges like immunosuppressants and scaling the technology for widespread use,
there's still a long road ahead.
Welcome to the show, I'm Justin, I have Type 1 Diabetes and I hope for it to be cured one day.
On here I talk off things diabetes tech news and management.
Last week we did an entire episode on the landscape of the cure research going into a cure for Type 1 Diabetes.
Today we've got fellow T1D and the CEO of Sernova, Jonathan Rigby.
He's joining me to share his personal journey in the diabetes and cure space.
Why this mission is so close to his heart and how Sernova's decade-long pursuit of a cure is evolving.
We get into the technology behind its cell pouch, the clinical trials that have already changed lives,
and the exciting next steps, including advances in stem cell derived isles and gene edited cells that could
eventually eliminate the need for immunosuppressants.
Keep in mind that anything here on the show is for educational purposes only, it is not medical advice,
always consult with a physician before making changes to your health care.
Now for the conversation.
Jonathan, welcome to the show, it's so great to have you on.
Thank you for having me, Justin, it's great to see you.
Of course, yeah, I've heard a lot about your research, your studies, your approach.
In fact, I had someone on the show who was kind of giving me the landscape of cures,
but getting a deeper dive in what Sernova's doing is exciting and I can't wait for everyone to hear
what's going on, but before we dive into that, I want to understand how you got involved in all this.
What's your background? How did you get into research for a cure?
Oh my word, I miss being a long journey to be honest, Justin, so I grew up in the UK and I'm a biologist,
but when I was at the ripe old age of 18 years old, I was diagnosed with type 1 diabetes.
I'm highly sure that I was type 1 for many years before I was diagnosed, so I guess most of my life
I've been diabetic and so it's something very close to my heart and even close to my pancreas.
I've been working in the pharmaceutical biotech field for just over 30 years now and I started
my career with big pharmaceutical companies and I really enjoyed that and then I figured I
maybe better suited to smaller companies where my efforts could yield a meaningful impact because I
got a great deal of satisfaction from working with fantastic teams that get drug products approved
for serious medical diseases. So when I was in the UK we got a couple of products approved for
pulmonary arterial hypertension and for cystic fibrosis. But I had my very keen eye
open scanning the horizon in the San Francisco Bay area where I was fascinated by the entrepreneurial
spirit. The finance things that were going on a lot of these scientific developments and I
particularly had an interest in a company called Aradam Corporation that were developing
inhaled insulin for the treatment of type 1 diabetes in collaboration with normal Nordisk.
And so a long story short I for the angle of myself a job and relocated the family from the UK to
California and that's where a lot of this began. How did you get involved with Sernova?
When did that start? Yeah okay so you know I moved out from Aradam and I co-founded my first
biotech company with a friend of the colleague called Sogenics. It was a CNS company and you know we
find us the company we grew the company we got a drug product approved and marketed for migraine
which is that company public and it went on to develop a drug for a rare disease called drove a syndrome
which is a terrible form of epileptic effects in children. So that that company was acquired
and then I went on to found a company called steady-med in the bay area to develop a drug product for pulmonary
arterial hypertension which with that company public and that company was also acquired. So in between
these things there were some pretty prestigious investors in New York and the Bay Area that invested
their capital into a company called Zeris Pharmaceuticals that at the time were developing the world's first
liquid-stable glucogon to treat severe hyperglycemia for type 1 diabetes and they asked me to
represent them on the board of Zeris which I was happy to do and then the company had a technical
setback and so they asked me to work on that and fix it and with again surrounded by a great team
we fixed the problem and that company went on to do a public offering as well and the product is approved
it sits on my bedside cabinet in the room behind me hoping that I never need to use it to
get a wife use it to get out of it to get out of it to be a happy glycemic. So I also on the board
of a company called IMtheraputix, they are developing a drug product to delay the onset of type 1 diabetes
I was on the board of a company called Thermaline that was developing a liquid a thermostable insulin
for countries that don't have called supply chain mechanism systems in place and then a few other
things but middle of last year I decided to look for something new and exciting to do
and a colleague of mine who I sit on a board with a cancer company board told me about Sermilva
frankly I haven't heard of the company but you know I started to look at the technology
this vision of developing a functional cure for type 1 diabetes and and I was sold you know I
looked at the data I looked at the technology and they asked me to join as a member of the board of
director's arranging to live last year and happily did so with the short period of time they asked me
to become the executive chairman and help capitalise the company so I said yes
that a little bit after that asked me to be the CEO and of course I joined
again because this is something very very personal for me and I believe in the future of the company
wow well thank you for telling me all of that because it's it's so interesting here people like
use your background and and all the work you've done in this field it it does sound personal to you and
it gives me hope every time I have someone like you on my show who lives with this disease
understands the struggle and genuinely wants to make it better in some way and to get to work on something
that can do that is is incredible so thank you for all the work you've done so far I'm I'm excited about
the work you're doing here and I think what that what someone like you also helps give me hope with
is you know so many people are jaded that there will ever be a cure you know people have been told for
years five to ten years there will be a cure and at this point people are over it they don't think it's
coming but when I hear about people who live with this disease working on that cure that gives me hope
because these people people like you want to see the cure because it will better your life too right that's a big
investment what are your thoughts on this fact that you know everyone's heard five to ten years there will
be a cure I mean have you been hearing that your whole life and do you think that we're actually at a
point where maybe that's true now just in first of all thank you for the thanks but I also thank
yourself for the great exposure of development stage technologies should products etc that you make
because that contribute significantly to the knowledge base of people in the field of diabetes
and for parents children caregivers who are frightened to death because of the disease that
their friends, their relatives, their husbands, wives, children have so a fact thanks to you and yes my father
ever since I became diabetic would send me newspaper articles you know three mice in the laboratory
and Liverpool hospital are no longer diabetic or you know there's a cure around the corner and I think back
to when you know literally a hundred years ago and before then diabetes was a death sentence
you were you are certain to die pretty darn quickly and I think of the scientists in Canada in London
Ontario and Toronto, Bunting and Baston and Colip you know they probably thought they could never do anything about this
but they did you know the breakthrough was made insulin was discovered it went sounds to be purified
and in fact when I was diagnosed I was injecting myself with porcelain insulin from a glass syringe
that was I would reuse over and over every single day terribly blunt and nasty thick needles
and no way to measure my blood sugar so you think about where we've come since then to where we are today
so now you know I'm the the benefactor of I use an insulin pump I use a continuous glucose meter
like a new you do and it's a it's a millennia of progress from where where I used to be and obviously
now we're injecting a recombinant human insulin which is very very similar to where we are now
to normal instant but we've got a long way to go and so I have absolutely no a day to my mind
that one day people will say do you remember that disease called diabetes you know it's it's gone
and there'll be a lot of people responsible for fixing this disease, curing this disease and
you know helping people live the lives of a daily basis yeah I really do hope for a day when we can say that
and I hope it's during my lifetime because I think that would just be so incredible to see
it would feel like a payoff I think to your work even to my work I think to so many people's work it would
feel really gratifying and then I guess just to be able to have my diabetes cared would be quite nice
this episode is sponsored by OmniPod as someone with T1D and with an incredibly active lifestyle it's
important for me not to get tied up especially with tubes on my insulin pump I love to go swimming,
lift weights and play kickball with friends and with OmniPod 5 I never have to worry about tubes
getting in the way plus not having to disconnect helps me to stay in range during all of my
favorite physical activities that includes sexy time too see if you're eligible for a 30 day
trial by visiting OmniPod.com slash dive tech on there you'll see full safety and risk information
and trial terms that's OmniPod.com slash dive tech let's get into Sernova tell us a little bit about
the company is the cure for diabetes what Sernova's always been focused on? Yes it has it's mainly focused
on type one diabetes we are doing some work in thyroid disease and hemophilia as well but the main focus is
always being type one diabetes the concept of replacing dysfunctional cells that are normal
pankers would have so the alpha cells are beta cells and the delta cells and so the company
going back in history developed what you can see here on the screen we call this our cell poached technology
and it literally is a poached and it's made from implantable, playable, surgical mesh so what
the physician does right now in our clinical trial is the physician will surgically implant this beneath
the skin of your abdomen but above the muscle fascia of your abdomen then what happens your blood vessels
grow around this they grow in it and they grow through it and we call it a bio hybrid organ so it
literally turns into what we call a bio hybrid organ we can see these horizontal channels there are plastic
rods essentially so when this has become vascularized the surgeon will go into under your skin again
it will pull these rods out leaving these cylindrical cylinders inside the pouch into which
he will then now she will then impregnate this with functional eyelet cells and so that's the technology
and we've been working on this for several years now and we are partly through the phase one to clinical
trial which means your evaluating principle is safety and also you're looking for efficacy
and the efficacy that we've been looking for is patients becoming insulin independent and what that
means it means that you no longer have to rely on your insulin pump, on your auto injector, on your vials and so
inches and you can go back your daily life without that as you know is a burden of some
way of treating T one day at the moment and in the first call hot we are six patients and all of those
six patients achieved insulin independence for varying lengths of time I don't want to over promise
and over stay where we are you know we are still very much in the research and development stage
but we have more patients in the study now and then next year we'll be moving to a different kind of
cell cells that I'd be happy to talk to you about it. Yeah a few of the things that you've mentioned I want
to dig deeper into but before we do where did the idea for a cell pouch come from it it seems so different
and unique compared to a lot of the other research out there why was this approach important for
certain of it to to focus on. Yeah so the scientific founders of the organisation you know
understood the debut going to try and cure human diseases that are related to dysfunctional cells
you need to have a mechanism or vehicle into which you can put the cells that you take them from
external you put them inside and one of the things that they've used being critical was retrievability
so if you put the cells into an organ into a muscle just into your skin have an preventeness but
should there be a problem it's preferable to be able to remove them so the cell pouch does a few things it
allows this containment system that can be retrieved of necessary but it also turns into this
vascularised organ so these cells need to live then you do oxygen they need nutrients and if they are
in something that isn't porous and in contact with the circulatory system and the chance that they will die
so that's where the idea came from and that's what we're diligently working on today. When someone gets the
pouch inserted is it on the outside like is it something you can see through see and feel through the
skin or is it like behind the muscles is so you have your muscles then on top of that you have the skin
and there's kind of a gap between so it goes into that gap so it sits on top of the muscles but underneath
your skin which allows for this prolific vascularisation and when the patients have these
implanted they don't feel anything you can't see it you can't feel it and they they forget about it
okay I mean I'm just so if I was you know had a six pack I don't right now because I'm you know
I just haven't been on my routine I I've never had a six pack but I've been toned anyway
if and when I have a six pack if I had this I wouldn't be able to see it like it wouldn't be over my
abs if I like was that cut or what it I'm just curious. No you wouldn't be able to see it it's incredibly
thin and incredibly malleable and it literally gets surrounded by blood vessels so you you can't see it
I know that this approach requires immunosuppressants. Can you explain to us why they are needed in this approach
currently? Yes well it's an interesting question because you and I are diabetic because of our
immune system. Not a lot of people know that so your immune system is your best friend
where it's fighting off millions and millions of bacteria viruses and cancer cells every single day
but it can it can turn around and attack the body's own cells and there are lots of diseases
caused by the immune system we call them autoimmune diseases and type one diabetes is an autoimmune disease
so once upon a time the immune system decided to draw a destroyer pancreas and one day decided to
destroy my pancreas and so what we need to do if you introduce a foreign object into a body be
there in this case obviously a cell a biological cell your immune system has the propensity to
recognize that it's not natural it's not native to your body and it will attack them so you know if
you have a heart transplant a kidney transplant any kind of transplant where you're introducing a foreign
cell or a foreign article into your body we need to tap that immune system down to stop at attacking
the organ or in our case the cells that have been implanted so there's a fine balance there between
suppressing immune system to a point where it's not attacking the cells but it's still able to fight
off the bacteria and the viruses that I mentioned we know there is a ongoing science
where people are looking at coating these cells with various matrices so that they essentially become
invisible to your immune system other our company is looking at gene editing the cells so what's
again they become I'm using the word invisible but they are not recognized by the immune system
there was a company that recently put out a little bit of good data on these gene editing cells
being implanted but that's quite a way into the phara rising let's get into the clinical trials
so far so I know there there was that first study when was that conducted and what were the
qualifications for the patients who took part in it? I'm sure there were many but I kind of want to have
a good idea of who these people were. No problem so this study's actually been going on for a number of years
what's been rate limiting to the progress the cells that we are putting in the cell approach right now
the isle cells which are the cells that you how in your pancreas we are obtaining those from human donors
so these are kind of very cells and so we know we can control how many of those we can get access to
we're waiting for donors and not can we control the quality and consistency of those cells
so the study's been going on for a number of years now but we also signed a collaboration
with a company in Germany called Evil Tech and they are using induced pleuriportive stem cells
to manufacture human isle clusters so these are cells that are biologically made from stem cells
they differentiate into isle cells so that is a program that we have going on at the moment and our
hope and expectation is that next year in 2026 will be in the clinic with these stem cells so that
does a number of things for us you know we have then have an abundant supply of cells we know that
they are all consistent in quality and there is no limit to how many cells we can make so in power
of that we've been doing our trial and looking to optimize and understand how many cells we need to put in
these approaches depending on the on the on the on the weight of the patient principally and we've been
optimizing the immune suppression regime and we're making good progress and we are very
confident that next year we'll be in the clinic with these eyelet-like clusters managed
actually by Evil Tech so that's an exciting day that I'm looking forward to so I want to
let people know also you know a lot of people are going to listen to this and be like well when
how can I sign up I want to be part of these trials but I know that when you're when you're
taking on people for these clinical trials it's a very specific type of patient that you want to
bring on it's not your everyday person who's got a pretty good A1C and is managing pretty well right
like you need to be pretty specific who are these people that are part of these trials what what is
their situation often like yeah so just in your your correct we we call it inclusion criteria
so we and the investigators and the trials specify what kind of patients are eligible to enter
into the trial and some of the things that I can disclose you know these patients have to be
over 18 years of age after have a body mass index that is reasonably in control and in range
but importantly they need to have demonstrated a history of severe hypoglycemia and
nocturnal hypoglycemia so these are pretty sick people however was fascinating you know people are
diligent a lot of the time a lot of the time they're absolutely not so we have a mix of people in the
trial some with high HBA1Cs which you know is a is a mechanism is a test for
seeing how well controlled your diabetes is over the last three months so we have some people who were in
the normal range which is less than 6.5% of the glycated hemoglobin and then there were patients that
were 10, 12, 13 which you will know that's a very very high number and what we saw in those trials
so the patients that had their A1Cs already controlled even though it's tremendous burden for
them to control the diabetes they have a controlled A1C over period of time this when they were on the
cell post therapy they maintained that good glycemic control but without having to do all of the
million things that you and I have to do every day to control our blood sugar and then the people
that had high A1Cs in the 910 11 range those came down into the normal range so from 10 to
below 6 to 6 and to put that into perspective because it doesn't sound like very much there are many
many studies showing that if you reduce your A1C by 1% you reduce the incidence of cardiovascular
problems, myocardial infarction by about 14%. So bringing that A1C is critical to the long term
control of cold morbidities associated with type 1 diabetes that a lot of people frankly forget about
these patients of with this study I know that there was one who became insulin independent for over
five years. Where's that patient now? How are they doing? Are they still insulin dependent?
Independent? How long has it been? What's what's going on with them? Yes so that was actually the first
patient in the trial and this lady whose name I can't mention she became insulin independent
the beginning of the trial and she was still insulin independent after four and a half years.
Unfortunately and there were no additional surgeries, no additional transplants,
or implants of cells after four and a half years she developed another condition which meant
unrelated to what the study that we were conducting and she had to stop her immune suppression.
So that meant that she had to commit a trial so we had the opportunity then to retrieve the cell
pouches and we retrieved them and we showed that the cell pouches were at no fibrosis,
the structural integrity was a hundred percent intact and then we went on to do histological analysis
of cell analysis of the eyelet cells in the pouches and we showed at abundance of fully functional cells
producing the three hormones that you need to control diabetes. So you know people when you
you talk about type one diabetes they said oh you just need insulin what's the problem?
But the normal person on the street the pancreas makes three hormones. So you have insulin that's
razor blood sugar down but in a normal pancreas you also decrease a hormone called glucone
which raises your blood sugar to prevent you going high pole glycemic which is as you know is
not a pleasant thing and is life threatening but then also a hormone called somatostatic that controls
insulin and glucocone and keeps your blood sugar in the normal range. So what we're doing here
we're not just providing patients with replacements of their insulin we're providing them with normal glycemic
control associated with all three hormones that are secreted by pancreas. Okay and I know that
there were another what five or six patients that became insulin independent. What what's the status
of those patients? So some of them are still going on so they're still you know they're still being
monitored by the clinical trial site and still insulin independent and some of them had to stop
three before various reasons. Again let's be realistic here you know this is a an early stage
proof of concept clinical trial upon which we will build year on year until we get this approved.
How long are you going to monitor all of these patients? We monitor if they're still on the therapy we
monitor them all the time you know these patients they're still used continuously cosmeters
so they can see every every minute of everyday what the blood sugar is. In fact our
principal investigator he has the continuously cos graphs and charts on his phone as well. So these
people have been monitored very safe then we there are obviously safety measures in place for when you're
running a clinical trial and those we take those very seriously and we monitor these people all the time.
Okay and I know that some people failed with this treatment. What were you seeing there? What was
what did you come up with the reason as to why some people you know it wasn't taking for them?
Yeah so in the second part of this trial we call it cohort B. What we were trying to do was put more
cells in but also try to reach a immune suppression regime that is well tolerated these these
regimes can be polluted by people but it gets to that level where we're not causing the immune system
to allow your immune sort of the immune suppressants allowing your immune system to attack the cells.
So you know in very late months term we've been turning knobs on the cooker head to try and
balance all of this out. So in some of those patients we have some of them ongoing that are insulin
independent in this second cohort and then we have others that failed and you know that's what we need to
know we need to know what works and we need to know what doesn't work so that when we move into the next
cohort we'll you know you take a big step forward each time you do these these trials.
Are you recruiting at all right now for for any trials or are you kind of working with what you have for now?
No okay yeah if you want to learn where this you know this contact information on our website
Feel free to send us an email yeah I'll put that I'll put a link to that in the show notes
Today's episode is sponsored by T1D Exchange you can directly make an impact on diabetes health care
treatments and technology by participating in the T1D Exchange registry it starts with the simple survey about your
life with T1D and it only takes about 15 minutes after that you'll have a personal portal with ongoing
T1D study and survey opportunities plus some of these studies even offer compensation
signing up with the link in the show notes help support my channel and it allows me to continue putting
out free content you can sign up at t1dxchange.org slash diabetic or click that link in today's show notes
So let's talk about kind of what's next for Sernova you mentioned the stem cell derived
Islet cells can you kind of explain that to us a little more deeply as to why that will be helpful right like right now
You're relying on donations of cells right so this could be an opportunity to just mass produced is that what this is
It's a certainly mass production and but when you obtain a donor cell so unfortunately these
poor people are deceased and they are on the organ donor list and the pancreas and other organs are
retrieved and you know thank the law of four people willing to do this and so when the cells are
harvested from one to the best phrase they are not always the same
you know taking cells from a deceased organ and putting it into a healthy
human being it is miraculous and you know we've been able to achieve that and you know organ transplantation
there's been able to achieve that but there are limitations on quantity as you said but also on quality
so deriving these Islet cells from stem cells allows us to address the quantity issue
because they're made in a in a GMP laboratory facility so you can make as many as as you like
and and they are all will be the same consistency and quality and the cells that we have so far we've
done them in pre clinical studies and they two produce insulin glucogram and somatic statin
and we've done some animal models where these animals are induced to be diabetic and of course
their blood sugar flies sky high and then you know they are the other recipients of transplants of these cells
and then that blood sugar comes into the normal range we see a very flat line just in a
unit I could show our curves and our phones now we we don't have flat lines but these high quality
highly functioning cells are in the normal range for the duration of the study and even when you give the
the animals a high glucose diet you know a high carbohydrate diet to see of the blood sugar spikes
it doesn't it stays controlled so it's the future and when we get there we can say we we had a functional
cure will it work for everybody who knows I don't know these stem cell derived Islet cells are these one
step toward the gene edited cells that you're working on that would that wouldn't require immunosuppressants
kind of are there some phases that you have to go on before you get to a cell that evades immunosystem
yes you're absolutely correct so the the stem cell derived Islet cells will be our first entry into the
into the marketplace if you like and then in power law we will continue to work on these gene edited cells
and then the expectations that one day the stem cells would be surpassed by the gene edited cells
well they're still stem cells but they edit the genes so that the the surface of the cells is it's not
recognizable by the by the immune system so that's the I'm not sure this is an appropriate phrase but
that would be the holy grail yeah what would you say is the big obstacle here the big obstacle is science
it takes a lot of time to validate the science scale up the manufacturing to make sure that everything is
at a very very high level of quality and that the cells are very very safe you have to prove that
in many many studies so it is a time under money candidly it just takes a long time to do this work
so um recently a company sent a biotechnology they put out research that their approach
for a cure doesn't require immunosuppressants what did you find interesting about their approach
I was fascinating um they implanted these cells into the four muscle of the patient with type one
diabetes and they monitored their insulin use and their glucose control over a month of a 28 days
and at the end of the 28 days they didn't see anything of safety concern and they did see
insulin independence so the patients was wasn't not needing to give themselves exogenous insulin
so that's that's wonderful news but we also have to put it into some kind of perspective it was one
patient over 28 days so ultimately you're going to need data on many many patients for a long
long time so great news but it's very early is there some form of crowdsourcing of information
like you have Santa biotech coming out saying they did this you have vertex building a factory for
their derived stem cells I'm sure you're not trading super secret stuff but is there some form of
when you hear a company do something oh maybe that's a direction we kind of go into or or is there
some form of communication going on between these companies there is I mean there's definitely
communication and we communicate with people in the field they're interested in what we are doing
they're interested in what they're doing and you're all of these clinical trials particularly
in countries like the United States you have to get permission to do them by the US FDA the food and
drug administration so those drug applications the protocols for doing the trials they are public
so you can go on to pubmed.gov is called and you can read our clinical trial design you can read
vertex is clinical trial designs what kind of patients they're looking exactly how that that
I can do up to these studies and then there's an obligation when you get the data when you the trial
completes that you have to disclose the good the button the indifference and each trial especially
early there's good sometimes bad and indifference data so it's very very transparent what people are doing
and then people like to publish their their information and have peers review their information and
present them a conference is so it's a very transparent organization actually Jonathan thank you so much
for coming on the show I'm so glad that we got a deep dive on what Cernova's going on it's very unique
and I'm excited to see you know how it evolves I'm glad to hear that it won't affect people six packs so that's
great but yeah this was this was super enlightening it's great to hear that someone like you is working on it
is very close to the project and and I'm hopeful for for the future trials that you have going on
well thank you Justin and I I don't need our deserve any praise because I'm surrounded by
great teams great scientists people that curb it this and I'm just one of the one of the
little cogs and the big mechanical clock but thank you and again thank you for the exposure that you give
because it's important that people know that we are working on this it's important for people who
the reality I'm doing this it's not an easy task but look at Ryan there are many many diseases
that have been cured many many diseases were years ago we were also death sentences but the farmer
farmer and biotech industry are fixing them in a pretty rapid succession so all good what do you think
about Cernova's approach let me know in the comments on YouTube and what do you think of the landscape
of diabetes cures did you watch last weeks episode if you didn't you gotta check that out I'll throw
that in the show notes and if there are any cures out there that you want me to speak with someone from
that company I will do my best Cernova reached out to me I think and luckily we could get something down
but vertex I've been trying they're they're not they're not into it but maybe there are some other
companies so let me know who you want to hear from in the comments and if you aren't already subscribed to
our blog and newsletter I've got articles going up every week on there as well as a newsletter coming
out every other week on diabetic.behive.com there's a link to that in the show notes you can click that and you
can subscribe to our newsletter that way you know what is going on in diabetic content as well as the latest
and greatest in diabetes technology news until next week I'm Justin I'll take you later