Hey everyone, Justin Tech here and today I am joined by Mr. Cain Blake of Cain's Way YouTube. Check them out.
Howdy. Today we are playing some V-R.
He's gonna be fun. We are playing raw data, which is this first person shooter. It is multi-player.
So we are going to be playing together.
Look down. Look your left waist. Left side of your waist. And then we'll pick up your bone.
I mean, hold it. And then you can't let go.
Yeah, you literally go get it. You'll get it. Hold a little string part.
And then pull it back and let go.
Oh my god, the...
Oh, yeah.
You're gonna do your good. Just lightly put your figure on your seat and then press it.
Oh, you're so pretty. Now I am going to join Cain in the TRX spirit.
All right Cain. Hi, I'm in here.
Oh, that's crazy. Where do you go?
Up. Way to go right there. Hey.
And there we go. Look up.
Oh, holy crap. What is happening right now?
All right, so Cain, we want to go up and get that handle.
And then put it in that keyhole.
Not going to work.
Oh.
That's good.
So then put it in.
Oh, there's so many stuff in.
There's so many things in.
Oh, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
Oh, just literally just don't want to go.
There's an invisible guy.
We got a come on.
Oh, there's a visible guy.
Oh, there's my...
Oh, I don't know.
Oh, there's a visible guy. Oh, there's a visible guy.
Oh, there's a visible guy.
He got me.
He got you.
Come here, drones.
Oh my god!
Okay, yeah, she wants it. There is so much work my shoulder is killing me
Oh my god, this is like a what up I've gone check it off
Oh
Oh shit oh shit oh shit oh shit oh shit oh shit
Yeah
You do some bootcast
Let's see, all right, I'm about to get it soon. Yeah, okay
Okay, it's like a giving you a massage right there. Oh, so take me thought you lost your head
Oh
I was not even a really difficult level. Oh my god, I've been on part with them. I can understand why people like I want to stay in that world
It's literally real like so you're in
Squisting if you want to try VR as well, you can totally check it out at
Any local best by our game stop if you live in New York like New York City or LA
There's the IMX VR experience that you can go check out and it's like $10 an experience and it's definitely a good way to try it out
Thank you cane for checking out the VR with me. It was fun. I'm a little bit about your channel
So the channel called Cain's Way you check and check it out at youtube.com
full slash cain's way and all my social media
Cain's way so check it out did a video with this one collaboration check it out. We made cupcakes with other hands
We did and it was a lot of fun as always please like and subscribe this video to stay tuned with all of my future videos and I will see you later