Hey everyone and welcome back to my Magic Leap series with many of us social distancing and
working from home these days, we've found new ways to work and communicate with our friends,
families, and co-workers, aka lots of video chats.
While these video chats have proven useful, they still don't provide that presence for
use to in person, right Max?
Right.
Today I partnered up with Magic Leap to show you how co-presents in spatial computing,
can be an excellent alternative to these flat screen-based communications like video chat,
and provide experiences that really are the next best thing to be in person.
I think now more than ever, spatial computing shines, and I'm really excited to show you
how to be used.
So here we go!
Let's start with spatial.
Spatial is a great option for businesses and colleagues to build a shared workspace where you can
meet up as holograms, the app provides the ability to create persistent room so you can save
your information and return to it in future meetings.
You can even set up social rooms like the office water cooler where people can have conversations
about Tiger King and add a nice social break to their day.
Now to show you spatial in action, I'm going to meet some Magic Leap members in the series room,
and oh my god, it looks like they are there, and I am late, so let's go to the room.
Hey, Katie, have a talk, Katie.
Hey, thank you, hey, how's it going?
Thank you guys for coming over, my place is Taylor.
Oh wow, Taylor's right, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I was legitimately taken a back by how real it felt to have their holograms in my room.
Spatial is cross-platform, it could be used on your magically desktop and phone, so even if someone
lacks a headset, they can join and follow along.
Hey guys, am I late?
Yeah, but does Tigerly matter anymore?
There are lots of cool features.
You can upload media for your computer, if I mean?
Yep, there it is, screen share, so that's my desktop.
That is way too many tabs.
Place notes, photos, and videos on display, view 3D models, and even sketch on them.
This meeting only had four of us, but spatial can support up to 30 users and headsets
in one room at a time.
Taylor explained the benefits of using spatial for company meetings and presentations.
You can see the people are more engaged, you can watch the people are actually looking at the
presentation versus just like trying their video off and fiddling with something else while you're
listening to something in the background.
It does feel like you're in the room with me right now.
Having a conversation, making eye contact with me?
If this could be useful for you, why don't you try it out?
Magic Leaf has launched the Quick Start Collaboration Package with Spatial,
which allows you to set up four headsets with your company and try it out for 45 days.
I placed a link with details in the description.
Now, let's head over to Meetings a free native app included on the headset for a bit of a different experience.
Magic Leaf has repurposed avatar chat into meetings.
You can now invite local and remote users to join your meetings using a code.
In meetings, you can chat, share your affiliate web browser screens, and share and collaborate
on 2D and 3D content.
The app includes beta collaboration features in the gallery app,
so attendees can draw and comment on 3D.glb models.
You can import these images easily using the desktop companion app.
How are your weekends?
Well, you might see the grocery store was fun.
But as you do just, I played Animal Crossing on my Switch and then ate a lot of food.
The avatar's and meetings are much more expressive than Spatials.
These avatars have head tracking, hand tracking, and eye tracking,
so you can make direct eye contact with others.
And you can tell when they're not paying attention.
There's also a new dedicated outfit out where you can personalize your avatar's physique and accessories.
But there are still no moles.
Come on Magic Leaf, help me out here, get it together.
And lastly, with the Helio web browser, you can create your own workspace with multiple documents,
videos and websites open at a time.
You can also throw up video chats like Google Hangouts and make the screen really big.
It's me again, I'm still not wearing pants.
And you can use that Logitech keyboard I talked about in my last video to toggle between browser screen
easily. Best of all, these screens will stay where you left them each time you pick up your headsets.
You can easily hop back into your daily routine.
You can also personalize your workspace with images uploaded using the desktop companion app.
I went into detail on this in my last video and if you guys want to check that out,
I place it in the description.
In just the last few weeks, we've seen an instantaneous shift to remote work.
And evidence that some companies can work just as well if not better.
People are realizing they don't need to hop on a plane or physically go to their office for that meeting.
Although this shift wasn't voluntary, it may have changed the way we work together
and began a completely new era workflow.
Spatial computing widens that gap even further and introduces a more life-like way to collaborate
in a physical space without actually having to be there.
I'm looking at your avatar next to Keyans and like no offense but Keyans' posture looks better than yours.
That's the first.
I think this technology becomes more well-known.
Companies will switch from 2D video chats to 3D holograms.
I hope this video has you just as excited as I am about these new ways of collaborating.
And if you want to continue this journey with me,
one of you guys click that subscribe button down there and click that bell for alerts you don't miss a video.
And if you enjoyed this, give it a like.
For more magically videos, stay tuned. We have more coming.
And if you want to watch my other ones, click that playlist right there.
I'm Justin and I'll take you later.
Right Max?
Right!
But I can fart more often now.