Hey guys, welcome to my review of the Philips Hue Play HDMI Sync Box. I'm so excited about this thing.
I've been waiting for it as we all have and it is finally here and I have so much to tell you.
This device will basically take what is playing on your TV screen and have all of your Philips Hue lights in sync with that media.
This video is going to cover a lot. I'm going to show you how it works, how to set it up. I'm going to have it play in action
and then I'm going to tell you whether or not you should get it. Also, any Philips Hue devices that I bring up in this video,
they will be in the description below. So check out that link if you want to check out these devices.
And while you're checking it out, why don't you hit that subscribe button and hit it the bell for alerts. That way
when I come out with more Philips Hue videos, you see it. All right, without further ado, let's review the Philips Hue
Play HDMI Sync Box. A lot of words.
The HDMI Sync Box is a sleek looking device that almost looks like a wide Apple TV.
There are four HDMI inputs on the back where you can connect devices like Apple TV, Chromecast,
a Blu-ray player, or a video game system. Once it's connected, you'll be able to watch any
content on your TV and the box will create what I like to call the surround sound of lighting. The box
will use the sound and what's on the screen to completely immerse you into the media. The Hue Sync Box
is intuitive. It knows when you're switching devices. So right now I have it on Apple TV.
When they turn on my Nintendo Switch, it's actually going to act as a switcher and switch over to
the Nintendo Switch. And then the lighting is going to match that. There you go.
Voila! If you have a receiver, don't fret. All you have to do is have the receivers output go into the
HDMI Sync input and then have the output from that go into your TV. So as long as the HDMI Sync
Box is the last thing to plug into your TV, you're good. Unfortunately you can't have the smart TV apps
from your TV go into the Sync Box and then back into the TV. You'll need to buy an external device
like a fire stick or an Apple TV, etc. The HDMI Sync Box supports 4K at 60Hz and HDR10. It does
not support HDR10+, Dolby Vision or Dolby Atmos, which I definitely hope they introduce in the future.
Phillips Hue has included a couple slots in the power cord to connect lights near the TV to save on
outlet space. If you couldn't tell, it came in handy for me. In order to use the Sync Box,
you need a bridge and some lights. You can link up to 10 color-capable Phillips Hue lights through the
app. I do have to say I have a preference for lighting, so let me show you my lighting setup.
Over here, I have a Phillips Hue go right there. Then I also have these Phillips Hue playbars.
And this is where my preference comes in. I definitely prefer to have one of these on either side
because I really like the stands and the light that they shine off on the TV. So I highly recommend
getting those. They also come with an adhesive plate. The adhesive plates really great, especially if you
have a wall mounted TV. Then on top here, I have a Phillips Hue light strip that could also be a
playbar if you wanted. And over here, I have just your everyday colored light bulb by Phillips Hue
in a canister. And I'm going to put that canister in the description below a link for that because I think
it's a great thing to have for any smart home lighting enthusiast like me. All right, let's talk about the
app. First, you will need to download the Phillips Hue Sync app. It is a separate app from the Phillips Hue
app. Once the app is open, you'll need to connect your Hue Sync to the bridge. Then you'll be
instructed to open up the normal Phillips Hue app and set up an entertainment area. This is located
in the setting section of the main Hue app. After that's created, you can add the lights you want to use.
Then you drag around the lights to where they're located in the room and assign the vertical position
by tapping on the light. There's ground height, TV height, and ceiling height. I really love that when
you're setting up a light, it turns green and flashes. This makes it super easy to know which light
you're setting up and it's a great touch. There's also the option to set the behavior of your
lights when the sync stops. So when you stop the sync, your lights can go to a certain setting. I love
this option. I set my lights to dim because I'm most likely you can be using the sync box at night.
Once your entertainment area is set up, it's time to switch back to the Hue Sync app. From there,
you'll have the ability to choose the sync mode, the intensity, the brightness, and finally begin the sync.
All right. The time has come. Let's see how this thing works. Let's get lit.
So there are four intensity modes on the sync box and I'm going to show you all of them side by side.
First, we're going to start by playing a video on my Apple TV. I really wanted to play like Marvel
Avengers or something like that, but copyrights can be difficult with Disney. So you know what? Why
don't we just play some random video on YouTube? This is familiar. We were ready to plug into the virtual world.
So for those of you who don't know what this video is, it's a video on the void VR. This awesome
VR experience that I checked out. You should totally watch the video of your at all interest. So as you
can see, there are a lot of different ways to have your sync box set up. I'd say for me, after watching
video content with a box for a week, I found that I liked the moderate setting with half brightness,
the best for video content. The mini-games were fun, quirky, and simple yet strategic. At one point,
we were shooting pancakes and milkshakes at cats and puppies. Next, let's play some video games.
In this clip, I'm playing the game Astral Chain on Nintendo Switch. I was surprised by how much I enjoyed
playing the games with the sync box. The colors flow seamlessly as I moved from dark to light areas
and truly added to my video game experience. Next up, music. I took a song from my music library and
interplayed it to my Apple TV and set the sync box to extreme.
I love how the lights interact with the beat of the music. I can absolutely see myself using this
when I have parties. What's definitely lacking here is the ability to set the color palette.
Here's sync on the computer allows you to do this and I miss it here. I reached out to Philips
you and they said they planned to include this in the future. Okay, so now for my final thoughts.
With the Philips you play HDMI sync box, you are getting an entire home entertainment lighting
ecosystem. You could switch between devices seamlessly, control the mode, brightness, and intensity,
and you can set a number of user preferences. Some of what you didn't even know you wanted. I was impressed
by how much I enjoyed this box. There's literally no lag between the light and the content on your TV.
The Philips you sync box is $230 and I realize that's not cheap. But if you're looking to invest
in your Philips view system that you already have built, it's worth it. This is going to greatly
enhance your entertainment experience. The lack of HDR10 Plus and Dolby Vision and Dolby Atmos
is a disappointment here. But for someone who doesn't have those implemented, this is a no-brainer.
This is a sophisticated device and I can't think Philips you enough for putting so much thought into it.
Like seriously Philips you, you guys are awesome. This was a great job and I'm excited to see what
else you have in store for us. And if you guys feel the same way, then you should subscribe to this channel
because I have a lot of Philips you videos coming out and I don't want you to miss them. So subscribe right
down there and hit the bell for alerts. Also, if you guys found this video helpful or enjoyed it,
why don't you give me a like because that helps other people find this video. Also, I just want to
give about a huge thank you to everyone who subscribed to my channel so far and has been supporting
me to geek out over technology and tell you what I like and enjoy and maybe find some stuff that you
don't know about. That is my dream and you are definitely supporting it. So from the bottom one,
blah, so from the bottom of my heart, thank you so much. That's all I've got for you guys today.
I hope you enjoyed this video and I can't wait to show you what else I have in store. I'm Justin and I'll
take it later. Thank you. Thank you, sink. Well, I'm thinking. Thank you, sink. Is that a copy written for