Oh, well hello there YouTube, come on to my new smart home.
I just moved, so it's my second smart home.
This video is all about remote to buttons and switches around my smart home
that you can get to make your life way easier and way smarter.
A lot of people out there are saying, why do you need Alexa?
The reason is because I don't want to move, but if I'm okay with moving
or if I ever remote with me, then I'll use that.
I will have all of the links to these products, the best deals I've found
in the bio down below.
So let's come right over here to my power station.
So what we have right here is you may not recognize it, but this is a light switch.
We do not touch these in fact, I should put some tape over those.
What we do use though is this right here, and this is the Phillips Hue
like dimmer switch.
This thing is so, so great.
This alone is $25, but you can also get it for $35 with a light bulb.
I can control up to 10 light bulbs, just with this.
I'm turning them on, off, dimming them.
Great device and super cheap for what it does.
And if you're in the Phillips Hue family, this is like a note-brainer.
I would probably have five of these if I had more two lights around my house or bigger house.
One day YouTube, one day.
The device that I just got in I am in love with is the Logitech Hop.
Actually put bell crow on it.
So that way I can kind of pop it off, put it to it.
For the starter pack, it's $57.
The starter pack includes the bridge for the device and to just get a button.
It's $40 as a smart home, liver and builder and creator.
I'm always looking for a device that connects all of my smart devices and this is it.
I can either tap it once, tap it twice or do a long tap.
Give me three different abilities.
If I tap it once, it turns on all my lights.
If I do a long press, it turns on the parting mode.
What that does is it completely transforms my entire apartment.
It turns off my light lights light into color light bulbs.
Also, right over here, I have my neon smile face.
That turns on with a wemo smart oven.
It sets my living or lights and my kitchen lights to dim.
And it turns on music.
And so whenever I'm gonna have friends, I'll write just long press that.
I actually haven't had many friends over since I've gotten that device soon.
I will.
So when I have friends and then when I have those friends over, I'm going to put party mode on.
One day YouTube, one day.
All I have to do to turn this off.
So that's party mode and I freaking love it.
This next device is one of my favorite devices.
It is the Logitech Harmony Remote.
And what I love about it so much is that it controls my complete entertainments.
So as well as all of my lights, it has a few different buttons right here that control my Apple TV.
My Nintendo Switch.
My speakers.
So if I want to watch a movie on Apple TV, all I do is press this movie button right here.
And it turns on my receiver.
Turns on my Apple TV.
And it will turn on my TV.
And then I can watch a movie.
Then if I want to turn it off, I just click this off button and it turns everything off.
I can change the light set if I want.
So this light right here, it's connected to this.
So if I don't want that on, it can turn off.
If I do want it on, but I want it in a little bit.
And just give it down right there.
And then I can turn this light off because it's a little too bright to the movie.
I want to turn my kitchen light off too.
And then that one.
And then another light bulb.
And then we go to the club.
And then we go out.
And another one.
The Logitech Harmony Remote is 140 dollars.
And it is so worth it.
If you have a system or set up that will fully utilize its potential.
It's sleek, light, and really comfortable in your hands.
Who doesn't like something that's comfortable in your hands?
Next.
So.
It's way right there.
So welcome to my bedroom.
The one and only just a tech bedroom.
Come on.
I have this brand new pop button that I showed you over there.
But this is the gray version of my tablet once.
It will turn my lights on.
I want to get things done.
Some spring cleaning, summer cleaning, winter cleaning.
I could double tap it.
And it goes into like, move lighting when I want to get things done.
And then I can hold it down.
And it's a nice little night like late night.
Then it'll switch.
So like late night pillow talk or just like late night nap time.
Get out of here.
So there's your T's in switches, remote and buttons around a smart home.
Basically, I've done so far.
I have a lot more to do.
Make sure to subscribe down below to stay up to date with all of my tech videos.
And follow me on Instagram.
I've been doing a lot of fun stuff on there.
And you should check it out.
Lots of good deals.
Until next time.
See you later.
Have a good day.
Catch you next time.