Hey guys, welcome to my E-Bags Professional Slim laptop backpack review and unpacking.
Today I'm going to tell you all about the backpack, why I love it, and I'll show you
what I have packed in it for every shoot or vacation.
Cheers!
Also, don't worry, I've placed links for the backpack and all other products I bring
up in the description below.
Before I start, be sure to like this video, subscribe to my channel for more videos like
this, and hit that bell for alerts.
Alright, here we go.
Meet the E-Bags Professional Slim laptop backpack.
The backpack is full of innovative and organized compartments, allowing all of my gear
to have its own place, and it's extremely versatile.
I can plop it onto my suitcase and roll it around, I can un-latch the straps and tuck them
in to carry it like a briefcase, oh, yeah, I can also wear it like a backpack.
I've had this backpack for months now, and I've taken it all over Europe on weekend trips,
video shoots, and of course, those basic economy flights.
I can say with absolute certainty that this is the perfect technology and content creator backpack.
The backpack's listed for 140, but there is always a discount code right on the website that allows
you to get it for 69, 99, and let me tell you, it is worth every penny.
It comes in a few different colors, I love the Olive Green one I chose.
There's a smaller version called the Junior Laptop backpack that goes for the same price.
The reason I got this is because it was recommended to me by someone who was recommended to,
by someone else who was recommended to, by someone else.
Basically, this came highly recommended, so I had to get it because as a producer and video editor,
I was looking for a backpack that I could hold all of my technology that I'm going to take
for video editing and shooting for some weekend trips, or just like a really heavy shoot.
Now, I'll unpack it and show you what I've gotten inside.
First, I'll show you this cool little compartment down here.
So this has my charging from iPad, my computer charger, and it also has the DJI Osmo Pocket.
This is a camera that I take everywhere with me, and it's a three-axis stabilizer, it's by DJI.
When I go like this, it's going to stabilize.
It shoots in 4K, slow-mo, and has facial tracking.
This is a really great piece of gear to take on the go for shooting.
So what's really cool is this whole thing comes out here.
So if you really want to cram this tight, and then lock it up with this zipper, that,
then you put it right back in, love it.
The front is where I put my notebook, some business cards, yep, that's me on the business card.
I also put stevia's in here.
Stevia's are very important for anyone to have, and I actually take some of these from Cockishops
here and they call them my steleas.
America runs on Duncan, but just in tech runs on stevia, let me tell you.
Now my favorite compartment right here, check out all this organization.
So I have OCD, like a tiny bit, and this helps me out here.
I've got an external battery charger, then a mouse, but I like to have a mouse when I'm editing.
In here, I have my go-to-
It's my iPad, but it's Toby, let me guess it's Toby.
Hi, what do you want on filming?
Say hi.
Hi.
What do you want?
Hey guys, look, look, look for the first time in forever.
So right here, actually, while we're filming, this is our home that we are completely renovating
and throwing in all the coolest smart home gear, stay tuned for that series, really excited
about it.
We have a blue door now.
And we've got a blue door.
Yeah, it's blue door.
Love it.
Okay, Toby, so we're going to go because we have to film.
Okay, bye.
Okay, and right there, not going to tell you what that is, but right there, that's a bookcase.
You did tell us what it is.
Or at least that's what you're thinking is.
Okay, so back to the shoot.
And right here, we have my go-to SSD for editing.
This Sandisk Solid State Drive is amazing.
It has a read right of 550 megabits per second, and it is such a portable and efficient editing
hard drive.
It's also shock absorbin and water and dust resistant.
Then right here, I have another gadget that I love, which is basically an adapter for MacBook Pro,
and it gives me all of the different ports I need.
And then, of course, my AirPods Pro, I came out with a review recently, and if you haven't seen that yet,
you can click that link right up there that I just threw there.
Highly recommend these, and I've got a lot to say about them.
So check that out if you want.
So, yeah, lots in this front compartment, and I love how organized it is.
Oh, my god, it's so organized.
So, yeah, I mean, my therapist tells me I shouldn't compartmentalize my feelings,
but, you know what, I can compartmentalize my tech all I want with this thing.
He said it's okay.
Back here, we've got an opening, and that's where you put your laptop right there.
Perfect.
You must be wondering, what is all this?
Well, I'm going to show you.
Right in here, this is where I put a pair of clothing for my weekend trip,
and then also my Nintendo Switch.
If I'm not going on a weekend trip, I'll actually put the camera that's being used right now.
In here, this will fit perfectly in here, and then I'm literally ready for a shoot.
Another cool thing, while I'm here, I'm a little dehydrated.
I'm going to put this water bottle right there.
You'll never go thirsty with this backpack.
I swear.
Unless you don't refill.
And then, oh my god, I forgot.
Right here, there's another slot.
You know what's in there?
My iPad, and it also has a keyboard case on it,
and I also just reviewed this case as well.
Plug right there if you want to check it out.
So there you guys have it.
That is my e-bag's professional slim laptop backpack review.
I'm Justin, and I'll pack you later.
Cheers.
It's a really old water.