I just received my Oculus Go, and it is blowing my mind.
There are so many experiences on this device, but these are the top 5 things you have to do as soon as you start your Oculus Go.
The first thing you have to do when you put Oculus on is check out the app store.
There are over 1,000 experiences, games, and multiplayer options.
A lot of them cost money, but there are also a ton that are free.
The app store is basically like the app store on your iPhone, but in virtual reality.
And a lot of apps that you can play online, which brings me to the second thing you have to try.
And that is multiplayer games.
One of them that I thought was really cool is also free is poker VR.
You're literally sitting at a poker table with people from all over the country playing poker and socializing.
I could see their lips move, and I could see them looking around.
It was crazy. It was really weird too, and they played a joke on me at one point.
And I was like, this is very odd.
Another game you should check out is Death Horizon.
In this game you team up with others online to defeat Wave zombies.
It's super fun, and it's not easy.
The third thing you have to try out, this is probably the coolest thing in my opinion on the Oculus right now, is your Oculus room.
So the Oculus room is basically this one bedroom apartment.
I don't think there's a bathroom where you can decorate the walls.
You can decorate all furniture, and then you can have friends over and play games.
And just hang out, listen to music, watch clips of SNL.
The fourth thing you have to try out is surfing the web in virtual reality.
It is really weird.
So basically you can go on a website browser and search the web on Oculus.
I mean it's a little gimmicky, and am I really going to use this?
I don't know, I kind of did last night, but not really.
But it's still really cool when you gotta check it out.
And the fifth and final thing you have to try is the whole theater.
So basically any videos you take on the Oculus or if you import videos, you can watch them in different surroundings.
So look, I'm watching the video I took at my home theater.
I'm on a lazy boy right now.
How about that?
Then I can also change it, and I could be in a huge movie theater.
Look at that.
I'm just looking around, and this is a huge movie theater, and I feel like I'm sitting here.
Also I can go to the moon and look guys, there's Earth.
That is where I am right now.
I'm on the moon.
Well that was really cool. I'm sure I have the Oculus hair.
That's everything I have.
Definitely let me know in the comments below, like any experiences that you want me to try out
or that you think would be awesome on the device.
Like this video if you enjoyed it.
Also follow me on social media just in underscore tech.
And subscribe to my channel. I have a lot more coming, and I want you to be there for it.
Alright, well I guess I'll see you in the virtual world.
Bye.
See you.