I have been wearing the tandem moby insulin pump for about three months now.
It is the smallest hybrid closed loop tube pump in the US.
I mean, look at it. It is a tiny little thing.
Today, I wanted to dive deeper into its algorithm, my favorite features about it,
and some tips and tricks with it, and talk about what my transition from
tubeless to tube has been like.
Welcome to Diabetic. I'm just an eye of type one diabetes, and on here, I talk all things
diabetes, tech, news, and research. Today, I'm joined by diabetes educator, David Mina,
who lives with type one himself and uses the tandem moby. He helps train patients on a wide range
of insulin pumps, including the moby. We get into why he became a diabetes educator,
his experience with different pumps over the years, and why he chooses to still use tandem.
We also break down the tandem algorithm, how it works, the updates with control like you
plus, and what people should know before switching. I share my take on what the transition from
an omnipod tubeless pump to a tube pump. What that was like, it's been quite challenging,
as well as my love for the moby-quick-bullet button. This thing is so much fun to use, and then we
also get into some excitement. We have over the twist insulin pump that is coming very soon.
This is just the beginning for my moby content. There's already a site change video up on YouTube.
I've got an app walkthrough video coming up, as well as a video where I dive deeper into my transition
from tubeless to tube. I'm going back to tube, and then also a review of the tandem moby that
will be coming soon. So, make sure you subscribe to my YouTube channel so you get updated as soon as
that releases. Keep in mind that all of my episodes are not medical advice and are educational
purposes only. Always consult with a physician before making changes to your health care.
Let's get into it. Dave, welcome to the show. Good to have you here. How's it going?
Good to tell me. I'm good. I'm good. I'm very excited to be here.
Yeah, you work at the same office as David on, right? I do. I do. How well do you know him?
Pretty well. I've been working with him for about two years now, and we've been
good friends also before then. So, okay. Pretty comfortable. Very, very cool working with him,
learning a lot from him daily. So, that's great. Yeah, he's a crowd-favored on this show. I love having him
on whenever there's a conference him, and I will get together and talk about what we saw there and
geek out. It's always fun talking to him. But more about you, you were diagnosed at 11 years old.
Yes. And now you are a certified diabetes educator. Tell me about what inspired you to choose that
line of work. Well, I, like he said, was diagnosed at 11. So, I was in the sixth grade. Very new
concept to me. Did I know anybody in my life personally living with diabetes at all, but let alone type one.
So, it was very new to me. Very shocking, obviously, to me and my family. And just learning that
news at first. So, I think my experience being introduced to diabetes, I will say, did not start off on the
best. But I was very confused, very scared. Why is this happening to me? You know, you're 11. You want to just
be a normal kid. Be with your friends. Go, you know, to school. Do all of those things. And now I
had to relearn. I feel I had to relearn life in a way and how to incorporate diabetes into my life. So,
you know, I will say I went through a couple of burnout periods throughout my first couple of years with diabetes.
Had the highest A1c, I had ever hit maybe about two or three years afterwards. And there was a
point when I went to my endocrinologist for my three-month appointment. And my diabetes educator,
actually, is the one who came in and pretty much gave me this fear factor lecture telling me, you know,
if you don't get a grip on your diabetes, you're going to have X amount of complications later on in life.
And that really impacted me. It made me want to change my habits. You know, I was going for long periods
of time where I would be afraid to take insulin at school because I was afraid of going low. Very,
you know, embarrassed back then that I had this thing called diabetes that no other kid at my
school had. And so that is a lot where the behavioral elements came from and from that moment,
right after that appointment, I changed my ways. I said, I'm going to move forward on a positive note
and I'm going to take control over this thing. So, that was a very pivotal moment in my whole journey with
diabetes that really spoke to me and made me want to do something not only for myself, but for others.
I think that experience that my educator and I shared where it was not the most positive experience.
It taught me that I wanted to be that person to somebody, but handle it in a different way, essentially.
I want to go into a room with a patient and give them proper education and allow them to feel that they know
they have the resources available to them and here's how we can get to that point together.
I never want somebody to feel that they have to manage this disease alone. So,
that was a very, like I said, pivotal moment in my life that really spoke to me and made me want to
do something more with my diabetes. Yeah, that's so cool to hear. I mean, my diabetes educator has been
one of the most pivotal people in my care and I always tell people when they come to me and they're
having problems or they feel really lost. I'm like, get a diabetes educator, go find one. They
are your, what mindset to me was she was like, I'm your diabetes therapist. You can come in,
you can talk about whatever you want. It's all related to diabetes. It's all going to be in some way,
you know, that struggle, that whatever it is, that stress. It's all connected and she's made me,
you know, the the carb counter I am and I'm so grateful for her and I'm grateful for people like you,
that that help other people too. And I try to offer my own education too when it comes to at least
the technology that's available and then they can go over to you and then, you know, learn how to use it and
ask about it. You help people get on an on all pumps, right? Or a lot of different parts.
Pretty much yes. Like I always say I like to meet patients where they're act. So, you know,
at the point where they come see me, they've already made the decision. They want to start insulin
pump therapy and so depending on which device they choose, it can be, you know, just using
CGM. It could be using pump therapy with CGM. You name it. There are a lot of great options out there
these days. So, we usually just let them choose and then, you know, I'm able to train them on the device
that they choose and I really want to instill confidence in them that they know they can use these devices
in their own lifestyle. You have to choose a device that fits your lifestyle. So, yeah, that's
usually how it goes when we, when we have a training. Yeah. And I'm sure you've heard of the new twist
pump coming out. Have you been trained on that yet? Are there plans to get trained? Like it is happening?
I just went to Manchester, New Hampshire and I saw them in the production line being built. It was
so cool. Dean came in the inventor of the pump and the original, like the first wearable pump ever.
He took me on a tour, which was like so cool. But I'm excited for this. What are your thoughts?
Yeah. I actually have been having conversations with our reps here locally and so it's been really
exciting learning about the technology. Very, very interested in how it's going to work. As
come to therapy, compared to the options we have nowadays, I think each device coming out nowadays
is just getting better and better. A lot of features that I feel the diabetes community has been
voicing what they want out of a system. And I think I'm seeing a lot of that being placed into these new
devices such as the twist pump. So, yeah, very excited in the process of getting certified to train on
those, but we haven't fully started training yet. So, you know, more to come on that, but very excited
and always, always ready to learn more about all the systems. Yeah, they all have their pros and cons.
And I've experienced that firsthand after wearing Omni pod for the last three years using both Omni
pod five, the FDA cleared platform, and then using DIY systems. I've been able to experience
all those, and then switching over to Tantamobi for a few months, which inspired this conversation,
and I want to get as much information as I can out of you of, you know, the ways you're using it,
the way you speak to patients about it, because there are so many factors of the Mobi that I found to be
really beneficial, but I've also had moments with it where I struggle or I'm frustrated about whether
it'd be lifestyle experiences with it, but also just like understanding the platform or getting it to
work the way I want to. And I've worked with my educator, but I don't know, there's just, there's just been
a lot of like back and forth of how I feel about it. But before we get into Tantamobi, I want to get an
understanding of some of the pumps that you've used leading up to Tantamobi. So I, like we said at the
beginning, I've been living with diabetes since the age of 11, so it's been about 16 years now. I went my
first year with diabetes doing completely, you know, MDI. And then after that, I started in my first
insulin pump way back when it was a metronic pump one of the very first models available. I did that
for a few years, and then I switched over to the animus vibe no longer available, but that was a great pump.
I really enjoyed it. I hear people love that. It was very, very, I feel user-friendly as a good word to say.
Did you use the Cleo infusion set with that?
Ooh. I don't remember. Yeah, it's far back. They were very similar infusion sets. I think back then
I was still using steel cannula as I remember. So a little bit different, but yeah, I did the animus
divides for some time. That was when CGM was starting to become a thing too. So we started seeing that
integrated into the insulin pump. It wasn't, you know, a closed loop system or anything, but
but it was nice, as you could see your decks come, readings on your pump when you would go
initiatable as it would automatically populate. So I felt it helped a lot just having two devices in one,
essentially. And then I switched over to once my warranty ended with that, and I found out
animus V was no longer, I switched over to tandem T-slim. Did that for a few years, and then as
it recently, within the past year, switched to the movie. So that has been my, you know, journey with
insulin pump therapy. So I've been on a pump for about 15 years total, and I'm sure we'll talk about this
more within our conversation. But it's been, you know, a lot of learning, but I find that each system,
I switched over to, it's only getting better and better with the technology and the progression we're
seeing in pump therapy, all the features that are being incorporated into these systems are just making things
so much easier to live with diabetes. And it's something, obviously, you and I are both, I'm sure
very, very grateful for to have because it does provide a sense of luxury in a way to live with diabetes.
And that's something I'm fully aware of and grateful to have. Yeah, I feel so fortunate to have an
automated system. And fortunate to have been diagnosed at a time where that was ready for me. I mean,
at least in the DIY space, it was maybe a year after my diagnosis that cleared FDA cleared system,
started having loop or closed loop systems. But I didn't have to go through the years that you did
of not knowing or not having the CGM levels connected to a pump. And I don't want, I don't want to
have imagined that. So I'm grateful for that. You know, you had this big decision when T-slims contract
went up, you moved over to Moby. Why do you decide to stay in that control-like ecosystem?
Like I said, I always tell patients, you have to find a system that works well in your lifestyle.
So when I applied that to my own like the diabetes, I found that the Moby made sense to me,
and especially having that same algorithm that I'm so used to with the T-slim,
you know, I've been on the T-slim for about four or five years. And so when, you know, it came
time to switch over to the Moby, I felt like I've had a good grasp on my diabetes in a sense with
having control like you. I found the control like you element helped me live my lifestyle.
You know, I'm a busy person. I'm out of the house for 12, 13 hours at day at times. And so it's just
a lot of go-go-go, where I find I need a system that I find can be essentially like an assistant or a
sidekick to me in managing my diabetes. And I find control like you is very helpful for that. It has
a lot of features in the system that I find I use often to help me optimize the system,
manage my diabetes and achieve the goals that I have for myself. So, you know, that can come from
temp bezels, that can come from, you know, this system deciding to decrease or increase my basil rates
to prevent moments where I would normally pause and have to treat my diabetes. So, have you ever
thought about just trying out omnipod for a short amount of time? I mean, it's pharmacy benefits.
It doesn't necessarily affect your contract with Moby. Have you ever considered or have you tried on a
tubeless pump for a month or two just to see what that experience is? Yeah, great question. I actually,
that is one of the few pumps I have not tried yet. I remember before I switched over to my T-slim pump,
it was between the T-slim and the omnipod. And, you know, back then, I remember the plan that I had
my insurance plan could only cover the T-slim. So, that's why I moved forward with that. But, you know,
I'm glad I made that decision, obviously. But, there was a period of time where I was wanting
fully tubeless pump therapy and having that freedom where I'm not connected to a device or a tubing.
But then, you know, part of my decision was I realized I've been on a pump for at this point now 15
years and they've only ever been two pumps. So, that's all I really know. I'm very comfortable with it.
And then now kind of having the Moby where you could do make it a patch pump if you wanted or you could
wear it as a tube to pump. It gives me that option. So, yes, I've been very interested to try omnipod.
Just as, you know, experience just to see how it works fully and, you know, compare the two with
their algorithms. But, I think both are great options. And, I do love that it is a pharmacy benefit too.
So, it is more accessible. I had an interesting experience switching from omnipod to Moby for this
little experiment. And, I wasn't ready for this. Like, I didn't realize it would challenge me this
much. But, you know, I've been so spoiled by this by omnipod being just like kind of on me and going through
my everyday routine, not even thinking about it being on me, really forgetting it's there. And then,
starting a tube pump when I go to shower needing to not only detach it from it, but also go
find my phone so that I can stop insulin delivery. So, every time I'm going to shower, I have to go find my
phone, which is, you know, nothing, something I didn't have to do. Going and sitting on the toilet and then
either pulling my clipped pump and like, it almost like hurting, you know, like a little bit or it
dropping to the ground and like needing to catch it, just like this dangling thing coming off of me or like the
worst, somehow like when I'm switching outfits or like coming out of the shower and I guess I put the two back
on getting dressed and like using one hand to hold my shorts and on my other hand to hold the bump.
I'm like, oh my goodness, like that was a big adjustment for me in that realm. And then the other
thing that was a bit of an adjustment for me is, you know, I just lived on an island off of Brazil,
Florianapolis, beautiful place and I was wearing Speedo a lot and having this like tube coming out
or wearing this little sack that little adhesive pouch with my Speedo just didn't feel and I hate
that I felt this way. I hate it, but it's true like I just didn't feel as confident in the way I
looked with it and and I hate that and I hate that I say that because I am a confident person. I'm proud of
who I am in my diabetes but it was just a really interesting situation that I found myself in and I actually
documented all these feelings and experiences in a YouTube video that is probably coming out I think at the
end of the week that this airs so stay tuned everyone but that was my experience with that shift and
I don't know I just thought I'd bring that up because these are just things I never had to experience before
but it just resonated with me that like some insecurities came out for me. Absolutely and thank you
for sharing that because I think that is a very real point that maybe a lot of people experience with
diabetes and maybe don't feel like sharing and I think that is something that we have to incorporate
into the decisions we make for how we manage our diabetes so I know a lot of people unfortunately may not
want to wear a pump or a CGM for reasons like that and by all means I mean I always say again it has to
work for your lifestyle so as long as you're obviously not neglecting your diabetes care you're still
taking injections or checking your blood sugar manually whatever works for you but I think there are ways
and there are you know transition periods where you switch over for example from one insulin pump to another
where you might experience a moment like you did you know at the beach or something and it's the first time
you're faced with that reality where it's very new to you it's a new device it's a new environment and
you're just now having to essentially relearn how am I going to live my life with this new device
and doesn't make sense for me or not so these are all valid feelings and all very important things to
consider I think by you sharing that especially is going to help a lot of people because you know they won't
feel alone I mean I felt similar to that before just kind of in my everyday life like I totally
understand when you're changing when you're showering things like that you have to know
disciple where is this pump gonna go and how am I going to operate it in these moments that a lot of
people wouldn't think about so very very real moment yeah I feel like in those moments of using the toilet
showering swimming whatever it was it was a reminder like a poke saying you have diabetes you have
diabetes and I don't experience that as much with the the tubeless factor and and and the good
good news is for people who feel that way too a lot of these companies including tandem are all
working on a tubeless pump so soon we're going to have so many options and I'm sure there will still be
people out there that prefer to I'm actually I'm wearing my movie probably for like the last the last day
I could I was gonna like take it off yesterday and put on my omnipot before I returned it but I was like well I
should wear it for the amp you so I've got my movie on and I'm returning it so they had the 90 day return ball
Sam returning it this week but I'm so grateful that I got to use I mean this thing is small it is a tiny little
this is the smallest two pump a half the size maybe even more than half the size of T slim and then
way smaller than metronics 70 dg I think my favorite feature on this pump has got to be the
ballas button I am obsessed with this thing like and I'll tell I used it yesterday at the Delta lounge
I'm you know I left my phone by my computer and I'm going to to get some snacks at the buffet and I'm like
shoot I don't have my phone I'm like wait a second I don't need my phone a ballast right now and I just hold down on it and it goes here
I'll even I just hold down on it and it goes like Baba and then I go like one two three you could do up to three one two or three
I'm not gonna confirm it and so what I would do is I would confirm that and right there that would have been 45 grams of
carbs logging into it you could do you know you can program it a bunch of different ways so that was it saying you didn't
you know dose which is good because otherwise I'd be low in 20 minutes but that that is hands down the coolest
feature for me especially coming from the tubeless pump where Omni pod doesn't have any type of onboard
controls to bolus you need to go get your phone in order to bolus so
you really could just you know be without your phone for a while have the alerts from your pump if you go low
use that for eating and then your dex calm or your CGM you're using could be connected to your watch I mean you
really could be pretty mobile from your phone and I like to not use my phone what would you say is your favorite
feature of moby you know I think going back to that where to use the personal system or
psychic I just find that you know every device I've used to manage my diabetes I just adapt to that device and so
now I know anytime I need to make treatment decisions specific to my pump it's all on my phone so I really love
having that option I think my favorite feature is simply mobile voicing you know looking back to when
I was newly diagnosed and we didn't even have yes there was technology but I wasn't at least using it right
away the concept of being able to deliver a bolus from my phone at the age of 11 would have been beyond me I mean
I think that was the coolest thing and I remember when I started on the tandem T-slimp pump there was
no mobile bullets just yet and I remember when that update came out I was super super excited because
again that concept is just very freeing to know you don't have to always pull out your device and deliver a
bolus if you're for example in a meeting or you're you know in a situation where you can't always pull out your
device or maybe you don't want to you have that option you can very very discreetly look at your texting
almost and you're really delivering a bolus I say like you're texting your pincreate essentially and so
just kind of allowing that flow of insulin to go through and very seamlessly is very exciting
this episode is sponsored by OmniPod as someone with T1D and with an incredibly active lifestyle it's
important for me not to get tied up especially with tubes on my insulin pump I love to go swimming,
lift weights and play kickball with friends and with OmniPod 5 I never have to worry about tubes
getting in the way plus not having to disconnect helps me to stay in range during all of my favorite
physical activities that includes sexy time too see if you're eligible for a 30 day trial by visiting
OmniPod.com slash dive tech on there you'll see full safety and risk information and trial terms
that's OmniPod.com slash dive tech first can you kind of explain to us with control like you
how what that algorithm is doing absolutely so just like it says control like you it's trying to keep you
within a type control and so you know there's this graph I love going over with my new pump starts
because it really simplifies the whole concept those control like you essentially it'll show the
diagram of those colored diamonds that you see on your screen and then you know different functions what
may be taking place if you see it happen on your dashboard so usually I like to go over you know the pump
is trying to keep you in this maintenance mode is what I call it and it goes to keep your glucose
between a 112.5 and a 160 range yeah you're target glucose on the tandem is 110 but within that
112.5 and 160 range you're you're good essentially you know and it's trying to keep you within that box
anything above or below it's going to adjust accordingly and try to prevent a high or a low
blood sugar one thing I always want to stress with my patients is don't think that once you start an
insulin pump your high and low blood sugars will go away you'll still have them but control like you
is trying to limit that and reduce it as much as possible so anything above that 160 threshold if it's
predicted to go above 160 and 30 minutes it gives you an increase in your basil rates and then anything
predicted above 180 it'll give you that more aggressive auto correction bullets on the flip side
if it's predicted to go below the 112.5 it's going to decrease your basil rate and below 70 and 30 minutes
it's going to suspend all insulin delivery until your glucose goes back up so I really love that it has
that type control for you and then you know once you go into you know tighter features for example
there's that sleep activity and there's the exercise activity those are what I like to call safety
nuts in those particular situations when you're sleeping it's trying to keep you in a tighter range of
112.5 and 120 and then while you're exercising 140 to 160 so very careful in those situations it's
trying to make sure you're safe and you're good essentially as we have said several times lifestyle
you know we sleep at different times of the day we exercise at different times of the day to having these
assistance to help you in those particular situations are very very helpful and it's all trying to increase
your time and range decrease your A1C to that target that you and your doctor may set for yourself.
Yeah I want to get into those modes in just a second but before we get there tell us about the auto
corrections so how tandem stands out ahead of some of the competition is it can send out auto
boluses in addition to its basil adjustments that will treat they'll do it up to once an hour
it will treat with a burst of insulin in order to bring you down. What is it kind of doing there so
when you're for example in the sleep mode it shuts all auto corrections completely and then
when you're in the exercise mode it does up to one per hour just to prevent you from having a low
well exercising but having those correction boluses sometimes obviously our glucose is rising a bit quicker
through our pattern and our trend that the dex calm is displaying it might show we are rising pretty quickly
and based on the settings we input into our device is going to give us those correction boluses as
a more aggressive dose versus your basil rate because your basil rate can only go up to a certain amount
based on your max basil rate so you know let's say you're running high for several hours the pump is
working super hard to try to bring you down with those increased basil rates but once it hits that max
it's going to you know almost tap out it can't do beyond that so that's where the correction
boluses come in and you know with that algorithm it's predicting above 180 and 30 minutes if it continues
to notice that pattern it's going to deliver the correction bolus it takes into account you know
your insulin board and when is the last time you pull this things like that but it is there to assist
beyond those basil rates if needed so one thing I noticed using the moby that kind of scared me was that
if I saw that if I was having a low like a minor low around 70 or going low if I was going to eat
say 50 grams of carbs I would enter that in and the app would still recommend me taking insulin
whereas I felt like when I used not even when I used the Omni-Pod 5 system when I was at that
same amount it would not allow me to even if I put in 50 grams of carbs it wouldn't allow me to take
insulin for that what's the difference here it scared me when moby was like no you should you should have
more insulin I'm like no I'm low yeah I mean it's going to obviously drop the amount of the insulin
you may require because it is seeing that your blood sugar is low and it may be continuing to drop
you do have that option to as soon as you go in and type of bolus it will say you're either above or
below your target glucose of 110 and if you want that correction obviously you would click yes and it will drop
the amount of insulin if you are low for example I get it there is that fear that maybe you don't want
insulin in you while you're going low which by all means obviously you shouldn't but it gives you
that option and it just shows that you can take a lower amount of insulin just because of the fact that
simply you're low obviously maybe you want to treat a little bit before you initiate a bolus because also
when your glucose starts to rise back you'll notice the amount of insulin the pump wants to deliver
will now be a little bit more because it sees your glucose is going back up so those are just things
to consider obviously you have the option to override the correction or take it if needed but yeah by
all means you you have that ability I know on the pipe you're saying would not give you insulin until it
senses your glucose going back a tandem it just gives you that option but it's still something that you don't
have to do is just by going to completely shut it down essentially I also noticed that my
mobile would send me an alert that I was going low well before my dex calm would and maybe 50% of the
time that mobile be told me I was going to go low I actually didn't okay have you ever noticed that with
your system that mobile is like you're going to go low and then you actually don't wind up going low
and dex calm you know dex calm never alerts you that you are because they're obviously using different
algorithms but I just it was interesting like it was just adding another alert that I didn't even want to
need it yeah I know you're talking about may think sometimes because you're getting those alerts yes it
can be a lot sometimes but mobile is remember able to predict up to 30 minutes into the future so with
those predictions it's trying to alert you and make it seem more intense than maybe it actually
will end up being but with those safety nets it's decreasing basal or it's suspending basal that is when
you may end up just leveling out so yeah there have been times where I would get alerts like that and it
looks like I'm going to have a pretty low blood sugar but then I'll let five ten minutes pass maybe
in that process and then see I ended up flattening out and I primarily attribute that to the
algorithm not treating with maybe cars because I feel having less insulin going into my system is what
is going to help me from crashing and so yes those scenarios do happen but it is nice that you have
that second set of eyes essentially through the mobile to give you those alerts but also to prevent
insulin yeah I kind of gotten to this a lot before about wearing a two pump of being so new and
in all these areas of my life it being kind of annoying are there any tricks that you use to
to hold on to your two pump and in all these areas of life so with the teaspoon because it was a
little bit bigger I would just clip it usually on the back my back pocket and then sometimes
depending on what I was wearing at the time it was probably something a little more uncomfortable sorry
more comfortable like sweats I might just clip it to the front of my waistband now with the mobile because
it's small I mean I'm wearing it right now and I honestly don't feel it on me I don't know where it is at
the moment because I'm on the screen it is sorry usually clip it actually on to my underwear we
stand and then there's still that layer of my pants over it but I feel it's more discreet this way so I
just clip it on there and you know the tubing is kind of hanging out but it's not really in the way this way
obviously we don't want anything covering the pump too much because that can obstruct connection
with the decks comp but I personally haven't noticed anything with you know signal loss or anything
like that so I find that words for me you're talking about tips and tricks for maybe clipping the pump
of particular way one thing that I found to be quite helpful I actually learned from another educator I
worked with is you can actually put the mobile on the clip backwards essentially or upside down
and this allows any bubbles that may form to go to the top of the reservoir or the cartridge
rather than the bottom which is where the insulin starts to be pushed out of this way you're preventing
any bubbles from going into your tubing and missing a delivery of insulin so I find that if I notice I
filled the cartridge and maybe there was one bubble I missed it's not the end of the world but it is
pretty hard to get out at that point so what I'll do is just put the pump upside down and clip it on and
it seems to work yeah you know there's having bubbles in a cartridge this was the first time I've ever
had to deal with that can you explain to us what happens when there is a bubble in the cartridge and
with Omni pod it like is it possible that there are bubbles in an Omni pod or does it
get those out like you can't see it I've never thought about that I mean for example the Omni pod
that yes you can't really see the quote unquote cartridge inside the pod but keep in mind the insulin
is going or any bubbles are going more to the top of the cartridge essentially or where the
cannula will be placed so depending on the placement of the pod it can push that bubble to the top if
you're wearing the cannula facing down for example similar to the movie if you're placing that
cartridge facing down than the bubble is going to go up so it's basically a pressure change when we
fill our our syringe with insulin and insert that into the cartridge there are bubbles that can form
we always say you don't want to fill your insulin pump with cold insulin because that can cause
pressure change it can allow bubbles to form and so if you're filling it with room temperature
insulin you're less likely to have bubbles form and then if you still do the bubbles will form but
it's important that they don't collect towards the opening of the tubing because that is going to
potentially block insulin delivery and that would just mean you're not getting your full dose which
could result in a high blood sugar so that's why we always stress flicking out your bubbles as
much as you can the positioning can really help with that there are different tactics we can do but
you know it is important to reduce the amount of bubbles okay thank you for that that I learned
something new I didn't know that stuff and I've been filling my pump up with cold insulin too so I'll
make sure to let those sit out in room temperature at a longer today's episode is sponsored by T1D Exchange
you can directly make an impact on diabetes health care treatments and technology by participating in the
T1D Exchange registry it starts with the simple survey about your life with T1D and it only takes about 15 minutes
after that you'll have a personal portal with ongoing T1D study and survey opportunities plus some of
these studies even offer compensation signing up with the link in the show notes help support my channel
and it allows me to continue putting out free content you can sign up at t1dxchange.org slash
diabetic or click that link in today's show notes so with let's go into the modes a little deeper let's
start with activity mode so one thing I needed to do with activity mode was like a lot activity mode alone
did not work for when I did like intense cardio when I was running at maybe five to eight miles per
hour fluctuating between there or whenever I do I go low and with activity mode that alone would not
do the trick I would need to put on a temp basil ahead of that and luckily with control like you
plus you can now do that what what are your kind of tips and tricks when people are for using
activity mode for people in different situations. Definitely so I got that question a lot especially
with new pump starts you know this is a very new concept that they're starting a pump for the first time
so when we do a deep dive on the activity mode basically like I said that is trying to bump up your
target glucose to 140 to 160 so you're getting a little bit less insulin this way up to one
correction bowl is per hour I usually say starting it about an hour before your actual activity begins can
help the algorithms are working in your system bumping up that target glucose so you go it in with a bit
of a higher glucose to basically allow for some breathing room if that activity decides to you know
make your glucose drop a little you're already bumped up a little bit so you'll have that safety net
I usually notice you know personally when I use activity mode so I think I've shared really before but
I am a local to Disneyland so I love going there all the time and you know obviously you're walking
a lot it's a big park and so I pretty much will set my exercise mode every single time I go
you know depending on how how soon usually I forget and I'll just turn it on maybe as I'm leaving the
parking line and walking into the park but I oftentimes find I don't have as many low blood sugars
if any because I'm in that mode I already know I'm going to be more active depending on the weather
it could be warm that day hot weather can you know sometimes make my blood sugar drop a little so I'm
already you know taking all of that into account I find that activity mode really helps because
I'm more active that way a lot of times I'll ask my patients are there any particular activities you
like to do they might like to swim they go for walks they will you know play baseball things like that
so I say great well then let's utilize the activity mode and just make sure you're turning that on
about in power before and then that is one feature that you will also have to manually go in and turn off
so I always say if you want to maybe set a reminder on your phone or go in and turn that off if you can
remember but you don't want to keep it on too long after because then you're still getting that bump
up target glucose yeah I wish they would just introduce a timer for that for both they have it for sleep mode
essentially right with the with the sleep schedules why don't they have an activity mode like timer like
it it's the perfect thing it's the thing we we really need I mean you even have that with 10 basil now
and automated I mean you get it with kind of everything you we should get it in activity mode for sure
because those are the times we're like okay I'm gonna go run errands for a couple hours let me put this on
and let me tell you running errands that is like this this feature may might as well be called
Aaron mode because running errands oh my goodness if you're like add it you're shopping you're going from
place to place like you can drop low I was in a I was low in line for addressing a room the other day
because we were just like popping around from the order store the other day someone asked me well what
if I am cleaning the house or doing laundry and you know I'm you know reaching into my laundry basket
and pulling out something to fold there you know things like that there's a lot of movement in that
and a lot of times they might find themselves going low while we say let's try exercise mode
or activity mode and if you find that maybe that is helping prevent those little blood sugars then
there's your answer you can use that for instances like that
yeah swiffering let me tell you when I swiffer I get my back into that and I I've probably gone
low 50% of the times I swear yeah no that that can definitely happen I I don't I I completely
know you're you're talking about even a lot of times people say vacuuming will do that or somebody just
yep and it's not always it's not the simple act of swiffering it's the fact that maybe I ate lunch
an hour before and took a little more insulin than I should have whatever and then that in combination
with the the action that you're putting into with the swiffer it's like that's all you needed to go low
so now with sleep mode are there ways you're you're having people use sleep mode outside of sleep
are there other parts of life where this could be a good that that could be a good moment for people
to use it I think you know obviously we want to try to use it only for the sleeping hours but
you know for example there was a time I'll give you a personal example where there was a period of time
where I was having low blood sugars left and right did not know it was taking place and I brought that up
to my endocrinologist and we decided well let's go and sleep mode 100% of the time
because you're still you know in a tighter range but you're not getting those correction bonuses
so you might get a little bit less insulin to try to bump up your your blood sugar and prevent those
lows from happening and I used it until it stopped working essentially I used it for a couple of months
was doing great and then I noticed my insulin needs changed and now I was facing high blood sugar
so I said well then let's turn off sleep mode now so I can get those correction bonuses so that would be
maybe a time obviously I always tell patients you know when you decide to use a feature like that
outside of what it's intended for it then let's bring that to your endocrinologist because they essentially
have the final say but there are ways to basically manipulate the system or optimize it fully by
using it in other scenarios than what they are intended for. Gotcha yeah I have sleep mode set to start
at 3 a.m. now I used to have it start maybe around 11 which is more true to when I was going to sleep
but the issue I found with that for me was that I do late night snacking or I'll eat dinner a little late
around 9 and I found that because sleep mode came on just two hours after that meal especially if it was
of the high fat meal that I was going pretty high a couple hours into sleep mode and I didn't have
those auto correction bonuses to get me down fast enough so then sleep mode would spend forever
trying to get me down through basil and it didn't do a good job it would take until 4 or 6 a.m.
for me to get back in the range which is really bad what are you seeing there with patients what are your kind
of go to strategies with the time that sleep mode goes on and people like routines definitely I think
I usually ask patients first what are your typical sleeping hours depending on where they are in
light you know maybe they are a working adult or maybe they are retired you know their sleep schedules are
going to change obviously so I'll use usually tell them you have up to two sleep schedules you can set
maybe a weekday profile and a weekend profile if you want or you can do every single day the same
sleep schedule then I'll ask them what time do you typically go to bed what time do you typically wake up
and then we'll come up with you know if they say oh some nights maybe seven and some nights maybe nine
we'll say let's let's come up with an average let's do eight and then it'll just start to kick in with the
option that they can also just go in and automatically or manually turn on that sleep mode and then
same thing when they wake up they can turn it off if they want I think it's a very smart you know option
that you you just share it about maybe setting it to start later into the night because yes you are going to be
getting rid of those correction bullises so if you know that you are somebody who may be snacking late eating dinner late
depending on what your diet looks like too if you mentioned you have something a little bit higher fat
potentially then you may need those correction both so you may need a little bit more insulin because
as I'm sure both of us are aware of something like pizza it's going to hit you several hours later and so
if you have pizza one night and then your sleep mode goes on a couple of hours after you may end up having
some high blood sugar you may not but you know it is it is helpful to set that sleep mode maybe later then
so I always just kind of try to meet that patient in the middle where they're up and try to assess
what does their typical night time routine look like and how it's sleep mode fit into that let's talk a
little bit about control like you plus so this released in the US a couple months ago it's not
outside the US just yet but it is with government agencies for in preparation for clearance
first one of the big updates was the temp basil not and not just temp basil when you're outside of
automated but now when you're in automated insulin delivery you can have that temp basil up to 72 hours
tell us a little bit about about what temp basil is and the different ways that people can now use it in
automated mode basically temp basil is a new feature as you just shared it to
tandem and especially when when you're on that control like you algorithm so now it's control like you
plus what's nice is you can basically get your standard basil rates usually you're at 100% depending on
it if you're glucose is above or below target you may you know get a little bit less or more but the
pump would do that for you but say you're normally in 100% getting your basil rates standard basil rates
now you have the option to go as low as 0% and up to 250% which means say you are for example running
higher one day maybe you're having your sick or you know you have a cold flu things like that where
your blood sugars will be a little bit more stubborn you may have higher blood sugar you can bump up your
temporary basil rate to be a little bit more than that 100% rate you could get 150 to 200 you name it
and then same thing if you're noticing you're running low one day maybe you're more active you're a
little bit more sensitive to insulin you can decrease that temporary basil rate and so again it's a
safety net just yesterday I was having a lot of low blood sugars and at a very busy day where I really
couldn't stop too much and I also was getting tired of popping glucose tab so I said let's go ahead and
put a temporary basil rate so I did that for about an hour and a half and I decreased that and I noticed
it helped I noticed my blood sugars were doing just fine and then as soon as that timer and
it essentially that's when I noticed my glucose was starting to shift up or down so it was pretty
eye-opening help how powerful that can be and it is a new feature and tool that you can now incorporate
it's so funny just like hearing you talk about that and this whole conversation we're having with all of
these different features and knobs that you can turn and make like increase or decrease things like
so many people who don't have diabetes have no idea all the tinkering that goes into managing diabetes they're
just like oh they have an insulin pump they're fine like we we have the temp basil the extended
bolus we have this that we have all these features for adjusting our pancreas needs it's just so funny
another one of those features is extended bolus which now there's been updates to that
the fact that you can extend a bolus in automated insulin up to I think it's eight hours
how are you using these yourself so extended bolus I personally don't use it too often but the times I
do are when I'm having maybe a higher carb high fat you know content meal something like pizza of course
that's the time I would normally use it so that's basically just to give a summary of what
extended bolus is for those who may not know it's basically you can take a percentage of your total
bolus for a meal up front and then a percentage the remaining percentage can hit a couple of hours later
up to eight hours as you said so it used to be before control like you plus you could only go up to
two hours now you have up to eight and we can get a little bit more into why would you necessarily need to
use it up to eight hours later but essentially you and maybe say you're taking you know a hundred
percent of your your total bolus but you decide I'm going to have a slicer to a pizza maybe I'm going
to take 30% of my bolus now and the remaining 70% to three hours later usually when that spike hits from
something with high fat high protein sorry high fat high carb content meal so that is a time I would say
would be great to use it obviously depending on particular needs and diets everybody has a different
lifestyle they may want to use it for other meals it's not just for something like pizza but that is a
time you would essentially use it when you know your spike is going to hit you several hours later
yeah and you were saying for up to eight hours is that for people who have gastroparesis like slow
digestion yeah that's probably what we'll start seeing you know who will be using it more obviously that
is a very new feature and at first when a lot of us heard you can go up to eight hours maybe we thought
why would anyone want a bolus hit them eight hours later but when you really break it down it is for
things that are a little bit more individualized something like gastroparesis yes so I think over time
with this new feature we'll start to see who is actually utilizing it and when would it be most beneficial
I want to ask you a few things about the future of tandem moby and I'm going to split this up so first
if you could have any feature on the physical side of moby any dream feature what would that be
physically physically okay um I would probably say maybe having like a built-in clip but
something that would just pop in and out so if you decide you don't want to clip you can just
pop it back in but for those who do it would just simply pop out stick to that same slim profile without
having to add an extra component like the clip we have now I will say the clip we have now is pretty thin but
I know some people may feel it's still a little bit clumpy for their liking so maybe having the option
to pop in a clip and pop it back out as needed would be beneficial for those moments where maybe
they're wearing it as a patch pump or not wearing it as a patch pump they have options but it's all built in
yeah almost like the Nintendo switch the Nintendo switch has like a stand that pulls out and then
clips back in and goes into the form factor also the fact that when the moby is in its clip you can't
charge it so maybe that would help something with the help with charging for example yeah yeah I also just
find it funny that the clip was designed in a way that you can charge it I think that there's some room there
for for updates on the on the future model because this this charge is on a pad it's it's all wirelessly
charged which by the way having to bring a wireless charger and the idea of forgetting your wireless
charger adds like a whole other aspect of like packing your diabetes supplies that I
already messed up with going on a little weekend vacation and then bring my charger and luckily it lived
okay now on a software angle what area of the software what's a feature for the software that you would love to see
come to the system personally I'm very happy with the features that are available I find that the
all word great you can utilize them as needed but first thing that comes to mind is actually what
we talked about a little earlier we're having maybe a timer for the activity mode would be helpful
I would say that is just beneficial because there will be times where we forget you know maybe we're running
from the gym over to work and we've just completely forget to turn that feature back up maybe if you
I was later and then will realize well our blood sugar is high how come and you find that you're still
an activity mode so I think from a practical standpoint things like like reminders or timers would be
helpful because people with diabetes were busy people too so we have to you know have as much health as possible
in our system yeah I forgot to bring up mind so with the the form factor I would love to see
the ability to turn on suspend bolus from the button on it because every time I have to shower the
fact that I have to go find my phone to suspend bolus no I'd prefer to use the on board button to
suspend bolus I'm sure there's a you know a certain of what characters that they can create on there to do that
with software wise what I would like to see is I'm already creating these like temp bezels plus activity
feature turned on at the same time I wish that there was the ability to create customizable widgets that you could
just tap and what it does is it turns on that temp basil and activity feature it turns on sleep mode and
temp basil it whatever it is these like custom made presets would be great and they're not adding a
feature they're really just allowing you to more quickly activate some of the some of the settings
now lastly if there was a dream feature that you could see come to the algorithm what would that be
maybe I would say going to the ability for the pump itself to predict your blood sugar 30 minutes
into the future and and correct based on that I think it would be nice if we could see what those
predictions would be what is the what is the algorithm assuming we might end up at and why is it deciding
to increase or decrease our basil rate so maybe just giving us a little more information but in an
optional format I know a lot of times people have alarm fatigue and all these constant beeps
and the reminders can be a lot so having it be optional would be great but the ability to tap in and see
what are these predictions and what is my basil rate being based off of why is it increasing
why is it decreasing I think that would be pretty eye opening for sure yeah that would be great I could
definitely see it being TMI for some people but on some open source apps they do show that they do
show where glucose is going in fact actually the twist pump that's coming out which uses an algorithm
from the open source community that software does show you where your glucose is going which is exciting I
believe it shows you a six hour graph I think that the first two hours or where your glucose already was and
then the four next four hours are where they're going so that's exciting people will have that feature
on twist coming out and I wanted to end with this if someone's considering becoming a certified diabetes
educator what would your advice be to them that's a great question actually I think obviously I've noticed
in my experience living a diabetes but also working in the diabetes bill people the diabetes
have this sense of passion for helping others with diabetes and I think that is a very important
trait to obtain to have I would say if you're open to the idea a research how can I get to that point
obviously there are specific pathways that you do have to go through before you would qualify to become a
CDC yes but having that ability can be very beneficial because they're different routes you can take
within that as well you can do it from the dietetic standpoint you can do that from the technology standpoint
there are a lot of different avenues nursing and so I think you know I would just say do your research get
involved work with others living the diabetes volunteer get some experience and you know from that point
forward you know move next to that educational piece to get certified but it all comes down to
to passion I think you have to obviously have that passion to help others which I feel people that
diabetes naturally do so you know I would just say go with go with your gut and move forward if it's
in you move forward with that yeah we really do have this passion the communities incredible and so many
people have helped me on my journey whether that be in you know an endo office or just on chat rooms
or social media and it's it continues to inspire what I do and to create this kind of content to
help educate others Dave thank you so much for coming on I'm glad that we got to do this I'm so glad
you could tell me everything I need to know about mobile before I were doing it but also I think people
listening will you know really grab grab a lot of great well that is the hope but thank you so much for
having me this is really cool and yeah I don't just speak with you here. Thanks for listening I've got so much
more on tandemo becoming out so make sure you subscribe to my YouTube channel and make sure you are
signed up for our newsletter on diabetec.info that is www.diabetec.info you can get signed up for our
newsletter and check out all of our blog posts coming out which are like the latest degrees in diabetes
tech news I'm Justin and I'll see you next week.