Hey guys, Justin Tech here, and this is the ET2 Friends of Hugh Smartlighting Pendant.
Yeah, you heard that right, Friends of Hugh.
That means you can connect this ring of light to your Philips Hugh set up at home and have
full control over the color and brightness and create the perfect on the Alps.
This light is part of an entire line of Friends of Hugh fixtures from ET2 and I was lucky
enough to get one sent to me, so thank you ET2 for sponsoring this video.
Now I'm sure many of you are a little upset because this ET2 isn't the continuation
of Steven Spielberg's extra terrestrial, but I'm going to make it up for you because this
light is so cool, so here it goes.
The ET2 Pendant is a beautiful and sleek fixture, its white dual matte ring is made of aluminum
and steel and is of course integrated with a powerful Philips Hugh light strip.
This light is in small, when it first arrived I was taken aback by how big it was.
I want my god is huge, it's literally huge, it's just what it's going to look like to
hang that up and it's going to be awesome.
The Pendant is 28.5 inches in diameter and 4 inches tall.
It can dangle from as high as 124 inches, look at how long the wires are.
I could see this light being used in super lofty spaces like over a dining room table or even
ballrooms, if people even go to those anymore.
And this light shines, it can present up to 16 million different colors and will give you up
to 2,800 lumens of light.
Installation was surprisingly easy, I recommend if you're a professional or you know what you're
doing, that's cool, if not higher in electrician.
This is also a two person job and I was very lucky enough to have my friend Toby to help
me out.
Installation only took about 40 minutes.
The light has a really impressive mechanic that allows you to pull through the wiring and adjust
the length by pressing and holding down on the openings.
So after we hung it up it was really easy to even out the wires one by one.
To connect this to your setup you'll need a Phillips U bridge, it's basically the hub that lets
you control all of your Phillips U lights.
When connecting it to your bridge, the fixture acts exactly the same as any Phillips U bulb.
So here's the thing, the fixture was originally called the Icarona.
I know that they're changing that name and I don't really know why the marketing person told
me that.
So I can't really speak to that but I do know that that's where you're going to be looking for
as of now.
I decided to call mine UFO because it looks like a freaking UFO and you know what ET probably lives
on it.
Here is the lovely UFO, it is so big and so beautiful.
Sometimes I just like going in it and you can, you know, blind yourself, whatever.
Then of course, with the Phillips U app I have full control over it and look at how vivid the
colors are.
They're really, really strong.
You can also sync the ET to fixture with content on your TV using the Phillips U Sync box.
Gaming has never felt more immersive with this ring of light reacting to every move I make in
my games.
You can also fully immerse yourself in TV shows and movies.
And of course, you can use any voice assistant to control this thing.
Set UFO to blue.
Lovely.
The ET2 friends of you fixture is a sleek, modern and gorgeous fixture with great attention
to detail when it comes to design and installation.
It seamlessly meshes into your Phillips U ecosystem and enhances the ambience of any scene.
This fixture looks great, whether you're using it for a nightlight, a candle lit dinner,
movies, or gaming.
Not to mention, it gives off an impressive amount of brightness and extremely vivid colors.
All this beauty doesn't come cheap.
The light retails for 9.78.
Why?
Because it's a well-made designer light with mechanics that make installation much easier and give
you the ability to alter the length at any time.
So there you guys have it.
That is the ET2 Pending fixture.
You're formally known as the ICorona, but we're not talking about that.
Anyway, I hope you guys enjoyed this video.
I have a lot more smart home coming your way.
I have an entire series, the ultimate smart home series coming in just a few weeks.
Stay tuned for that.
How do you do that?
Subscribe right down there and click the bell for alerts.
I'm going to tell you guys how to set up your smart home, all the accessories you need, how
to get everything to talk to each other.
It's going to be a load of information and I'm so excited to show you.
And if you guys enjoyed this video, why don't you give it a good ol' like?
I'm Justin and I'll take you later.
Now let me show you what my UFO can do.
I noticed it rhymed on like the third take and I had to do that and I'm sorry.