Check this out, it is inhalable insulin.
Well, it doesn't quite have insulin loaded in, but with this, you can breathe insulin.
Let me tell you more.
This is a fresa.
It's currently only available in the US, but it is also now cleared for use in India.
Currently it's only for those over the age of 18, but there is a study currently going on.
It's called inhale 1, where they are studying it for ages 4 to 18.
That's been going on since 2018, so hopefully they're getting closer and those younger
can start using it.
What makes inhalable insulin so unique is a fresa uses human insulin.
So the way it goes into your system, it acts faster and gets out of the system sooner.
Unlike other insulin that are taken subcutaneously, those will take longer to peak and
will take longer to exit the system.
It is in powder form, you load a cartridge into the device, pop it in, and then you go.
And inhale it.
The cartridges come in a few different doses of insulin.
If you want to learn more about a fresa, you can watch my podcast episode where I spoke
to a user, ginger, fiera.
There's a link to that in my bio and for more diabetes tech tips and news, keep it here on
Diabetic by following my page.