And can you kind of explain to us what that early night scout set up required?
This was the rig.
That was what, because it was, yeah, to put all this stuff together, it was a night scout
rig.
I came up with this.
This is actually a Cabela's tackle box, foam padded, and you could cut out the foam to
do various things, fairly bomb proof, and then had another layer of foam in the bottom for
the foam.
So there's this whole thing, none of it moved once the lid was shut and clamped.
It's got worked by connecting CTM device from Dexcom, right?
So this is a USB on the go cable.
This cable was designed originally to allow you to use things like external keyboard with
an Android phone.
Android is doing some pretty cool stuff with their phone devices, and on the other end of it is
sort of your standard USB jack.
And this actually had another dongle, and I'm realizing I'm missing another piece of this puzzle.
I had to go from that, and it had to basically go through this dongle into an Android phone
or Android tablet, and it typically, that was another connection.
That device basically tricked the CTM into a constant download, and then every five minutes
it would upload that single data point to your night scout database in the cloud.
And so, at the bare minimum, you had it.
The candy bar device, and then you had, you know, and I'll just go my phone in here, you had
a foam plugged in.
I can't tell you how long we ran this.