I had a crazy situation with my Dex CompG7 sensors this week, and I needed to tell you about it.
The other day I was going to hop on a train, but before I did I had to put on a new
sensor, so I put it on, let it do its thing, was on my way to the train, and I realized that
the sensor never connected to the app after I put in the code. It just couldn't find the sensor,
so I had to go back, I wound up missing my train, got a new Dex CompG7, put it on,
and the same issue happened. It kept scanning for a sensor but never found one. So I had to call Dex
Comp, Dex Comp let me know that this is an issue people are having. Dex Comp had me find the number
on the box, that is under number 21, so make sure you take a picture of that and you have that.
It's on both the applicator and the box, you just have to have a picture of that and you can give them that code.
That way these replacements aren't part of their like three replacement policy. This is a failure
and they will replace it, and it's not part of that. This had me a little concern,
no, because what if I had taken these as my backups for vacation? And I would be out of luck. Also,
right now I'm traveling a lot outside the US. If this happened to me, I would have no idea what to do.
I would have to put something on social media asking if there's anyone around. I don't think that they
would be able to send them to me outside the US. Dex Comp correct me if I'm wrong. I learned a few things
here. First of all, if yours has a similar rev number or serial number as mine, make sure you bring
others that aren't part of that batch. Luckily, I had another sensor, my third sensor to put on,
and that was a different rev batch, and it worked just fine. So I'm only taking those with me to
live in later today. I have like five of those, and I'm like praying that there's no issues with that.
Are you having any Dex Comp failures? What is that situation? And if you are having a failure,
how long is it taking for you to get replacements? I've heard about shortages. I haven't necessarily
experienced that, but yeah, let me know in the comments. This experience really freaked me out and showed
me how tied we are to technology and how one little technical difficulty can make us miss a train,
freak us out and could theoretically put our treatment on pause and put us in a situation where we're just
not as ready to tackle our diabetes. I was nervous. I was off to go to the zoo and this really just
put a damper on my morning. Thank goodness. I got a sensor to work and I'm so thankful that I figured this
out before going to Europe. Let me know what you think in the comments and follow this page for more
diabetes tech tips and updates on this story.