Hey everyone, Justin Tech here, and today I'm going to show you how to take video and pictures
off of your Oculus Go Oculus doesn't really tell you how to do this, so I have to do something
and then I was like, I'm going to make a video about it. So what you have to do is you have the download of software
called Android File Transfer from the Android website. I'll put the link in the comments below.
Once you have it on your Mac or your Windows, you can then connect the Oculus to your computer.
What's going to happen is the program's going to pop open right when you connect it,
and it's going to say it can't access the device storage. You don't worry about that because you
have to go in the Oculus to make it work. So let me put this on. It's going to say allow
access to data. The connected device will be able to access files on this headset. Yes, allow that.
Once you allow that, the program will then open back up again. It will say VR-head setup top and it's working.
So then all you have to do is go down to the folder called Oculus, open that up, and then in there,
there's a video shot and a screenshots folder. So then all you have to do is drag it onto your computer
and then you need your videos and screenshots. It is that easy. So there you go.
Go ahead and take some videos and screenshots and enjoy your Oculus Go. See you later.