Hey guys, it's Justin Tech, and welcome to my Hugo review.
Now, why did they call it a Hugo?
Because I can Hugo here, or here, or here, or here,
hey, or here, or here, or here, or here.
I'm super pumped about it because they added a Bluetooth functionality to it,
which is making it probably the most versatile, smart light ever.
Correct me if I'm wrong in the comments below.
So you guys ready for me to light up your lives?
Well, before I do that, why don't you guys subscribe right down there,
click the bell for alerts.
And if you can give me a like for that whole algorithm thing that really helped me out,
but don't Hugo anywhere. I've only just begun. Here it goes.
This is the second Hugo coming from Phillips U, and it is packing a much bigger punch than
its predecessor. For a few reasons, first, it's battery.
The original Hugo only got about three hours of battery life,
but guess what? This one's going to give you up to 18 hours of battery life.
Seriously, but some colors and brightnesses will drain your battery faster,
and there's a handy list right on the box that tells you exactly how long it will last on that setting.
The Hugo takes about two hours to charge, and of course you can leave it plugged in,
and it will never die on you. So you can also Hugo know where and use it around the home.
The other upgrade is its Bluetooth functionality. So now you can control the Hugo anywhere
using the Bluetooth app. Before you could only adjust lighting with its single button,
but now you've got the app which is easy for anyone to pick up and understand. And of course you can
use it at home, connect it to your bridge, and you can control it through your phone on that.
Phillips is moved where the plug goes in on the Hugo to a new spot. A lot of people were really unhappy
with the last position, because it was difficult to prop the Hugo up. So we're good now.
Thanks for listening Phillips. When unplugged the Hugo will only reach a certain amount of brightness,
and when plugged in, it will reach its full capacity. You can control the light manually in a couple
waves. First you can do a short single press, and it will siphon between a bunch of presets.
You can also double press and hold, and it will siphon through just colors. To conserve on battery
you can place the Hugo in standby mode, meaning you turn it off via the app or press the button for
two seconds. But it will only last for 12 hours. Power will be draining because it's ready to turn on
at your command. If you don't think you'll be using it for a while, I recommend putting it in
battery saving mode. In this state, it won't react to the app you'll need to manually turn it back on.
I've found some really cool ways to use this thing. You could light up a car. Why? I don't know,
but it's cool. You can light up your tent when going camping, light up your hotel room on a vacation,
or light up the fort you built in your living room. So here's what I think. I love the Hugo. It is the
perfect travel in companion, and you can take it on vacations with friends and family and surprise them
with a little bit of color. I'd say the downsides are definitely price. It is expensive. It's $80,
but the way I like to think of it is a Phillips Hue bulb is $50 and with that one. Yeah, now they have
Bluetooth and you can take them everywhere, but you still need a socket to put them in. With the Hugo,
you're paying an extra 30 bucks for a versatile light that you can place and prop in lots of cool ways,
and you don't need a socket to plug it into. You're not going to get it as bright when it's unplugged,
but this is something I'll make do with because I want that longer battery life. So what do you guys
think about the Hugo? Are you going to get one? Also, if you get one, how are you going to use it?
Tell me all those cool ideas in the comments below. I want to hear them because I probably want to
try it out myself. That's all I've got for you guys today. Make sure to subscribe right down there,
click the bell for alerts, and again, if you want to give me a like for that algorithm,
love that for you for me for you. I'm definitely going to have more Hue videos coming your way soon.
They have a bunch of outdoor lights coming out, and I have to get my hands on those, and second I do,
you will know about it. I'm Justin, and I'll tech you later.
Thank you so much.