Hey everyone, Justin Tech here, and today I am joined by Mr. Kane Blake of Kane's Way YouTube. Check them out, howdy.
Today we are playing some V-R.
He's gonna be fun. We are playing raw data, which is this first person shooter. It is multi-player,
so we are going to be playing together.
Look down, look your left waist, left side of your waist, and then pick up your bow.
Hold it, and then you can't let go. Go get it, go get it, pull the little string part,
and then pull it back, and let go.
Oh my god, the...
Oh, yeah, you're gonna do your good. Just lightly put your figure on your seat, and then press it.
Oh, you're so pretty. Now I am going to join Kane in the TRX spirit.
All right, Kane. Hi, I'm here. Oh, that's crazy.
We're ready. Where do you go?
Up. Way to go, right there. Hey.
And there we go. Look up.
Oh, howdy. What is happening right now?
I am freaking out. You are a high-ranking executive.
All right, so, Kane, I'll let you do the honor.
We want to go up and get that handle and pull it.
This is quite an important thing. I'm going to put it in that keyhole.
There we go. Nice job. The data is down.
Okay, see what guy coming? Put it to the right.
Uh-oh.
I'm sure that this is a bad one. I'm sure that every one is fine.
Oh, that's fair.
That's fair. So, then.
All right, so we're going to start coming you out.
So, put your hand in.
Oh, there's so many coming.
I'm coming inside.
Oh, come on. Come on, come on.
Oh, god. What is happening?
Yeah, I knew it.
Oh, I just literally just got one.
Oh, there's a- this is a guy.
Watch out, that's not really bad.
We got a time.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Very soon.
They're ready. Okay, there may be drones came so keep in the air.
Yep, there's drones.
Okay, this is not big, guys.
Where is he? He's hiding on mom.
Where?
Yes.
Where am I here?
Oh, hang on.
I'm trying to get him.
He's there.
I got there.
We got one.
Oh, there's a visible guy.
Anywhere in the visible.
Oh, where's mine?
You have to hit him, oh my god.
Turn you.
Huh?
Where do my guard? Where do I go?
Turn me.
Do I know?
Watch out, turn me back.
Oh my god.
I don't know.
Do I know you?
Don't hurt me.
Oh my god.
Come here.
And then down here.
Oh shit.
At the end of the night.
Nice big guys.
Turn this way.
Okay.
And then shoot the shoot rocket.
Shoot the rocket.
Oh my god.
That's hurt.
Help me.
I think the gun's a bit of the matter.
There is so much work.
My shoulder is killing me.
Oh my god.
This is like a one-off.
Oh god.
Shake it off.
Oh, oh.
Into the church.
About behind me.
Oh my god.
Oh shit.
Where am I?
Back down there.
Where do you go?
Behind you.
Back you back. I died. I don't see it like him.
He had to use a bootcase.
Nice.
All right, let's go.
Let's see.
All right.
Congratulations, sir.
Good to see you.
Can't.
Okay, it's like a giving you a massage right now.
Oh, so I take this off.
You lost your head.
Oh my god.
Yeah.
Where did I lie?
I was not even in a really difficult level.
Oh, my God.
I've been on part with them.
I can understand why people like
I want to stay in that world.
It literally feels real.
Like, swear it.
Squisting.
If you want to try VR as well,
you can totally check it out at any local best-byer game stop.
If you live in New York, like New York City or LA,
there's the IMAX VR experience that you can go check out.
And it's like $10 experience and it's definitely a good way to try it out.
Thank you, Kane, for checking out the VR with me.
It was fun.
Give it a time.
A little bit about your channel.
So I have a channel called Kane's Way.
You check it out at youtube.com.
Flash Kane's Way.
And all my social media is at Kane's Way.
So check it out.
Did a video with this one?
Collaboration.
Check it out.
We made cupcakes with other hands.
We did.
And it was a lot of fun.
As always, please like and subscribe this video
to stay tuned with all of my future videos.
And I will see you later.