Hey guys, welcome to Tech Tip Tuesday. It's my brand new segment where every Tuesday
I will be giving you the top tech tips that I know
On Tuesdays first tech tip that I'm going to give you is actually two tech tips. The first one is price matching
So did you know that a lot of stores like Best Buy and Target will actually price match other stores price
So if you see something on Amazon and you love that price, but you want it right away
stores like Best Buy and Target. I'm sure Walmart and other ones will match that price. Here's the second tip
And I just did this yesterday
stores will adjust prices if they are lowered within the return exchange period
So in 14 days a store like Best Buy and Target will match a price if it's lowered. I just did this yesterday
With my DJI Osmo Pocket which I love it was $350 but I noticed on Best Buy's website that it was
319 so I went to Best Buy. It had been eight days. I asked them for price adjustment and no problem. I got my $30
back and it was awesome. So make sure when you're buying gadgets at these stores just keep an eye on the price over
the next couple weeks and if it lowers, go into that store and get your money back. All right until next Tuesday
I'm Justin and I'll take you later