With loop, you can log foods using different emojis.
There's like three main ones, right?
There's the lollipop, the taco, and the pizza.
And these are all for glycemic index.
The lollipop being the highest glycemic index,
meaning that food that you're eating will hit you the fastest
and pizza being the slowest, it will be an absorption time of five hours.
And the algorithm gets to know this information.
And I think that that's what I love so much about loop
is feeding it the information of the actual food I'm eating.
It has more info than any other systems able to take
that that's FDA cleared.
That was one of the biggest reasons why I was so interested in using the app
because of the way it integrates food.
Past just carb counting because carb counting is a science, but it's also not.
And I think that having more pieces of data to inform
how you're going to react to food, that was attractive to me.
What about favorite foods? Are you using that?
I am. I tend to have a cold brew with the Choco Milk every single morning.
And it's a very specific brand of Choco Milk.
So I always know what it's going to do to me.
I save that specifically as a favorite food.
There's a few other items from restaurants that are local that I've saved.
So yes, I do use it.