Today I'm at AT&T in Westwood, checking out the Magic Leap 1 Creator Edition.
This device isn't necessarily VR or AR, it's a spatial computing device, it analyzes
your surroundings and sends light to your eyes, creating three-dimensional objects around you.
In my last video, I played Game of Thrones, The Dead Mustie Experience, and it was really
cool.
There's a white walker.
Yeah!
Holy sh, oh he just died.
I killed him.
Got with Tim Johnson, VP of sales for Magic Leap, and he told me all about the device
and let me play a bunch of games.
Your retina is the screen.
So when people say, oh, what's the resolution?
There's no pixels here, so I can't really talk about resolution.
Your retina is basically seeing the information, so just like you absorb light from the
room, we're sending light to your eye, and then you're seeing the three-dimensional objects
in space.
There are four world cameras, basically, or recording everything you see.
There are depth sensors and all kinds of other sensors that are basically making sure that they
can measure the space and know how you're moving through it.
There are two eye tracking cameras that are basically watching what you're looking at.
Obviously, with your eyes, you can also get biomarkers, so obviously, long-term, you wouldn't
log into this, you'd put it on, it would recognize that it was you, and then it would work.
Otherwise, it wouldn't work for anybody else, if that's what you decided.
We can tell a lot about your health, your heart rate, your cholesterol levels, all of those
kinds of things we can tell from your eye, so it's pretty amazing what it can do.
This is the first of its kind, sixth degree of freedom, control.
We can tell what position you have it in space, so you can obviously move it very freely, and basically
you can tell where it is in relation to you, and where it is in relation to the content.
Gesture, obviously, just like HoloLens, voice, eye tracking, head pose, even, so if you're
holding your face in a certain way, you can actually tell whether you're questioning something,
so as the AI gets to know you over time, we'll know what you're responding positively to,
which you're responding negatively to, and the core apps, we've got Helio, which is a volumetric
web browser, so one of the apps that you can see on here is WayFair, which you can shop for furniture,
you can pull the pieces of furniture out of the website, put them into your room, and again,
because we know the size of your room, and we know the dimensions of that chair, it's the
right size when it's put into your room, you can change the pattern, all that kind of stuff.
Also, shopping will be a lot different in the future than the social, which you can chat with
other people in kind of an avatar state, more like a Jedi Council, and then yeah, HoloLens, yeah, definitely
thank you.
Tim gave me his personal headsets to try out.
First I played Angry Birds, first person's sling shot.
It was fascinating to see how far this game has come since it's original release.
I remember the first time I tried out Angry Birds, and it was so dictating, is on my iPhone
4, and now I'm trying Angry Birds out for the first time, and augmented reality.
This is amazing.
Okay, so we've got a bunch of pigs, we've got a TNT on top, I'm going to pull this back, I'm going
to do this hard.
Here we go.
Boom, I've also played the Angry Birds game, Isle of Pigs, on the Oculus Quest, which is a pretty
similar feel, and it's a fun, quick, and easy game to pick up and play.
I highly recommend it.
See three peos here.
Next, I played Star Wars Project Porg.
I'll em x-lab, I know them, I just tried out the void.
Side note, a couple months ago I tried out this awesome Star Wars VR experience, you should
check out the video.
Now back to Porg's.
This game was basically Tomagaji meet Star Wars, these cute little Porg's were running all around,
and I was feeding them.
There's Porg's, there you go, it was adorable.
After the games, I checked out the gallery, which showed up some cool features.
Right now I have this deer that I just placed right on that shelf.
Wow, there it is, my horse video is on my wall, and I can look away, do my thing, and then
if I want to just see beautiful horses on the countryside, there they are.
I love it.
I was also lucky enough to check out the magic leap at 18T shape a few weeks ago, and played
one of the best games on the device, and one of the hardest names to pronounce.
Dr. Gordbord's invaders.
Basically I was fighting off hordes of robots that were entering from a hole in the wall.
This game was extremely impressive, and it's the number one game you have to try at 18T.
Wow, that was probably the coolest AR experience that I've ever witnessed, move over HoloLens.
So the magic leap creator edition is a really cool headset, and unlike any I have ever tried.
But there is no way I would buy it for $2300.
I do recommend heading to 18T and checking this thing out, but I don't think I recommend anyone
to buy it unless you're filthy rich or an early adopter.
Alright, well the battery died, I was playing too much.
Wow guys, that was incredible.
I want one of these, can you get me $2300 please?
I've got to say I'm thoroughly impressed, come to your local AT&T store, you can must do it.
It's in these five cities right here, you definitely have to check it out, they're going to be rolling
it out to more AT&T stores throughout 2019, so if it's not by you right now, it will be coming soon.
I've gotten an awesome VR video coming out on Thursday and a giveaway, so make sure
to subscribe and click the bell to get notifications.
That's all I've got for you guys, I'm Justin, I'll take you later.