Hey guys, it's Justin and I just got the Philips Hue Bluetooth Capable Lightbulbs in the mail.
Thank you so much Philips Hue. I am so excited to try these out.
These are the first bulbs that Philips has ever made with Bluetooth Capabilities,
so that you can connect your phone instantly to these lightbulbs and start creating scenes.
For the first time, you won't need a bridge connected to your modem, you will be able to connect
to your lightbulbs instantly over Bluetooth and control them and create cool scenes.
Let's try these out.
First, I have the white and color ambience, lightbulb right here, and it has the Bluetooth
capabilities right in the corner. You're going to want to look for that. Then I have the white
ambience, which basically allows you to do warm white and cool daylight, basically switch between
those two on a color wheel. This one's a little more expensive than this one, which is the simple
light light bulb. It only gives you a soft light. You're not going to be able to change
the different type of light you are going to be able to obviously dim it up and down.
So, these are the three bulbs I have right there. Behind me, I have three lamps. They have
light bulbs right now, while I'm taking those out, I'm putting these Philips Hue bulbs in them,
and trying them out. Also, this right here, that's a canister lamp. I really love that for accident
landing. I'll throw a link to that in the description below. Let's open them up and try them out.
Here are the three bulbs. They're all the same size. They all look exactly the same. Thank goodness,
though. They put the names on them right in front. So, I won't have any issues knowing which one's which.
Thank you Philips. Appreciate it. I'm going to now put these bulbs in the lamps behind me,
and let's check out how it works with the app, set them up, and play around them.
Over here, we have the hue white and color ambience. Then we have hue white right here,
and then the hue white ambience. Okay, so this one will be able to go between different
colors between different types of white. This one will just stick with that white, and this one will
have whites and colors. So, now I'm going to open up the new Philips Hue Bluetooth app and set them up
over Bluetooth. So, I'm going to open up the Philips Hue app and click get started.
And I'll put my name in there and my email address. All right next. Add hue Bluetooth lights. Let's do it.
All right, so it's searching for my lights.
Bluetooth pairing will pass to you lamp. Would like to pair. Let's do it.
All right, which one is that up? There it is. Found the first one. All right, so let's call this one
for the purposes of the video white ambience. That's a special white ambience, right?
Yep, right. So, there's my white ambience. I'm going to pair another one. Wow, I already
love how simple this is. So, let's see. Now I'm going to come up. There's my second one. I'm switching
between the two different types of white. Love it. Wow, I'm already impressed by how quickly this is
moving. All right, I'm going to call this one just white. Oh, wait a second.
I put the lights in the wrong bulbs. So, I made a mistake. This one is actually the white ambience.
So, I'm going to call this one white ambience real. Classic me. All right.
And then we're going to pair the last one, which is, oh, this is the colored one. I got that one.
I should, oh, let's retry that connection. Okay, lost the first second. And let's call this color.
So, I love this. You're a huge Bluetooth lights. You have just installed these
lights. Do you need to add more? The answer is no, because I only have three Bluetooth ones. So, done.
Wow, that's it. Done. All right, real quick. Let me change these names back to
what they should be because I messed that up.
All right. So, it was really easy to set up the lights. That was extremely easy. Actually, I
made it kind of harder for myself because I messed up those two white bulbs. But, got it down, changed the
names. And I love the layout. This is pretty great. I had the list form here where I could see the
lights that I have. And I can tap each one individually, like the white ambience and move it around.
And we put it to cool for now. Put it to cool. And then I can go back to the list and I can
do it. And I'm also going to turn off that light one, why not? Put that up. And then I'm going to go to the
color and change it to a pink. Raise it up a little more. And then I can always turn off all lights before
put it back on that top right corner. I like that easy. And then I can go into the middle,
this palette, and choose from a bunch of defaults and seasons and some light. So, that's cool too. So,
I'll put on an energize. Right? I can go through those. And then I can add one. Let's add one. Let's try that.
So, I'm going to call this party mode just easy. I'll need one eventually. And then so what I'll
do is I'll treat the color. We'll be, I'm going to make the color, the pink. And then for the white,
I'm going to make that actually white ambience and then dim. And I really love how on top it's showing like
kind of the color scheme of the party mode. I'm going to make it a little warmer. And then save that.
And let's see where that went. Your seams. That's great. Awesome. So, I have to say,
I'm really pleased with Phillips Hughes Bluetooth light bulbs. You saw it yourself. It literally took
me seconds to set up three bulbs with one, two, three. And now I'm in this app. And I can control all of them.
So, I am going to set them up with my bridge later. But I just want to just show you guys kind of how the
Bluetooth works. This is really great for like a parent or someone who's really not technologically
savvy. Like everyone can do this. All right. So, there you have it guys. Those are the Phillips
you Bluetooth smart lights. I have to say, I am extremely, extremely happy with the simplicity of
setup process and how easy it is to kind of understand the app and create settings. I highly recommend
these light bulbs for anyone who doesn't want to get all the whole Phillips you family, which honestly,
I'm sure will go Bluetooth completely, eventually. Seems like that's where they're heading. All right.
So, that's all I have on Phillips Hughes for now. That is the Bluetooth light bulb. I'm throwing links
to all of these bulbs in the description below so that you can check them out. Highly recommend them. Also,
let me know in the comments below if there are any smartroom devices or especially bulbs that you
want me to check out. I'm happy to do some reviews or comparison videos. As always, subscribe to this
channel for more smartroom and tech videos. Follow me on social media. I'm Justin and I'll take you later.