I just got the tandem movie tube pump and I'm going to be unboxing all of the supplies and accessories that come with it in order to use it.
So here's what the pump looks like. It's super duper small and you've got the little charging pad that goes down and you put the pump on it,
a cable to connect it to the wall. Now let's look in the accessories pack. There is an AC adapter for the wall,
and then you've got a clip that you can, you know, clip it onto your belt or wherever you want.
The starter kit comes with two of the adhesive sleeves. It's kind of big, especially when you compare it to Omni pod.
So the way this works is you'd put the pump inside this little sleeve, slide it in and then there you go.
It looks a little medical more so I think than Omni pod. Let me know what you think in the comments.
Now let's see what the cartridge looks like. The cartridge goes on top and then that's what the infusion set clicks into.
There is like a whole plunger system in order to put the insulin in. Let's look at the infusion sets.
And I got both the short and the long infusion set. So the short one is only five inches. So this is the infusion set. It's super short.
You basically pull it out, put it down, pinch it together, and then it puts it on.
This is going to be a new experience trying on tubes. Let me know what you think.
Whether you like tube or tubeless in the comments. And let me know if you have any questions about Tanda Mobie as I reviewed.
I'll be putting content all across my YouTube channel, my blog, and my podcast.
So make sure you subscribe to those and follow for more diabetes tech tips and news and updates on Tanda Mobie.