Huge news, the Dex Comstello continues glucose monitor now integrates with the ORA Ring Fitness Tracker.
Stello is what Dex Comst calls a biosensor.
It measures glucose readings every 15 minutes and it has no alerts.
The ORA Ring is a fitness tracker that measures a bunch of different biomarkers from stress, sleep, activity, heart rate, and a lot more.
Now here's why this matters.
There are over 42 factors as to why glucose levels fluctuate.
An integration like this could help us learn a lot about how daily activities affect us.
The ORA app now has a glucose graph that not only shows glucose levels, but puts little markers showing whether it was stress or activity that may have affected us.
There's also a food tracking option where you can take pictures of your food and it will implement that into your glucose trends.
Here's the bad news.
Stello isn't for people with diabetes who use insulin in a way this roll out hurts because I feel like if anyone needs to understand glucose trends and why they're affected, it's people with diabetes using insulin.
But my hopes are that this is the start of something.
Now what are your thoughts on this? How do you feel about people who don't have diabetes wearing continuous glucose monitors and getting all of this information?
Let me know in the comments and if you want to learn more about this partnership and the integration,
check out my article on diabetect.info or just click the link in my bio.