Welcome to this Justin Tech. I'm Justin and I'm going to tell you all about tech. Today
we're going to talk about Hugh and Lifex to the most popular colorful bulbs for the smart
home. They are direct competitors and they just came out with their brand new bulbs. The
Hugh is a lot sleeker looking. It's also lighter. The Lifex happens to be bulkier. The Hugh
needs a bridge to connect the lights to your internet. The Lifex they are their own Wi-Fi light bulbs.
No bridge necessary. The Lifex is the bridge. Lifex has 1,000 lumens and the Hugh has 800 lumens.
They both function completely different. Their apps are completely different. The Lifex app
is extremely intuitive. It's beautiful. It's just so easy to use. So simple and I love that
simplistic aspect of it. Whereas the Hugh, it's a little clunky. It's very listy. The number one
thing that I like with Lifex is the color wheel. So easy to use. They're so much flexibility with it.
Not only can you change the color but you can also change the brightness with this little scroll. On the
Hugh they have an actual Hugh. You try to go to different areas and you're thumb gets stuck on the edge.
You can't get exactly where you want or you're trying to move one light bulb and then it gets
included with all the other light bulbs and you're just not happy. For those of you
have an iPhone, you're in luck with Hugh because HomeKit is available which allows you to speak to
Siri and turn your lights on and off, dim them, change colors. Not available on Lifex yet but they have
announced that it will be available this year. But Lifex has Microsoft's capabilities with Cortana.
There's also a Windows app that runs on Windows 10 so you can be on your PC, your Surface Book,
awesome. When using these light bulbs side by side, you can see a complete difference between
the two. So now I'm going to use an app that allows me to control both life bulbs and make them the
same color. First I'm going to take them to green and as you can see Hugh just doesn't make the green
I'm looking for and then I'll take them to yellow and Hugh like barely change. Lifex there's a distinct
difference between the two colors and when I take it to sign on Lifex is that color Hugh just makes
like a white. Now when I take it to a purple you can't see it on screen that well but Lifex is purple and
Hugh is way more blue and Lifex is white brighter. When I take it to the pink they both look similar but
still Lifex is way stronger and I could always dim it to make it match the Hugh and then when I take to
this red Lifex again is Way stronger and Hugh just doesn't compare and brightness. On top of all that
the Lifex is said to have 36,000 hours of life and the Hugh only has 15,000 hours of life.
The light bulbs are the same price but to get started with Hugh you need that bridge and 60 dollar
bridge. So you can get the starter kit for 200 bucks comes with three bulbs and a bridge or
you can get a bridge for 60 bucks in a life for 60 bucks. So that means you have to spend $120 to get
into the Hugh colored life bulb world. With lifex like I said earlier no bridge necessarily the
life bulb is the bridge it's 60 bucks done. After playing around with both bulbs for a week playing around
with their apps the colors I have to say that lifex is a winner for me. Both bulbs claim to produce
16 million colors but it's pretty obvious watching them side by side that Hugh just doesn't perform.
It really should be called lack of Hugh. They should only say they produce 10 million colors. Lifex is
creating awesome environments at my home. You can create all these different colors Hugh can't.
Hugh does have their huge family Philips behind them with the whole line of products. I would go with the
lifex bulbs for your normal bulbs that you want to make colors with but if you want the light strips the
Hugh go the bloom then I would have those around get a Logitech Harmony remote that can control all of it
and good to go. While I hope this comparison video has cleared up some questions about both of these
bulbs like I said lifex is for me but maybe not for Hugh. This is Justin Tech. See you later.