The Woosier Vest Edge in Strat Edge are finally here, or at least on Kickstarter.
I got to try Woosier out at this year's E3 and I was thoroughly impressed.
Here it is.
Alright, so what do you guys have here?
We have the new Vest Edge.
This one has six transducers and it works with stereo.
So three left, three right, which makes it amazing for VR.
Because in VR you don't have 7.1 but you do have the spatial sound.
This means that let's say you get an explosion on the left.
You'll feel it from the left and then if you turn around, the feeling will go to the other side.
So you'll feel it for the right.
And we have the Strat version, which is the lighter version.
It has a very powerful component of ours that you can put either on your chest or your waist
or anything with it.
Basically people can do jogging with it.
The sports activities from music for gaming.
Connect to everything.
Both of the products have Bluetooth, low latency, APTX.
Catch it on.
Sure.
We're going to try the loser Edge Vest with just headphones.
We're going to start with the battlefield.
We'll see how this Vest brings me into the experience.
Oh.
And I'm actually feeling the recoil against my chest.
And when there's an explosion, I kind of feel a sensation throughout my body.
Oh, wow.
Feels very real.
Can feel the, like, walking on the gravel right now.
Wow.
I feel that huge explosion.
Next, I had to try out the Vest in VR because that's what I'm most excited about.
But on right here.
What's going on right here is this gentleman is using the Oculus Quest system with the Woodrow Best Edge.
And as you can see, Oculus was kind enough to put two very high quality headphones
in two Oculus Quest.
So we've got to connect it directly on either side for the best possible sound quality.
There is Bluetooth support in Oculus Quest.
And there is a very handy USB-C port on the side.
But we don't have access to it yet, Oculus.
What's up.
That's how it's about Bluetooth.
But overall, it's an excellent headset.
It pairs beautifully with our products.
Awesome.
Well, I look forward to trying it.
First, I'm going to put a nice little face mask on.
Don't want those cooties.
There you go.
How do I look?
I suited up and turned on one of my favorites, Beat Saber.
The music was vibrating through my body and I felt ridiculously immersed.
I think I enjoyed the best more with music.
The battle field honestly felt a little too real and a bit jarring.
Wow.
Beat Saber is way more fun with this vest.
I've never played Beat Saber with vibrations running through my body.
And that was definitely an experience.
Definitely a game changer.
So this is the loser edge vest they have a kickstarter going.
The strap is also on kickstarter.
And I'm throwing the link in the description below.
Subscribe to this channel for more VR technology and make sure you click the bell for alerts.
Also follow me on social media.
I got some giveaways coming and a lot of other fun stuff.
As always, I'm Justin.
I'll take you later.
So you can position it like this.
You can position it here.
Position it in under your jacket or everyone.
I definitely want to try it out with VR porn at some point.
Yeah sure.
That's what these are designed for.
Right?