Hey guys, today I am at Tubit Circus in downtown Los Angeles.
It's basically the Stavenbusters, means virtual reality meets the circus kind of place.
What is that?
Why don't we go inside to find out?
Actually, one second, something just doesn't feel right.
Whoa, there we go, Tubit Circus, let's do this.
Tubit Circus is a micro amusement park.
This place is almost the size of a football field and is broken up into lots of different
zones.
They have VR arenas, comedy shows, a midway circus, story rooms, which are their
own take on escape rooms and a loaded arcade.
Many of the games here are made by indie developers, so you won't find them anywhere else.
Besides the games, they have a restaurant with some great food and an awesome bar with crafty
cocktails.
Oh, and a robot bartender.
Cheers!
I'm fantastic.
I guess you could say he has an eye for it.
Before I explore the premise, I wanted to know how this place got started.
So I talked to Brent Bushnell, the CEO of Tubit Circus.
Fun fact, his dad is the owner of Atari.
In 2008, we were pretty frustrated with fact that everybody was on their phones and on Facebook
and like basically home alone depressed.
And we thought that there was a really great opportunity to get people back together in public,
use a lot of new technology and also it's a fun stuff to get people playing together again.
So we just set up making interactive games, rooms, a laser beams, walls of buttons, stuff
we could just take to parties to get people having fun.
We did our own traveling carnival for two years before finally saying let's go permanent
and build this place.
This place is full of some of the most unique games you will ever see and lots of different
activities.
So, have they also have this?
Let's start with the circus.
So here is the midway and that is where you're getting that circus part of Tubit Circus.
Most of these games you see here are created by indie developers and you can't play these
anywhere else.
The midweek games were a lot of fun and unlike any carnival games I've ever played.
Most of them required you to play with others.
The things we make here are designed to create micro friendships.
Friendships that might just last for a second, they might get you to the bar, right?
They might last all night, they might be a new friend for life.
Tubit Circus is also jam packed with arcade games.
Just like the midweek games, a lot of these arcade games are made by indie developers.
One of my favorites was this DDR body movement game.
It was really, really neat.
Right behind me is the VR section of Tubit Circus.
They have a bunch of different games, multiplayer and single player and I'm going to play some.
When you come here, make sure you set up a point for VR right away.
The time slots fill up quickly.
This section has a few VR arenas where you can play a bunch of different VR games.
I played Zombite multiplayer.
Basically I shot obsombies with a few others.
It was fun, but not the most impressive VR experience.
There are also a bunch of VR rig setup.
If you're new to VR, you'll have to check them out.
One VR experience that caught my eye was battle zone.
This game had me driving around in a tank shooting enemies.
The seat moved, making it a super immersive experience.
After the eight minutes, I was left wanting more.
The next place I checked out was story rooms.
This area has a few different experiences that are basically there take on escape rooms.
I walked through the Minitor's maze, which actually had some scary moments.
The Minitor's maze, it reminded me of what you get at the void.
I really hope that Tubit Circus decides to introduce more of this because it's working and it's
a lot of fun.
I've also played the space gloves and wrapped VR story rooms and those are a must play with
larger groups.
Tubit Circus is unlike any other arcade I've ever been to.
Even with some games and VR setups, occasionally crashing, there were still always something
fun to experience in something new to see.
That's kind of a testament to what this place is.
It's an ever evolving technology experiment.
I've been here four times now and every time I come back, things have moved and there are
new things to try.
This is an awesome place to take a date or come with a large group of friends.
In fact, I actually had my birthday here last month.
So there you have it, that is Tubit Circus, it's definitely unlike any arcade I've ever
been to.
You guys have to check it out and you know what, I'm having to give away.
I'm giving away three gift cards worth $50 to some lucky winners head over to my Instagram
for instructions on that.
It is starting two days.
Before you do that, subscribe to this channel and click the bell for alerts.
I'm Justin and I'll take you later.