Hey guys, welcome to my AirPods Pro Review.
I am so excited to tell you guys about these.
I got them for Christmas and I've got a lot to say.
But first, if you guys enjoy this video, make sure you give it a like right down there.
And if you want to stay up to date with all my tech reviews and adventures,
make sure you subscribe.
There's a button right down there and click the bell for alerts.
Also, any products I bring up in this video,
there will be a link in the description below.
Alright, without further ado, here's my AirPods Pro Review.
Hmm, it rhymed.
The AirPods Pro are the latest earbuds coming from Apple,
joining the original AirPods.
The pros come with a super sleek wireless charging case that's incredibly enjoyable to open in
clothes, and are packing a much bigger punch than the OG AirPods.
They have a shorter stem than the originals, but I can guarantee you they will still fling off your
ears when taking off your shirt.
And I still feel like an alien wearing them.
Unlike the originals, these are sweat and water resistant.
So they're great for anyone who wants to work out, or is it a heavy sweater?
And their main selling point, of course, is their active noise cancellation ability,
which I'll get into in just a bit.
They support soft silicone tips for a snug fit in your ear and come with three different sizes
for a customized fit.
There's a fit test right on the iPhone, which helps you find the perfect size for your ear.
Just go to Bluetooth, click the eye on AirPods Pro, and run the ear tip fit test.
A lot of OG AirPods peeps say their AirPods easily get dirty with earwax.
First of all, gross. Second of all, I'm happy to report that with the AirPods Pro,
the silicone tips actually prevent wax from getting on the netting.
Yay! The AirPods Pro get about a total of 1.5 hours of one charge,
and up to 24 hours with multiple charges from their case.
Apple says after just about 5 minutes of charging, they should last you about an hour,
which is perfect for a cute workout.
While on that topic, I've got to say I don't feel entirely comfortable wearing these on a run.
I found that the AirPods on my left ear loosens up as I sweat, and I need to continually adjust it.
They haven't fallen out yet, but I'm not super confident that they'll stay in.
Casual walks in weightlifting haven't been an issue, and they're definitely more secure than the normal
AirPods. But I'm bummed, I wanted these to be my running earbuds.
The AirPods Pro have seamlessly worked themselves into my lifestyle.
If you're an Apple user like me, you'll experience the same thing.
Shooting? But this is great because this is helping me,
because I'm literally doing a little video on my AirPods Pro.
As soon as you open the case, you get a pop up on your iPhone, showing their battery life,
and they instantly connect. If they were last connected to my computer, they'll automatically connect to that.
Check out how seamless this is. Right now, I'm going to play the cut. I'm literally editing
this video right now, and when I take out the AirPods, the audio quickly starts playing from the speakers,
like instantly then put the AirPods Pro back in my ear, and it's playing in my ear already.
They obviously built with the Apple user in mind, so if you're not an Apple user, these may not be for you.
When you place the AirPods Pro into your ears, a pleasant ding goes off, letting you know they're
connected to a device and ready to play. It's pretty instantaneous and extremely satisfying.
One of my favorite features is that when you take an AirPods out of your ear,
the content pauses, and when you put it back in, it plays. So when you're ordering your coffee,
you won't miss a second of your podcast. The controls are pretty simple. A quick pinch on the
stem will pause and play your content. Two pinches will skip forward, and three pinches will skip backward.
If you hold down on the stem, a little ding will sound to indicate you've switched between
noise cancellation and transparency mode. I'll get into what these are, how they work, and just how
awesome they are, and just a bit. Don't worry. Like the original AirPods Pro, these have the Apple H1
chip. With this, you get some great abilities. First, you can talk to Siri, just say, hey Siri,
and ask whatever you'd like. This is also how you change the volume. It works seamlessly, but I wish
there was a way to control the volume right on the pods, because sometimes I'm in the middle of
a coffee shop, and I don't really want to be talking to her. A super cool functionality is sharing
music. You can share whatever's playing on your AirPods with one of their person who has a supported device.
This is a functionality I've been dreaming of for years now, and finally you can do it,
but I wish you can connect it to more devices. Hopefully in the future.
Now it's time for the nitty gritty. How it works? Let's start with the most important feature,
the active noise cancellation. Basically, how it works is there's an outward and inward facing
mic. Both are detecting unwanted noise inside and outside your ear, and canceling it out with anti-noise.
I don't know what anti-noise is, but it works. As someone who's used many noise canceling headphones,
I gotta say I am extremely impressed with the performance. I got these as a Christmas gift when I was
in New York, so naturally the first thing I had to do was try them out on the subway. In the past,
I've listened to music on the subway with my wired Apple headphones, and I could barely hear what I was
listening to. Let me tell you kids using the AirPods Pro on the subway was an air-credible experience.
They were the Apple of my ear. I liked them, okay? If you're in New Yorker, these are for you.
The next logical step was to try them out on a plane, right? But I was consumed by Delta's
incredible catalog of movies. I'm not a sponsor of Delta Airlines, but I would happily be one.
Hit me up, Delta. That I completely forgot to try them out. Also, while I'm on that subject,
if you want to use these AirPods Pro on and planes entertainment system, you'll need one of these blue
truth receivers to plug in. If you want to check that out, I put a link in the description below.
Anyway, I've used a noise cancellation at many loud coffee shops and while walking along busy streets,
and I could barely hear my surroundings. And as soon as I'm playing something,
everything disappears. Now, I understand this could be a little frightening,
completely shutting off yourself from the world. And that's why there's transparency mode.
Like I said earlier, when you pinch and hold the stem, it will switch to transparency mode.
In this mode, the AirPods let outside sound in, so you can hear your surroundings. It basically
removes that stuff you're feeling you get within the ear buds and allows your ears to breathe.
It's hard to explain, but it's really comfortable. I find myself using this a lot when I'm
walking outside because someone could easily be trying to jump me. Like, for an on-the-spot
tech review, can a tech YouTuber get some privacy around here? Oh gosh! Let's talk about sound quality.
The sound quality is great, but it's not amazing. Like, you're not going to get the quality that you get with
say the power beats pro, or your Bose noise canceling headphones, but for the size and the noise
cancellation, it's exactly what I need. While using the AirPods, I've noticed an occasional
blip in the audio. Like, very occasional, not to the point where I want to return them, but, you know,
definitely, to a point where Apple needs to figure it out. And it goes like a little bit, come on Apple.
Let's figure this out. What is that? We interrupt this video for a major AirPods pro mic
performance update. We have Justin in the field. Justin, what do you have for us?
Thank you, Justin. Yes, I'm outside Alford's one of the most overrated coffee shops in Los Angeles,
where I'm testing out from microphones on the AirPods. I've got lots of cars over here. We've
got lots of people chatting it up. Right now, I'm recording the audio from the AirPods Pro to my voice
Reynolds app, and I just want to give you an example how the mics work. Back to you, Justin.
Thank you, Justin, for that important wireless update. Okay, cool.
So here's how I see it. Yeah, they're 250 bucks. And that may sound like a lot of
money, but the price actually makes sense. The headphones I normally use for noise cancellation are my
Bose noise-canceling headphones, and I love them. But those go for $400. They're great, but they aren't as
compact as the AirPods Pro. Of course, they have impeccable sound quality, but what I love about my
AirPods is how versatile they are. I can easily pop the case in my pocket or in my backpack and take them
anywhere. The space they take is incredibly small, and they're packing a punch. Bose also sells
noise-canceling earbuds, but they're not wireless and they're the same price. Now, I've tried a lot of
headphones and earbuds, and I can confidently say that I justify this price point. I'm going to give the
AirPods Pro 4.5 out of 5 stars. They are seamless additions to your Apple family and have some
fantastic features, like noise cancellation and transparency mode. If you have an iPhone,
these are the most logical earbuds for you. It's a huge bummer I can't wear them running,
but they fit in all other aspects of my lifestyle. I think there's definitely still room for improvement when
it comes to audio control, but the AirPods Pro's far outweigh the AirPods cons. And August,
Jolly G, I freaking love them. Sorry for the swears. Let me know if you guys have any questions about
these products in the comments below. Also, I'm considering doing a comparison video between the
AirPods Pro and the Power Beats Pro. If that's something you're interested in, also let me know
down there. And if there are any other earbuds that you think I should try or compare, also let me know in the
comments below. That is all I've got for you guys. Again, subscribe for more tech reviews and adventures
right down there. It's free. Also, if you enjoyed this video, give it a like. That's all I've got for you
guys today. I'm Justin and I'll take you later. But overall, August, Jolly G, I love them.
Can you say that again? Yeah. August, Jolly G, I freaking love them.
August, Jolly G. August, Jolly. I'm the one that wrote it.