Hey guys, welcome back to my channel. I am so excited for this episode because I am at
sandbox VR. They have a bunch of different VR experiences from throwing players into a pirate
treasure hunt to shooting aliens on a futuristic space station. And now you can even beam into the
Star Trek universe. This is one of the most unique VR locations I've ever been to. It's no wonder
Katy Perry, Justin Timberlake and Will Smith have invested millions into this place. You can play with
up to six people in these experiences. Let's put our living stereo stylus in this room.
When you first walk into sandbox VR, you're completely transported to a futuristic station.
There are multiple green screen stages set up for parties to enter the virtual world.
These rooms and conjunction with the gear you put on will track your every move to fully encapsulate
you into the virtual world. Today, my friends and I are playing two of their five experiences.
We put on hand and foot trackers so the cameras in the room could track us. Before we even
enter the virtual world, there was a unique pregame experience. We split into two teams and chose team names.
Next, we took player pictures. The first game we played was unbound fighting lead. It's a player
first player game where you fight the opposing team with your choice of three weapons. Each weapon
has its own ability and play style. Whether it's throwing out landmines or sending fire towards your opponent.
Before we started the actual game, there was a tutorial where we chose our avatars and learned the game
mechanics. Then we were transported into an arena from an underground elevator. It literally felt like we were in the
hunger games. Each round a player from each team entered the stage to fight. The rounds were a workout.
I wouldn't recommend playing this game with under four people because you need the time to rest between rounds.
The game had wind effects which made us feel like we were there and the sandbox employee was a commentator
giving us tips and play by play announcements. I could totally see this in a VR esports setting
and that is definitely the plan with sandbox. So I'm super excited for the future of VR esports.
After playing that game, all right, next up we got dead wood mansion. It's a bit different of an experience and I'm
so ready for it. In this game, we were all in the same team sent to a mansion to fight off
hordes of zombies. Each way brought new enemies where we needed to adapt and figure out their weaknesses.
We even got to choose the weapons we wanted. A submachine gun, dual pistols or sniper rifles.
The game was full of scary moments and we screamed a lot. It was challenging too and we could
even die and our teammates would have to revive us. Compared to you with L, the graphics seemed less
vivid, especially when there were a lot of zombies coming at us in once. But this also makes sense since
this is the first experience sandbox ever made. Sandbox VR offers a unique VR experience and is
completely different than another one of my favorites the void. The void has you walking around a maze
and is more cinematic and sometimes scary. Sandbox is all about teamwork and physical activity.
I will say there were some technical snafos that need to be polished. It took about 20 minutes for them
to get dead wood mansion up and running and some of us had issues with our guns. Mine worked just fine.
You a fell took about 10 minutes of troubleshooting to begin because a couple of our avatars were stuck
into split position on the ground. But it was funny. Technical difficulties aside, Sandbox VR
is building a desirable experience here and I highly recommend everyone to check it out. They offer
the most player customization I've seen at any VR location and some of the best replayability.
After our games we went into the lobby and watched awesome the edited replay videos. This little touch
added to the overall experience letting us continue the fun outside of the game. I asked Cameron the
general manager what Sandbox has in store for the future. So what they can really expect is
this kind of getting a bit more involved in like tournament self and now we have to be a fell. We're really
trying to really expand not only in terms of our stores but also in terms of our content. Always looking for
something new so we finally did PvP and that's one of the first ones to do it. So we want to see what
us we can do with that maybe doing tournaments or kind of really opening the door and seeing hey can we get
something going on that's like a membership or eSports or something along those lines. My guess is VR eSports
is going to grow a lot over the next few years and I can't wait to be there for it. That is Sandbox VR.
It was so awesome. You definitely have to check it out. It is located in a bunch of different cities
and a bunch or more are coming this year and early next year. So definitely check it out. If you guys want to see
more videos like this be sure to subscribe right down there. You do it that way you know when my video
comes out. Also did you like this video? Why don't you give it a like right down there so other people
can find it because I think people should see this. It's pretty cool. So that's all I've got for
you today. Stay tuned for another video coming next week. I'm Justin and I'll take you later.
I can feel you guys watching me right now. No.