Hey guys, I'm at Oculus Connect, and I'm about to go right back here and play Echo Quest VR.
Yep, that's right. Echo VR is coming out on the quest, and I'm so pumped because it's one of my favorite games, one of my favorite multiplayer games. Let's go check it out.
Echo VR is basically ultimate Frisbee on steroids.
If you've read Ender's Game, it's basically that.
You're flying around in Arena in Zero Gravity, throwing a Frisbee into a goal to score points.
You use thrusters to fly around, latch onto obstacles to navigate through the field, and punch the opposing team to stun them.
For the demo we were split into two teams of four, I was so excited to get back into the Arena on Quest.
The gameplay just as smoothly as it does on the Rift, but definitely had less graphics quality, but that's to be expected.
As I played, I was yelling to my other teammates to pass me the Frisbee, and I was yelling at a pure excitement.
Zero Gravity in Virtual Reality is truly the best VR. If you have a Rift, get this game right now, it is free.
This is the game that literally sold me on VR and VR eSports.
I really think that this is the game that will encourage some VR skeptics out there to finally get a quest.
Oh my goodness, let me tell you, it was unbelievable.
It was just as smooth and amazing as it is on the Rift.
It was so much fun, you'll have to check this out when it comes out. There is no release date yet, but when it comes out,
I will definitely be making a video about it.
For more innocuous, be sure to subscribe to this channel and ring that bell for alerts.
And if you like this video, why don't you give me a like right down there?
It looks cute, I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.
Thanks for watching!