Hey I'm on the show floor at CS 2020 and right now I'm on stage at Monster, most known
for their HDMI cables, they're jumping into the smart home race with a bunch of new smart
home lighting and it's pretty cool let's check it out.
Monsters dig you in several different light designs and spring 2020, ranging from 3D wall-mounted
panels to water-proof LED strips to hand-dilled or white.
We have an entire array of smart Wi-Fi lighting under monster, price points ranging from $29
of to $69 so it's available for everyone to enhance their entire living space with light.
These are two flagship items, Prism and Digit and they allow you to create modular patterns
of light and color to really reinvigorate your space.
The Prism light panels have a unique magnet bracketing system so mounting and moving around
your light design is easy. Digit does the same thing but you can write custom messages and draw shapes
so it allows you to write anything you want, tell the time, write your name, write fun little messages.
Could you put like, see yaaase?
See yaaase definitely, love that.
This one's my favorite, this is the orb. This is a handheld rechargeable indoor outdoor lighting unit.
The orbs have a built-in handle, our water resistant, and can hang as pendant lights.
Another thing I love about these lights, you don't need a bridge, just Wi-Fi and the monster
lights app. Can you tell me a little bit about the monster lighting app? Absolutely.
So our map. Absolutely. Absolutely. Our monster app gives you full control over multi color,
multi white, and color changing modes. So you can create custom scenes that are mixed between
the color pattern, whether it's flashing, fading, dancing to the music and how fast it's going,
what colors it's using, what brightness, what speeds, and you can save that all into a custom
built scene. There are also preset ambient moods on the monster lights app.
That give you everything from soft light to read by to fun swirling colors and strobe lights.
This light bar right here, what is this exactly? How does that work?
Cool thing about this is the stand. Right now it's set into horizontal mode,
but you can also use adhesive or screw and make it wall-mounted for a nice little sconce.
Or you can remove it and snap it here on the bottom to have a vertical light bar,
hop one in every corner, and suddenly your entire room is changing colors.
So monsters lighting seems to be a beast of a product and it doesn't have a scary price point.
Alright guys, I don't want to get a ticket. Make sure you subscribe right down there. I got more
CES content coming out. Give it a like if you enjoyed it. I'm Justin. I got to go to CES. I'll take you later.