This year's E3 was packed with announcements and attendees lining up to play games.
There was also a lot of buzz because of the glaring accents of play stations.
But I've got to say, this year's event was packed with a stunning variety of booths, games,
and technology, not to mention surprises out the Wazoo.
I learned first hand, bass, and body about some emerging technology, played some highly
anticipated games, and has very important business meanings.
Even with my itinerary being as packed as it was, I still somehow managed to find time
to work out, dance, and time to recharge.
Here we are at E3 2019, one of the world's biggest gaming conventions.
I'm so excited to head in there and see all of the video games and technology.
If you guys see this graphic throughout the video, that means I'm coming out of the video,
specifically on that topic.
So, subscribe to this channel so you can watch it.
I'm going to go ahead on in.
Why can't you join me?
E3 is a gaming conference, so I'll start with some games and VR.
But I tested out lots of emerging tech, and this video will cover all of my highlights.
If you want to just see the booth that blew my mind, skip to red pill VR.
The first game I'm going to try is Pokemon, Sword, and Shield.
Something just doesn't feel right to me, though.
How about this?
Not that one.
There we go.
Feeling legendary.
Let's go.
I'm about to enter this Pokemon stadium and fight some Pokemon.
Let me practice.
Got it.
Got a stretch.
Yeah.
Just like tennis.
Are you ready?
I'm ready.
Oh, okay.
Yes.
After my warm welcome, I hopped into the demo.
Which had me at a water game, solving a puzzle by turning waterfalls on and off and fighting
Pokemon battles.
I faced the gym leader Nest up and experienced Dino Max mode for the first time.
It's a fun mechanic, but nothing groundbreaking.
Well, maybe literally.
This demo has me ready to walk through some tall grass and avoid eye contact with strangers
that all costs.
E3 is a gaming conference.
We can know what?
There is a ton of technology, and I had to cover all of it.
You know what?
It was covering all of me.
First up was the Unreal Garden, where I put on the Microsoft HoloLens and walked through
an avatar-like interactive garden.
Look at all these people, just pointing their fingers around.
It looks kind of funny.
The garden was full of holographic art pieces floating jellyfish in a flying nanta.
So what exactly is going on over here?
We have a technology to deliver, we have to keep back using ultrasound.
So you can see it's basically ultrasound waves, hitting the palm of your hand and creating
sensation.
Oh, right now I'm experiencing ultrasound waves.
I can't say if that's something that I've ever experienced before.
Is it a boy?
The Unreal Garden looked beautiful, but augmented reality is still really limited by the technology.
On the HoloLens, you only see the world on a small screen, and the holograms blocked people
even if they were technically closer to you.
I'm anxious to see how the technologies improve, but the HoloLens 2 coming out later this
year.
Next up, virtual reality.
VR took over this year's event with booths like Facebook Gaming and Oculus and attendance,
and in case you didn't know, Facebook owns Oculus.
I played games across all different VR systems, but I was most impressed with Stormland
on the Rift S. Stormland transported me to a dystopian future where I was a robot tracing back
memories.
I found weapons and upgrades that gave me the ability to fly and climb walls.
The level was beautiful, and I can't wait to play more so I can discover even more
worlds and fight enemies.
Stormland is one of the games that literally sells you on the Rift S. I don't have a Rift
S, but I really want one now, because that game was unbelievable.
Definitely check out Stormland if there's a demo around you, you have to do it.
The game comes out this holiday season, so definitely stay tuned for it.
Next, I met up with Philips Hue, my favorite smart lighting brand, to check out its personal
wireless lighting system, Hue's Sync.
Hue Sync is an app that runs on both Mac and Windows PCs, and syncs all of your Hue color
capable lights with the content on your computer.
It creates an immersive experience when you're playing games, listening to music, or watching
videos, and it works with any media you throw up on the screen.
Even me.
Philips Hue has also teamed up with Razor to make the PC gaming experience even more immersive
with Razor Chroma.
Unlike Hue Sync, which basically takes what's on the screen, Razor Chroma allows video game
developers to program lighting effects within their code.
I played some Mortal Kombat, and was pulled into the game.
I'd say this is the closest you're going to get to VR without putting a headset on.
It's definitely something that I'm going to look into for my household, and maybe you
should too.
Thank you so much.
Okay, lastly, I've got to tell you about two booths that blew my mind this year.
The first one was Fortnite.
They were dance shows, game shows, and tons of food.
I spent a good three hours at this booth, and I would have stayed longer if I could have.
But, nope, I had to edit this video, you're welcome, YouTube.
Finally, here is the booth that had me shook it, Red Pill VR.
Imagine if Coachella, the Sims, and Virtual Reality were all morphed together, and that's
what you get.
Red Pill VR allowed visitors to enter an interactive electric garden dance club in virtual reality.
We are essentially building the future of social music experiences.
We believe that music is one of the most driving things that brings people together.
So we invented a technology that allows for infinite scalability for an artist to be able
to reach a larger fan base than just the number of tickets that's torn at a door.
We're creating worlds and environments in which artists can perform, and connect to their fanbase.
And as we as consumers of the music can have these social sharing experiences with our friends,
from different cities all over the world, sharing this experience together.
It was time for me to join the party.
So I threw on a headset, a vibration backpack, and entered the club.
Inside was a real DJ playing music and a giant sized dancer.
Both were at the booths with me injected into the game.
Hey DJ!
The dancer was wearing body trackers to fully encapsulate her movements.
Red Pill VR has invented a technology that allows them to take a stereo signal of sound
and break it down to its core components, and apply the audio to reactive objects in the club.
So you may notice that a mushroom is beating to the base, or a flurry in the air is moving to the keyboard.
Isaiah says this is just the beginning.
Right now it's a location-based solution.
In other words, what you see here, we will show up and create and do as an immersive event experience.
So that's our sort of phase one launch.
But ultimately Red Pill is a platform.
You as an artist can come in to our platform, build your nightclub, or your venue or your space.
Invite your friends to come here you play, tear a virtual ticket, or have a subscription,
or make it free, or make it sponsor, and show your music with the world.
This segment is barely scratching the surface, so stay tuned for more content on Red Pill VR in the future.
There's the Aurora Ballet Ruralis.
There's the Northern Lights!
How does this technology make you feel?
Is this the beginning of Ready Player One?
Tell me what you think in the comments.
Also, don't forget people.
It's important to dance and real life too.
So there you have it.
That was E3 and it was unbelievable.
The technology and video games that I saw this year has gotten me so excited for the future.
Remember, if you saw this, that means I'm coming out of the video on that topic.
So stay tuned for that.
How do you do that?
Buy subscribing to my channel right down there.
Do it.
Also, follow me on social media.
It's fun.
As always, I'm Justin and I'll take you later.
Oh my god.