Hey, it's Justin Tech, and I'm at Pepcom's Digital Experience at CES 2020, and right now I'm joined by Aaron Amy, the CEO and founder of Brilliant.
So, Aaron, what is Brilliant? Brilliant is a whole home controller for all of the smart devices in your house.
Today we have two new products. We have a smart dimmer switch. It has a little touch groove, and you can dim the lights. You can turn the lights off on with a tap.
You also have a motion detector, so you can do occupancy based lighting, save energy.
And it also has a really unique capability where you can run scenes just by double tapping on it.
You can say, I'm going to watch a movie, and adjust the lighting just the way you want it. It turns off the stereo.
And the ability to just kind of do that and have it automatically happen from a light switch is really unique and different.
The other device they announced was a smart plug. Both the plug and the new light switch will work alongside one main brilliant switch,
which acts as a hub. Why should someone go with Brilliant?
Well, as you add smart devices in your house, it gets a little cumbersome to control them.
You find that you're running a bunch of different apps on your phone, and if you're not the homeowner or you don't have your ringer on,
you might miss someone who's at the door with a video doorbell. It's brilliant.
Build right into the walls of the house and allows you to control all of your smart devices and now provide all of them smart lighting.
Who are some notable companies that Brilliant works with?
We work with, for example, the ring video doorbell. We have Amazon Alexa voice services built into it.
We work with Honeywell Home and ECOB on the smart thermostat space, Schlag and August and Yale in smart locks.
We work with Sonos in a really nice way where you see all of your playlists and favorites and you can control zones and everything from it.
Pretty much most of the smart devices out there that are popular that we work with.
Can you tell me a little bit about the functionality?
If someone rings a ring doorbell, you see the video stream on the screen and you can unlock the door right from that.
It's room to room, video, intercom capabilities, and you can do remote camera viewing from your app.
You can actually take pictures and upload those onto your wall, so that's a sort of digital picture frame built in.
It's very intuitive. One of the things that's been a lot of time doing, trying to make it really easy to use, how to simplify it.
Are there any other features coming in the near future?
We do automatic over the air updates, so we're constantly rolling out new features.
Since we've launched just a year ago, we've rolled out over a dozen new integration, it just gets better and better over time.
Keep your eyes open for more videos on Brilliant, especially as I start unveiling smart home in Palm Springs.
That's right. We're building a smart home of your dreams and you can rent it. Brilliant.
There you have it. That is brilliant. It sounds like it could be a brilliant solution for your smart home.
If you want to check out their Instagram, it's brilliant, underscore tech. Yeah, they're my cousin.
Justin underscore tech. Brilliant underscore tech. I love that. I have a lot more C.S. coverage coming.
Make sure you subscribe right down there. Click a like if you enjoyed this. I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.