Welcome to Justin Tech, I'm Justin Easter, for those of you who know me, I am obsessed
with my Fitbit Charge HR, I've had it for months now, so the only logical thing to do
is to go run out and buy the Fitbit Blaze and do a comparison video, so let's bring out
the contenders. We've got the Fitbit Blaze that retails for $200 and the Charge HR that retails
for $150, but you can buy them at best and you know what that means, you get a 20% off coupon
and you save lots of money. The Fitbit Blaze sports a super sleek looking screen that's
definitely bigger and more noticeable than the Charge HR. The tracker itself is just the square
piece in the middle and you can pop it out, you can replace the bands with different colors and
materials, they have metal, leather and the classic band which you're seeing here. Unlike the
Blaze, the Charge HR is just one piece. Once you've chosen one of the five colors, you're
stuck with it forever. The Charge HR's functions are very simple and limited and that's why I like
it. You can quickly and easily navigate between all of the day stats by tapping on the band and there's
also a quick view feature where you can double tap and it brings you right to a specific stat. You
can easily track or work out by holding down its only button and then when you're finished you hold
down again and it ends. The Charge HR also supports caller ID. When someone calls you the band
gives you one little vibration on your wrist and shows you their name, the band also supports four different
ways to display the time and or date. Now for the Blaze, the Blaze looks more like a smart watch,
but it isn't. Instead of tapping through each stat, you must slide, tap and then scroll to see all the
stats. You can set different clock faces that allow you to scroll through a few stats, but not all
of the faces show every stat and some don't even show any. I don't get it. Like why not?
Tracking your workouts on the Blaze is awesome and it displays a great workout screen. On top of
caller ID, the Blaze also supports text message and calendar alerts. You can scroll up from the bottom
and see all of your notifications. I'm not a huge fan of the caller ID on this tracker because when
someone calls, instead of it just vibrating once, it just continues to vibrate until you click the
button on it and if you don't answer the phone call, then you get another vibration that says you missed
the call and it's like, I know I missed the call, I just told you to shut up and stop vibrating
and you vibrate it again. The vibration on this thing is annoying. Luckily you can turn off the
notifications by scrolling down from the top. This is also where you can control the music from your phone
and you can control the volume for the music with the two buttons on the right of the Blaze.
The Blaze also has a stopwatch and a timer and you could also set alarms on and off. You just can't
create alarms. You must do that using the app, bummer. One of the coolest features of the Blaze is
FitStar. It's basically your own personal trainer. It comes with three different workouts and
guides you through them with vibrations and gyps. I'm not happy with the Blaze screen. It just isn't
very responsive. I try and move things back and forth or press buttons and it takes a few tries sometimes.
Both watches are water resistant but not waterproof. After ranked FitB Blaze for two weeks
there were practically no scratches on the screen. My charge HR on the other hand is full of scratches.
But I don't really care. What I do care about is what happened to my first. Yes, my first charge HR
I already had another one. It started bubbling up and then peeling off. But I was really pleased with
their customer service. They set me new when I had it in five days. When it comes down to choosing a
winner I can really only choose what's best for my lifestyle. So I have to say for me the charge HR is the
winner. I love that I could just tap through all of the statistics and that's it. If I want to start
to work out I press a button. With the Blaze it's just a little too convoluted for me and it's screen
is responsive enough and I hate the vibrations. The Blaze has a lot more functions than the charge HR
but when it comes down to it I want to fit this tracker that's simple. The charge HR is simple. It just works
and it works quickly. The Blaze just doesn't do it for me. If I want something as big as the Blaze
and with even more functions then maybe I just go for the Apple Watch which is only $50 more. Ultimately
I have to say the true winner here is Fitbit. I have never known so much about my body. Their app is
amazing. It graphs out my resting heart rate, my sleeping patterns, my workouts, steps, calories and they've
got some really great products that go along with that. I definitely recommend getting some sort of
Fitbit because the app is just that good. So that is it for my comparison video. If you have any
questions about the two bands or the app, please let me know in the comments below. Also, I would
love to hear which Fitbit tracker or any tracker for that matter that you love and why. Please subscribe
to stay up to date with my videos and I will see you later.