I'm here with La Ura and we are doing a Moby site change. Okay, I knew that you wanted to try this so I was like
Well, why don't you guys to show you?
This is the the cartridge for it. It's tiny. What we'll do is I'm so excited. You're gonna take this and then you're gonna put the insulin
I'm gonna hand it in the top. Wow
Yeah, that's you see it going and you think I can see it also from this side. We got it. Yeah
Good job
Okay, I did it. All right look at this
Put that down and push down there you go now the cartridge is on now look at I mean look at how short that tubing is
That's five inches. I don't know what it is in the years. I think
10 centimeters
10 centimeters and that is the one I would love to use actually with Moby with Moby. It's always interesting to hear different people's viewpoints
I mean everyone is not really yeah, we may have one different things. Yeah, so that's that's good
Which is why it will never work
us
Yeah, of course we will always find something like that because we want different things
Exactly, actually we want the same thing for diabetes to be cured
Type yeah, is that it is that where you go?
Oh, there it is
Insulin now it's ready for me to insert so I think all I'll do this. Okay, and I'll put
There I know what to do don't worry
Well, you're okay, bro
You're faster at this than I am because I just started this
Did it hurt? No, I never feel it just put it in my eyes. Let me see yeah
Oh, nice so I put this in there. Well, you know it's in there. I mean it's not impossible and then okay, and you clip it there
I'm just gonna put it right there
This is what it is look there's my inside it. Let me put my mic on that
And that's that
I'm wondering when I will be able to do it
And maybe next year next year next year