Hey everyone, I have some really exciting news. I'm going to see yes! Oh my god, freaking out.
This has been a goal of mine for a really long time and I'm finally going and I'm going as
media and I'm going on media days and I'm related, but I'm also a little overwhelmed and that's why
I'm making this video. If you've been to see yes and you have any tips, that would be amazing.
Are there any companies or booths that you think I need to go to? I know it's just
such a huge event and I'm not going to be able to get to everything. So if there's anything you
think that I should check out, let me know in the comments. I can use all the help that you guys could
give me. Please. I already have a bunch of meetings set up. Philips you. They have some new products. They're
going to be showing off brilliant this like smart home control switch that I cannot wait to check out and
I do want to do future videos with them and then I have a meeting with Panasonic and Toto.
I'm going to do a smart home video of virtual reality video and kind of like an overall what you had to
see at CES this year video. That one I'm going to have a lot of fun with because I kind of just want to wander
around like the Sands Expo and find companies that I think are super innovative and are going to have a huge
effect in 2020 in the future. If you want to follow my journey at CES, subscribe to this channel if you
haven't already and also want to follow me on social media especially Instagram Twitter because I'm
going to be posting a lot on there. That's more of like behind the scenes and fun quick stuff. So that's
pretty much it. I just want to let you guys know that I'm going to... It's like I literally can't get it for it.
Have a great holiday season and the next time you see me will be at CES. I'm Justin and I'll see you at
CES. That didn't work. I'm Justin and I'll take you later.