Hey everyone, it's Justin, and if you're anything like me, you have no idea what to get your mom this year for Mother's Day.
Well, if you want your mom to be a little more tech savvy and have an awesome new device, you may want something for my Mother's Day tech gift guide.
Here it is.
First gift is the Satachi CD slot, it goes into any CD slot, and then you can mount your phone right in this.
Listen, my mom, see sometimes text and drives, or she picks up her phone to try and call me.
No, you're not doing that anymore. We're going to put this in your car, and then you know what we're going to do for you.
We're going to teach you how to use Siri. You can say, hey Siri, call Justin.
Hey Siri, text Justin, thank you so much for the gift, I love it.
And also, if they have an Apple music subscription, hey Siri, place them on Dreyabuchelli.
Saving lives, not texting and driving, and also your mom's learning how to use Siri.
I love it.
The second gift is something that I find really intriguing, but I never actually use myself, and it's portal from Facebook.
Now, portal is this type of tablet with a camera that's meant for keeping people connected through video chats.
What's so cool about these is that it's a stationary tablet with a camera that tracks you.
So you can literally place this tablet down, be doing your laundry, be cooking, walking around an entire room, and it will follow you.
So you don't have to hold your phone the whole time, you don't have to be out of frame, it's really, really neat.
On top of that, there's also Alexa built in, as well as other apps, like Spotify, CNN, and a ton of other ones that you can,
actually use as a tablet and go through those apps.
So there are two models for the portal.
There's the portal and the portal plus.
They're normally $200 and $350, but right now they're $100 off each, so it's either $99 or $249, and that's ending on May 12.
So make sure if you want to get this, you get it before then.
Again, I don't have the portal.
I can't fully be like, this is amazing. I used it, but I think it's really intriguing, and it's something that I'm considering getting my mom is here.
I help my mom isn't watching this.
So the next device is a smart home device, and it's really easy to use.
It is the Philips Hue light switch dimmer. It's super simple. It comes with a light bulb and a dimmer switch.
It's great for parents that, you know, in the middle of the night, they want to just run and use the bathroom.
They just click this little remote, that they could put right by their bed, and it turns light on and off, and also dims it.
If you want to go even a little further with that, you can look at the Philips Hue family, get that smart hub, and then also get some other light bulbs,
and then your mom will be able to use her Alexa, Google home, or Siri in order to turn those on.
They're great device, and you could always add on other smart home devices as well.
The next one is another gift I got my mom, and she loves it, and it is the NYX Play Wi-Fi picture frame.
You set up an account for the frame, and then what you're given is an email address that you can then email photos to the frame.
Literally, if I'm like on vacation with my friends, and I want to send a picture to my mom saying hi, I just take that picture,
and email to my mom at NYX Play.com.
I mean, that's not the email, she has a name, but I'm not giving out her personal email.
I don't want you guys sending dirty pics to her frame.
And not only can you send pictures, but you can also send little messages, so I can send her a picture that's like,
and also put Happy Mother's Day.
The NYX Play frame started $140 and go all the way up to like $200.
I'm happy with $140 when I got for my mom. It works just great.
My final gift is like, super, super easy to do, and I've actually done it before, hallmark e-cards.
On this website, you can go through a bunch of different cards that are sent to people over email,
and they have videos, beautiful music, beautiful images, and you just kind of personalize it, and then you can send it off.
It's just a really easy way to send your mom a card, but also they're really powerful sometimes.
Like, I sent my mom one last year, and she legitimately texted me saying, I bought it.
It's $5 for a month, or you can pay for an entire year, and it's only $1.75 a month for the year.
I mean, think about it. If you're going to get a card every three months, even, you're still paying less than if you go to CDS.
Those are all the tech gifts I have for you right now. If you have any for me, please let me know in the comments below.
I want to know what tech gifts you are getting your mom, and teaching your moms how to use.
I'm going to have all the links below again.
Subscribe to my Instagram, my Facebook, my YouTube, I'm constantly putting out material.
That way you guys can stay informed on discounts, and fun tech, and things for your mom, and stuff like that.
As always, I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.