The Dexcomg7 is officially the longest lasting continuous glucose monitor.
Here's what you need to know.
The FDA just cleared a 15 day wear version of the Dexcomg7, making it the longest lasting
CGM. Plus, it's got a 12 hour brace period, so make that 15 in a half days.
And get this, Dexcom says the accuracy is better than the 10 day version thanks to an updated
algorithm, dropping its marred from 8.2% to 8%.
The lower the better. The updated CGM will roll out in the second half of 2025. It is my
understanding that the sensor and the adhesive are exactly the same. It's just updated software.
I'm excited that I won't have to pack as many for trips. There will be less waste. But,
I'm a little apprehensive about the cleanliness of the CGM because I've noticed that the adhesive
can get really dirty by the end of the 10 day life cycle and not look as cute.
What do you think about the updated DexcomgCGM? Are you excited? Are you worried?
Let us know in the comments and follow this page for updates and more diabetes tech tips and news.