Oh, well, hello there, you two, come on in, come on in. Welcome to my smart home.
Any product I'm gonna point out in this video will be in the bio. One of the main devices
that is power in my smart home is one you probably have heard of and its name is Alexa.
And I whisper that because she's very sensitive, she sits right there. Basically, I tell her what I want her to do.
And she does it. And she has no feelings for feelings never get hurt.
Right over here is my happy smiley face neon light.
I connected it to a leviton smart plug right down here.
And I programmed that to connect to my wing device.
And my wing device then talks to Alexa.
I could say Alexa, turn off neon.
And then I can go Alexa, turn on neon.
Okay.
And there you go. You can connect any appliance to it and it will work.
So if you have like an air conditioning unit in your apartment and you want the air to turn on before you come home,
you can log on to your wing app and actually turn on the air conditioner remotely.
Other than that, I have few and life effects.
They both have their pros and cons.
I have another video that you can totally check out basically weighing which one you should buy.
Right over here, I have a life effects light.
And then I have my few light strips over here.
The cool thing about the few light strips is that right on my phone,
it connects to the apple home.
And I have my kitchen lights right here where I can slide up and down the brightness.
And I can also go to color and choose different colors.
Cute light strips. They're kind of expensive.
But you get these really great lights.
And I also can talk to Siri.
Hey Siri, change the kitchen lights to green.
And Siri does it.
So that's pretty cool.
I also have these few lights up here.
All of these are connected to my smart home as well.
So what I can do is I can connect that smart outlet over there with my life effects lights
and my few lights and they can all connect to my phone.
And I can do this.
Alexa, turn off home lights.
Okay.
And of course, it didn't turn off my living room light.
But I mean with technology, there's always issues.
The light effects bulbs are very temperamental and I've started to transition to you myself
because they're just more consistent and reliable.
The cool thing about this is that I've connected my Logitech Harmony remote with my receiver
and then that all connects to my Amazon Alexa.
So I can do things like, oops, she's already ready for me to say something.
Alexa, turn on Apple TV.
Okay.
And then what she's going to do is she's going to talk to the Logitech remote
which will turn on my receiver.
Turns on the Apple TV.
And it will also turn on the TV.
And then there you go.
This is my Apple TV and three, two, one.
Alexa, turn on the speakers.
Okay.
And then she's going to play the whatever's.
Yeah, she'll play whatever was last on my phone.
And I did not do that on purpose.
No, I did it.
I had an Alexa out there and I also have an echo in here.
I need to whisper.
Echo turn on bedroom lights.
There's my bedroom lights.
So I have two life ex bulbs right in those lamps.
And then down here, I have more LED lights.
The great thing about these lights are there only $18.
And I made them smart lights by connecting them to the same kind of outlet
that I had out there the Levitton outlet.
So for 35 bucks plus 18, I have a smart light.
And then they also have this cute little remote right here that I can change
the colors.
I do have to get down because the sensors down there.
Well, I hope you liked the tour of my smart home.
If you have any questions about the gadgets or want me to do a specific video on any of the gadgets in general,
I can do that because I can literally talk about these things for hours.
Oh, well, hello there YouTube.
Come on to my new smart home.
I just moved to it's my second smart home.
This video is all about remote to buttons and switches around my smart home
that you can get to make your life way easier
and way smarter.
A lot of people out there are saying, why do you need Alexa?
The reason is because I don't want to move.
But if I'm okay with moving or if I have a remote with me, then I'll use that.
I will have all of the links to these products, the best deals I've found in the bio
down below.
So let's come right over here to my power station.
So what we have right here is you may not recognize it, but this is a light switch.
We do not touch these.
In fact, I should put some tape over those.
What we do use though is this right here.
And this is the Phillips Hue like dimmer switch.
This thing is so, so great.
This alone is $25, but you can also get it for $35 with the light bulb.
I can control up to 10 light bulbs just with this.
I'm turning them on, off, dimming them.
Great device and super cheap for what it does.
And if you're in the Phillips Hue family, this is like a no-brainer.
I would probably have five of these if I had more queue lights around my house.
Or bigger house.
One day YouTube one day.
The device that I just got and I am in love with is the Logitech Hop.
And actually put the bell crow on it.
That way I can kind of pop it off, put a tentet.
For the starter pack, it's $57.
The starter pack includes the bridge for the device.
And to just get a button, it's $40.
As a smart home, liver and builder and creator.
I'm always looking for a device that connects all of my smart devices.
And this is it.
I can either tap it once.
Tap it twice or do a long tap.
Give me three different abilities.
If I tap it once, it turns on all my lights.
If I do a long press, it turns on the art mode.
What that does is it completely transforms my entire apartment.
It turns off my light lights into color light bulb.
Also, right over here, I have my neon smiley face.
That turns on with the we most smart outlet.
It sets my living room lights and my kitchen lights to dim.
And it turns on music.
And so whenever I'm going to have friends over,
I just long press that.
I actually haven't had many friends over since I've gotten that device soon.
I will.
So when I have friends and then when I have those friends over,
I'm going to put party mode on.
One day, you two, one day.
All I have to do to turn this off.
So that's party mode, and I freaking love it.
This next device is one of my favorite devices.
It is the Logitech Harmony Remote.
And what I love about it so much is that it controls my complete entertainment system.
As well as all of my lights, it has a few different buttons right here that control my Apple TV,
my Nintendo Switch, my speakers.
So if I want to watch a movie on Apple TV, all I do is press this movie button right here.
And it turns on my receiver, turns on my Apple TV, and it will turn on my TV.
And then I can watch a movie.
Then if I want to turn it off, I just click this off button and it turns everything off.
I can change the light set if I want.
So this light right here, it's connected to this.
So if I don't want that on, it gets turned off.
If I do want it on, but I want it dim it a little bit and just dim it down right there.
And then I can turn this light off because it's a little too bright for the movie.
I'm going to turn my kitchen light off too.
And then that one.
And then another light bulb.
And then we go to the club.
And then we go out.
And another one.
The Logitech Harmony Remote.
It is so worth it.
If you have a system or set up that will fully utilize its potential.
It's sleep, light, and really comfortable in your hands.
Who doesn't like something that's comfortable in your hands?
Next.
So.
It's way right there.
So welcome to my bedroom.
The one and only just a tech bedroom.
Come on.
You have this brand new pop button that I showed you over there.
But this is the gray version.
If I tap it once, it will turn my lights on.
I want to get things done.
Some spring cleaning, summer cleaning, winter cleaning.
I could double tap it.
And it goes into like bootlighting when I want to get things done.
And then I can hold it down.
And it's a nice little night like late night.
Then I go switch.
It's like late night pillow talk or just like late night nighttime.
Get out of here.
So there's your teas in switches, remotes, and buttons around a smart home.
What basically I've done so far.
I have a lot more to do.
Make sure to subscribe down below to stay up to date with all of my tech videos.
And follow me on Instagram.
I'm doing a lot of fun stuff on there.
And you should check it out.
Lots of good deals.
Until next time, see you later.
Have a good day.
Catch you next time.
Thanks for watching.