Hey, what's up? I'm Justin and welcome to Diabetic. Today we are getting into the
tandem Moby app for iOS. I have got it on my phone. I've been using the pump for about
almost two months now and I want to walk through kind of the entire app. What it can do and how you can
use it. This is the first time I've ever worn a tube pump and the interesting thing about this one is
there is no screen on it. It is completely controlled with the app although there is a button on it
that allows you to bowl this and I'll kind of get into that because you can set that up through the app
and I'll show you what I did with it. It's a really cool feature. If you're new here on the channel
I talk all things diabetes tech news and innovation. I have a podcast that comes out on Mondays
on YouTube and video or on podcast platforms if you just want to listen to it and I also have videos
come out on Fridays like this where I talk about my experience using technology and do reviews.
Today I'm walking you through the app how to bowl this with the home screen looks like the different modes
you give it in from activity to sleep mode and a bunch of other stuff. If you have questions I'm going to
be reviewing this. I also have a lot of other content coming out across socials and on here. So drop your
questions in the comments. Maybe someone else can answer and if they don't I will include that answer
in my review that will come out in a few weeks. Also be sure to check out diabetech.info over there.
I'm dropping the latest in diabetes tech and research news. We've got articles coming out every week. We've
also got all access where you'll get access to premium content including a brand new video all about travel.
Where I answer follow-up questions all about traveling with diabetes whether it be at the airport
keeping my insulin cool how I navigate different scenarios. It's got some great info and I'll
put a link in the show notes. All right let's get into it. All right let's start this bad boy up.
First I use the action button to open up this app it's super easy you just edit that in your settings
for your phone if you have that button. I also have a whole article about cool ways to use your iPhone
which I'll throw in the show notes. So yes it's open with the action button and here we are this is the
home screen. So let me kind of walk you through what is here. You've got in the top left the battery life
of the movie you have to recharge this pump on a charging pad. It's at 100% I just charged it on the right
side you've got how many units of insulin are left on board. So if I actually tap that it will take me down
and it will show me all of the information of like my insulin treatment at the moment. So my basil rate
currently is zero because I was going low just before filming of course my last bowl is
if control IQ is on which is like the automated insulin delivery system that algorithm
then the profile that's on and it even gives you like all of the details on what that profile is
etc. So that is on the home screen you've got your glucose level I'm 84 in steady thank goodness let's get
through this video and then the insulin on board 0.63 units. So yeah that is the the home screen
what I love there's this cool touch if you like scroll down to refresh there's like clouds it's cute they
did a good job here then you've got the main graph so as you can see there is a lot of information here.
First of all you're seeing these tear drops at the bottom or just drops I think they're insulin drops
not tear drops anyway these drops at the bottom represent two different types of
bowluses so the blue ones the light blue ones if I tap on the last one that is the last bowlis that I
gave the gave 17 grams bowlis and then they calculated 1.42 grams. I like that it also gives you
some other information that like tells you you know how much insulin was on board prior
bowlis and glucose so the cool thing is you can actually swipe through to like the last few
bowluses or just the last information so if I swipe to the left it shows me the glucose the glucose again
and then an automatic correction bowlis so you see all that's like a darker blue go back in here
that darker blue one wasn't auto correction bowlis and that's one of like the powerful features of
tandem's control IQ is that it will automatically bowlis you once every hour if needed
without you needing to like go in and do it yourself it is a nice way to you know have your diabetes
managed without having to really think about it so that is what the darker blue is again the light blue
is my or my bowlis says then you see how you have all of these numbers on the graph so for a while
I was trying to figure out like why are these so sporadic and happening at like the most random times
and I found out that those numbers come up when you open up the bowlis but menu so you see how I opened
up the bowlis menu and then look on the graph you will see a number up here right there you've got the
84 just appeared that was me I did that yeah I had no idea that was me doing that until someone told me
and then along the bottom you could see the the basil rate how it's fluctuating currently again at zero
because I'm going lower and you can kind of swipe through and see when it's getting you you know more of a basil
and then holding back and then your bowlis is so that's kind of all the information you're seeing on the
main screen and of course like that bracket is my target glucose range that I've set that app is always
going to try to get you to one 10 or like one 12 and then there are other features that will kind of maybe
raise that target for you which I'll get into so next up let's get into the bowlis menu so let's go into
bowlis and it's going to ask me if I want to reduce my bowlis calculation right now because I'm going low
so look you can see it is reducing my bowlis by 0.63 units at the moment and it's also saying that I
have insulin on board 0.5 so it's going to reduce that from whatever I put so let's say I put in like 50 grams
of carbs it's doing all of this math to and it shows you which is pretty cool it shows you what it's doing so
that is a correction ball is oh you can turn off correction ball is you know I don't do that because I want
to make sure that like the algorithms doing it's thing next you can do an extended bowlis now up to
eight hours which is so cool with control like you plus so not everyone has it's currently in the
U.S. you have it so here's where I can adjust the percentage of insulin I want immediately and then a
percentage of insulin that I want delivered over span of time so when I'm eating fatty your foods what
I do here is I give myself around 70 to 80 percent immediately and then 20 to 30 percent of the insulin
over time to take into account a slower intake into my glucose because it was a fatter your food
a fatter your high protein food so in this case I would go let's say you know 80 percent now 20 percent
later and then I would change the extension to four hours do I say up to eight hours earlier it's up to six hours
if I said up to eight hours I think it is up to eight hours actually I think that just sometimes it limits you
so anyway there you go that is up to four hours I'm not gonna bowlis now because I will go low on camera
and that wouldn't be a pretty sight so that was the bowlis screen now let's go to the actions menu so here
in the middle you've got action so on top you've got stop insulin this is where I can stop my insulin
and you see how when I tap that it's asking me to authenticate with my face with face ID so one thing I
like about this app is that unlike others you don't need to use face ID to open the app to quickly
view information but anytime you're adjusting something related to insulin treatment it will require face
ID it will only require face ID that one time while the apps open and you'll be able to you know do a
bunch of things I really like that feature because oftentimes you just want to open the app real quick to see
something on the home screen and you don't want to have to use your face ID and I hope that other
companies like omnipot introduce kind of that reversal of use with face ID on their app so then you've
got a few options here first you've got exercise so exercise is a feature you want to use when you are
going to be working out you want to put it on at least an hour before that workout and this will raise
your target to 140 to 160 milligrams per desoliter sorry I don't know the millimoles at the moment I'll put
them on screen you will it will also change up the algorithm a bit to be a little less aggressive to taking to
count that you're working out I also have to do something else if I'm doing heavy cardio which I'll get into
in just a moment but that's exercise then there's sleep mode in sleep mode what that does is it
narrows your target range to just 1 12.5 to 120 milligrams per desoliter so it's a tighter range
than it's bringing you to but it's only using basal insulin adjustments it turns off auto corrections
this is good for when you're sleeping when you don't need those auto corrections and it will just do
a good job of getting you down to your range and then keeping you flat over the night I've seen a lot of
flat nights thanks to sleep mode what I did was and you could see sleep schedules below it and which
you have to set I set my sleep schedules to start at 3 a.m. which some people may say like that's a little
late in the evening or morning the reason it works well for me is I tend to have meals late in the night
and I found that I wasn't getting the auto correction pulses I needed the strong auto correction
pulses that I needed to cover those meals so I decided to move my sleep mode to 3 a.m. that way
I have a little longer after those meals for the auto corrections to bring me down lower and then have sleep
mode activate so you could actually turn on you can create a couple schedules and then turn one off
turn one on the other so that's sleep schedules then you've got temporary which is 10 basil so prior to the
current algorithm you couldn't have this on during automated mode but now with control like you
plus you can that algorithms not out everywhere yet currently just in the US as of when I'm making this video
what this temp basil rate helps with is when you have different insulin needs for a certain period of time
this setting can be turned on for up to 72 hours which is for like if you're sick or you're having your
menstrual cycle and you need a different insulin treatment for that period of time so you can set
how much insulin you want so if you want you know 30% of your insulin needs which means you'll get a reduced
you know 70% or if you want you know over all the way up to 250% so you can get 150% more insulin
if needed for a certain period of time it gives you that ability then you can set the time so again
like I said it can go up to 72 hours specifically what I'm using this a lot for is working out I said it to
when I'm doing like a heavy cardio I said it to 30% and then I go in and I said it to
three hours which is basically one hour before I work out one hour during I work out and then one hour
after I work out what I do in combination to this and let's just see when I start it if it does anything on the
main screen it does have a little yellow tontop when you tap there it says temporary so let me also go and
turn that off what I do in addition to that for workouts that are cardio heavy as I turn on exercise mode again
in hour before my workout so in combination those two things have kept me in my range during workouts
and then lastly at the bottom you've got load cartridge this is when you want to switch out the
cartridge need to fill tubing fill your canula it gives you everything there it also gives you a site
reminder I didn't realize like it doesn't alert you if you have had your site in for over three days you
have to set a reminder so if you set a reminder you can say remind me and you know anywhere from one
to three days what time it is and then set that reminder I needed to set that because otherwise I was
forgetting like you know when did I load my cartridge and there is a way to find that which we'll get into in just a
second so that is the action step next notification tab luckily I don't have any notifications at the moment
but this is where notifications for if you have low insulin there's a CGM alert like you have a low or high
battery is low any notification you get will be here and your pump will continue to alert you until you
acknowledge that notification and swipe it and turn it off so that is the notifications tab and next we've
got the settings tab so here you have a bunch of different tabs to click on first we'll go into pump
here you've got on the first thing is personal profile so this is where you put all of your information for
your basil your bolus needs your insulin card ratio your insulin sensitivity factor all that jazz here in time
brackets and so as you can see I have a lot of time brackets I've been you know finagling a lot with this
system to to get it to work for me then you've got control IQ this is turning on automated insulin mode
you put your weight and your total daily insulin needs and you've got the quick bolus setting so like I said
earlier you can bolus from the device there is a button on it that allows you to dose insulin
if you don't have your phone on you which is great because I don't want to always have my phone on me when
I you know want to have a quick insulin dose and I'm you know in the pool whatever it is although
probably won't be wearing this in the pool because it's not supposed to like be submerged for too long
you can learn more about that in my review so stay tuned for that anyway the quick bolus button screen
so here you can choose whether you want it to be dosing you like in grams or units I use grams
because I card count when I you know treat myself for insulin other people think of it more of like in
in a unit's way I think of it in grams so you can set that in increments for grams from 2 5 10 to 15
I have 15 so 15 30 or 45 grams increments that's the most you can do is like three doses of this let's just
say it was units though just so you can see it you can do anywhere from 0.5 to 5 units per button
press which I get more into in my other tandem videos my like to switching to a two pump video and then
my review I'll also you know get deeper into that but yeah you can use the button right on the pump to
dose yourself insulin and it is really a lifesaver because you don't want to always you know
I have to go get your phone when you want to take insulin to that point I also wish that the
button allowed you to suspend insulin because what I do have to do is every time I wanted to attach my
pump and take a shower I have to go run for my phone to suspend insulin which was on that actions tab
that's not fun and I wish that there was a way to use that button to suspend insulin so
tandem please introduce that back to the settings though so then you've got delivery limits pump time and date
pump info and then software updates so there recently was a big update that's where I you know did
all that so let me go back to the main screen cgm so the main thing I wanted to talk about here is the fact
that what I love about moby and tandem pumps it seems is that you're able to switch out the cgm
within a session so I went from g7 the g6 to g7 while my pump was on and that was fine and that is all
done through this tab whereas on other systems specifically I know on omnipod you need to activate
a brand new pump when you switch sensors I really wish there was a way and I hope that they that insulin
builds away for omnipod to be able to do that in the middle because that's that was frustrating for me
it's not very often you're switching between you know types of sensors but it did happen in that case
and I wish that they would fix it but this video is not about omnipod anyway let's go back to alert
and sounds now so this is a pretty important thing to get right I think because one thing I've had with
moby that I didn't have with omnipod or DIY systems like use is I've had alert fatigue there are so
many alerts that you can get with this and more than I did with a tubeless pump because then there's like
the charging it and there's other alerts I can't think of right now but so here's where you can set them
so the first one is where you can set like a low insulin alert I have it set to 20 units
then you've got pump reminders so these are reminders you can have like for when you're having low or
highs you can set it to like remind you so let's say this low you can set it to remind me like after 15 minutes
remind me again the thing is I don't want to be reminded of my cgm alerts on my pump right I'm getting
up with my cgm so I have those turned off then you've got pump sounds here's where you can switch things
from vibrate to beep I've been finagling with this a little bit figuring out you know what do I want to
be what do I want to vibrate so yeah you've got all that information you can also have like a snooze on
as well then you've got cgm alerts which is you know having highlights and and low alerts here you've
gotten out an out of range alert which oh yeah that's been another alert that I get a lot to it
is like that my cgm's on range so just a lot of alerts let me know what you think of alerts by the way if
you're already using the system what's your alert experience like on mobile or any tandem pump or any
pump for that matter I want to hear from you let me know in the comments all right back to the main settings
then you've got app so the main thing in here that has been necessary for me to look at is history
so the history tabs where you can find out you know the history of what's been going on with your
pump specifically for me if I go to pump history which by the way pump history being in the app tab
always confuses me because I feel like it should be in the pump tab your pump history should be in the
pump tab and your cgm history should be in the cgm tab but you know perhaps there's a reason why you'd be
looking at both at the same time and maybe that's why they're in here together I don't know
anyway when they go to pump history what I'm looking at a lot is like the load when I've loaded a
cartridge so my last one was April 18th and I'm set to you know do one three days after that so
that is the history tab you can see like a bunch of things here your boluses over time like look at all
that which leads me to like another thing which is I wish instead of having to go to like pump history
which is great to have all that information I just wish on the dashboard that when you scroll back it didn't
stop at 24 hours we have the technology and the capabilities to scroll back at least seven days
of data like there are times when I'm on the phone my educator and I just want to look back like oh
what was Tuesday like and I think that I want this with all systems is more than one day of data and this
is like true for so many systems out there there's a very short amount of time you can look back
up on the graphs simpler a CGM from electronic did this really well you could like go back for for ages
which was great so if we can see that on here that would be that would be super nice so yeah that is the
tandem app I've got a lot more tandem content coming out I've got a site change video that's already out
where I you know walk through the entire site change process I've got a review coming for movie and I've
also got a bunch of videos on social with using tandem and omnipot and just I mean so many videos so
make sure to subscribe to this channel and if you want to get alerted to new videos click that bell
and give this video like so other people can find it I've got a podcast on Mondays these videos on Fridays
I hope you follow for more I'm Justin and I'll take you later