Hey guys, come on in. I want to show you iOS 13 CarPlay.
Oh, well hello people. Welcome to my old Fusion. Today I wanted to show you iOS 13 CarPlay
because it's really cool they added some new features and most importantly they added multi-tasking.
But before I show you that why don't you subscribe to this channel.
I'm a growing channel and I would love your support.
Anyway, iOS 13, let's do it. CarPlay, huh?
I just connected my phone and this is CarPlay right here.
So a few things that they did here, first thing is they changed the now playing button.
Should be more of like a play button.
Which I guess it makes it less like iTunes Z.
So we got that. Now when we go on now playing this is my Spotify account, which I really like the way they designed the Spotify
If you're a playlist browsing and you're library.
So right here, this is the tab that will take you to your apps.
But if you slide to the right, it will bring up the multi-tasking.
So right here, I'm able to see my maps and I'm able to see what's playing.
Right now, nothing. So let me play a song.
Let's play the five run playlist and I'm going to turn off the music right now.
But now, when I go here, you can see that Billy Isle is playing.
And then I have Apple Maps and a couple routes that it's asked me if I want to do it.
So unfortunately, you can't switch out this main map in the multi-tasking section for Google Maps.
It has to be Apple Maps at the moment.
I hope in the future that this is something that you can change because I am not a fan of Apple Maps.
Google Maps all the way.
Okay, so I really do love the multi-tasking here.
Let me put a destination in the map.
I'll put in my old work because it's not my home and you can't stop me.
And now that I have that, I can go back to the multi-tasking.
You can see my route right there and the music right there.
Also, when someone texts you, it's a little bit different.
So let me show you that actually what I'm going to do is I'm going to take the camera from you.
Brian, this is Brian.
Hi.
And text me.
Oh, shit.
I have your phone.
Okay.
Text.
So watch what happens when Brian texts me.
They moved where the text message comes, which I kind of like.
There it is.
So the text message comes there.
Also, one really great thing is when I press the Siri button on my car.
Siri no longer takes up the whole screen.
It is right in the bottom.
Which is really nice.
You can still see your directions.
Which was a super big flaw in the last version.
So yeah.
I'm pumped about that.
All right.
Let me give you this back.
When did my text message say?
Brian Hanson said.
Pock you.
Can you reply?
No.
Oh, we got something that I didn't say.
This is the best feature of all.
So let's say I have Google Maps open on my car play.
If my friend takes my phone now and they want to open up Spotify and change a song.
If you use to have it as soon as they open that app, it would change on the dashboard.
Now that doesn't happen anymore.
I will have Google Maps still on the screen while my friend opens up Spotify.
So you really only can change the apps on here from this screen.
That is the hands down number one best feature of a iOS 13 car play.
And I'm super pumped about it.
So you should be too.
That's all I've got on iOS 13 car play.
Really excited about it.
It comes out in September.
I do have more iOS 13 videos coming out.
So stay tuned for that.
Now you do that.
Subscribe to this channel.
Which do it.
Also, why don't you like it if you like it.
Like it if you like it.
It makes sense.
It's in the word.
Like is in the word.
Like.
So.
That's.
That's me being smart.
Anyway, I'm Justin.
I'll take you later.
But I think that's honestly.
Back to be it.