Hey everyone, it's Justin Tech, and today I've got something really exciting for Philips
You people.
It is the seanie conguera smart switch that is a friend of you switch, meaning this will
work with your entire Philips you set up, you can control lights, rooms, and zones with
this.
Same conguera sent over a few of these to me, I set them up, and I thought they were so cool
that I had to make this video, so now let me review them for you.
Let's do it.
We've got the switch right there, and this comes in a few different colors, this is the black
matte black version, you can tell when there's like finger prints on it, there's also
a white one in matte and glossy and a dark gray.
It's really nice build, I really like the way it looks and the way it feels, what it does
come with as well is a one switch, so it has these two switches, you can actually take these
off and then put this one switch on there.
It also comes with nice little sticky things that allow you to easily stick it onto a wall or anything
really.
Let me show you why this thing is so cool, and I'll show you that by opening up the app and finding
this one that I have already programmed, so it's right with Philips you out in settings, good
to access reset up, and that is where you will find my just-in-tech office switch, so if you
wanted to add one, you just add accessory, so right in here as you can see, you can control
the four different squares, what they do, so in this top, right, I have energized, which is
good for like in the morning when I want to be energized and get my work done, then the bottom
right is my daylight, or not my daylight, it's my bright, so it's a more warm color that's
for later in the evening, and then in the top left is this lighting, it's my just-in-tech
shoot lighting, so whenever I'm going to do a shoot, I click that button and this happens,
and then the bottom left, while I don't know where I'm in left, you just gotta do the trick, right,
this is set to relax, so at the end of the night, I'll click this one and that's relax.
Now on top of that, right, so I have all those different scenes on these light switches,
I can also do what a long press does, so but I have this long press to do on the top left
is I have increased brightness and then the bottom decreases brightness, so watch as I hold this
down, decreasing, hold it up, increasing, also listen to that click, it's a pretty loud click, it's
not like super annoying to me, it's engineered to have no battery, it's powering itself when
you're clicking it, it's regenerating power, and then let me show you how this works, so right here
I have the top right, do an energized, then in the bottom right is my soft right, then in the top left,
this is the just-in-tech shoot, so when I'm going to shoot a video, I just press that button and then all
of my Phillips Hue lights are ready for the shoot, and then bottom right, where bottom left is just
turning them all off, that light over there is just a life X light, that's why it's not going with
everything, don't tell Phillips. Let me go back to my shooting light,
and there you go, so that is how easy it is to just have scenes set on these, and instead of just rooms,
you could do it with zones which allow you to control multiple rooms or just lights, this thing gives you
so much capability, now if you want even more capabilities, you gotta download this app, it's called
I Connect Hue, it's 499, and you think you get all the features with that 499, and you don't,
they nickel and dime you for like every cool feature on here, but that's the thing, there are really
cool features on here for like music, and I want to do an entire episode on this app, I'm going to
definitely feature it in my Palm Springs SmartGames series, so stay tuned for that, but what related to
this, which really cool is if I go to devices, or no-not devices, if I go to lights, and that's not
correct, good automation, groups, no, I don't remember now, no settings, I absolutely forget where
this is located in the app, and I just was looking at it, why am I failing right now, okay, now I connect
you on here, if you go to settings, and you go to settings, and then you go to, no, oh my god, I just found
it, and then I lost it, got it, so on I connect you, when you go to devices on there, you've got a list,
so there's the just-and-tech office switch, now on top of all of that control, you can also on this app
control by pressing both of the lights switches bottom and the top together, right now I don't
have it assigned to anything, but that means you'll have another thing of control using the top and the bottom
together, so I will give that something at some point, I haven't yet, but that's something I'm going to do
now here's what I think, this thing is also works really well, looks really cool, I want a bunch of them,
they are expensive in the US, they're $69 for one or three for 189, which comes to about $63 each, and for
my European friends, they're available on Amazon UK for 59 pounds, I threw that in the description,
I highly recommend them, it was really easy to set up and super sleek design and really easy to use,
but expensive, other thing is these are coming from Germany, it's $299 for shipping to the US, and I'm sure it
will take slightly longer than ordering them from the US, the only other thing is there is some competition
out there, there is the run-less wire switch, which is $59, it essentially does the same thing,
and it's battery free, you just can't swap out the two switches for one switch, you can put it on
Amazon with the link in my description, I'm not as in love with that design, but I'm getting some
of those sent over for the Palm Springs Smart Home Series, I will tell you more about them in that,
so that's everything I have on the scenic and gear light switch, it'll be guys found this interesting
and helpful, if you want to see more smart home videos or you want to see my smart home series,
which is going to be freaking amazing, stay tuned for a trailer on that soon, make sure you
guys subscribe right down there and click the bell for alerts, and if you guys enjoyed this video,
give it a like, so more people can see it and maybe get one of these, all right, I'm just in,
and I'll take it later, left, and then that's very, that's off,
oh, I have it said, off, which is smart.