Hello, everyone, and welcome to this episode of Just In Tech.
Unfortunately, I do not have any technology for you today.
I also may not be wearing any pants, but I have a very exciting announcement.
I got my first.
Hey, comment. Yay, first. Hey, comment.
Bring it on. Bring it on.
I think many people would be upset by this, but I'm really excited.
Because if I got to hate comment, I think that means I'm doing something right.
And I just want to thank Mr. Art Wilbur so much.
I really appreciate it, because it just makes me feel so good.
Mr. Art Wilbur says, fix your f*** up mustache.
It's blinding.
It's literally all I could see in this video.
So Mr. Art Wilbur and the world, I have a confession to make.
I have a mole.
Done. Done.
Yes, it is true. I do not have a f*** up mustache.
I have a mole on my lip.
My mom and I like to call it Beauty Mark.
This isn't the first time I've gotten this comment before.
I've had people be like, oh, you're mustache.
And I'm like, oh, no, that's a mole.
I'm like, oh, okay, I'm so sorry.
This comment also brings up a lot of memories from elementary school.
The movie Gold Member came out.
This movie literally ruined my life.
Nice to meet you. Nice to meet you.
Don't say mo, I said mo.
Mo, le, mo, le, mo, le, mo, le, mo.
It ruined my 5th and 6th break experience.
Maybe 7th, too.
Mo, le, mo, le, mo, le, mo, le, mo, le, mo, le.
It's actually not funny at all.
I wanted to write a letter to the producers of Gold Member.
It was that bad.
Mr. Art Wilbur, Gold Member, the world, I am so proud of my mole.
It is who I am and I've come to embrace it for a long time.
I wanted to get rid of it.
But you know what, imperfection for me is beautiful.
I don't think anything about my mole is ugly.
I think it's special and I embrace it and so should you.
If you have any imperfection, it's who you are and it's what makes you special.
That is all I wanted to say today.
No technology, just me and my mole have a good one.