Hey guys, I am back at the void at the Santa Monica Promenade.
I'm here to play the Ralph Rakes VR experience.
But you know what, this is going to be way more fun with friends.
So why don't I get some?
Guys, that was your cue.
What?
Oh, sorry, doesn't it?
Let me, ready to redo?
Yes, so we're going to do that again.
We'll do it again.
But like I said, this VR experience is way better with friends.
So let's get some.
Whoa, oh my god, my friends are here.
All right, well, let's go, let's go, let's go, try this out.
Let's do it.
So last time I was here, I played Star Wars and Nicodemus
and was so impressed I had to come back.
The accuracy of the body and hand tracking
and how completely immersed I was had me gobsmacked
and a bit freaked out.
I was left wanting more.
And that's why I'm back to play Ralph Rakes VR
from the Walt Disney Company and ILM X-Lab.
I was told this game had a point system
and was better with friends.
So I brought my VR a literate friend, Jenna
and my most competitive friend Max.
What is your experience with VR?
Truly next to nothing.
I have used the Oculus.
I played some beat blaster.
It was awesome.
I nearly fell a little bit later.
Beat Saber, excuse me.
We're apparently all living in a simulation already.
So my whole life.
I'm truly a little afraid of VR,
but I'm excited for like a totally interactive gaming experience.
I'm going to be so bad at it.
How competitive are you?
I'm competitive.
I'm ready to win.
I'm ready to fight.
I'm ready to kill with me.
Like, I have to.
Love that.
First we were off to the briefing room
so we could prepare for our jump into the internet.
Then we got to choose our own characters.
What we would look like in the game.
Obviously I chose the one who makes the best dad jokes.
It was unbelievable.
After some quick stretching,
some squats and some ballet,
we were ready to plug in to the virtual world.
And we were in.
The first thing that caught our eyes was each other.
We all became our quirky cartoon characters
and needed a moment just to deal with it.
The game had a sneak onto the internet
with Reckitt Ralph and Benel B. Von Schwees.
We went from room to room, playing a bunch of fun minigames.
As we played, we could see the score in a risk.
The game had the same self-referential
and met at home as Ralph breaks the internet.
And that's what I loved about it.
The minigames were fun, quirky, and simple yet strategic.
At one point we were shooting pancakes and milkshakes at cats and bunnies.
And if we weren't immersed enough, we could even smell and feel the game.
My favorite part was when our group was split up for a game.
And it literally seemed like Max was taking a hundred feet away.
It was not a winner over here.
As soon as we were finished, I was ready to hop back in and get an even better score.
Oh, and Max won and we were all really proud of them.
It was our winner.
I wasn't jealous at all.
Besides winning, what did you love?
So, thank you so much for saying that again.
I went in there to think that I was going to be a bear.
I was going to be a bear.
It was a bear.
I wasn't jealous at all.
Besides winning, what did you love?
So thank you so much for saying that again.
I went in there to think that I was going to be a very competitive person.
I'm just like focusing on the games.
But I could not do that without walking to eat from the first thing.
Oh my god.
This is f***.
I've definitely went in this a bit of a skeptic.
Thinking that VR is dim.
It's not for me.
I'm like a little freaked out.
But genuinely, I want to bring my friends and my family to the void.
It was so cool.
An indescribable experience.
You just have to see it gently.
So there you have it.
Fun for the friends of family.
Back to your Justin.
Thank you Justin.
So I've got to say at this point that Ralph Frick's VR is my favorite at the void.
This game is the most strategic and has the most replayability.
The experience did feel a little short at just 15 minutes.
So I hope the void introduces longer games in the future.
I'd also love to see games that allow more than four players.
The void is one of the best VR experiences out there.
And you can check it out now in one of these cities.
The void's also coming to a bunch of other cities soon.
Are there other awesome places I need to check out?
Tell me about them in the comments below.
Also, let me know if you go to the void.
What you thought about it and what your score was in Ralph Brick's VR.
Oh, make sure you subscribe to this channel and click that bell button for notifications.
That was Ralph Brick's VR at the void.
A truly awesome VR experience.
Definitely check it out.
You know what?
Why do you enter my giveaway?
Where I'm giving away two sets of four gift cards.
So you can go with three of your friends.
Go over to my Instagram to get the rules for that.
As always, subscribe, comment, and like this video.
I'm Justin and I'll wreck you later.
Oh, nice.