Hey guys, it's Justin and I am at the B-VOID.
It's this amazing virtual reality experience that just opened four months ago.
Let's go check it out.
What sets the void different from all the other experiences?
Justin, what our goal is is to replicate what you are feeling right now in normal reality.
But just transport you into this just crazy world that you can never possibly visit.
Completely untethered.
We call it hyper-reality, right?
Because we think it's so much more than virtual reality alone.
So we have a lot of extra sensory effects.
You step out onto a balcony and you're going to feel wind in your face.
So a lot of that little extra stuff is what helps you to fully immerse in the experience.
First up, which Star Wars secrets of the Empire, which the void collaborated on with
the Lucasfilm and ILM X-Lab.
Next, it was time to suit up.
I put a computer on my back and a headset on my face, and that's it.
There were no hand controllers.
The void contract my hand movements all the way down to a thumbs up.
It was unbelievable.
The Star Wars experience had us going ship to ship, engaging stormtroopers and monsters, along
the way we found blasters and were attacked.
And when we got shot, we felt it.
We also went to a lava planet where we could literally feel the heat.
There was a moment where I was so stressed out, because stormtroopers were shooting at us and
our droid friend was being so sassy I just kept messing up.
That was nuts.
I felt like I was on that spaceship in that lava facing Darth Vader.
That was crazy.
I've never experienced VR like that before and I'm blown away.
On to the next one.
Let's go.
The second experience was Nicodemus, Demon of Inbanishment.
In this one, you're a time traveling detective going back in time to Chicago's World
Fair, where there's a demon on the loose.
It's basically a horror experience where you have to solve a bunch of puzzles and stay alive,
while getting freaked out along the way.
The cool thing about this one is that there's multiple endings based on how well you perform.
Needless to say, I failed miserably.
But now I'm determined to go back again and survive.
Holy crap.
I've been in haunted houses before, but I've never been in a virtual reality haunted house.
And I've got to say, that's the only way to do it.
Now for me, I'm never going in a haunted house with real people because you can't chop their heads up.
This one you can, I think mine was chopped off.
I need to get out of here.
I'm where the heck do I go?
In addition to these experiences, they also have wrecked Ralph VR, which I plan on checking out soon.
I can say with confidence that this is the future of entertainment.
Imagine one day going to a huge playing field and running around for an hour.
I have to say, I'm a bit speechless.
This was unlike any virtual reality I had ever experienced.
You gotta check it out.
You got it.
They are located in all of these cities right here.
It is unbelievable.
Come with friends, come alone, get scared, play around with Darth Vader, so many things to do here.
That is all I have for you guys on the void.
Follow me on Instagram, follow me on Facebook and subscribe to my channel for more VR and other
technology.
I'm Justin and I'll take you later.