Hey, it's Justin Tech at CES in Vegas right now.
I'm outside the Amazon booth, I'm about to head in there because they have a bunch of products
on display showing off how Alexa has basically integrated everywhere now.
Let's go check it out.
2020 will be the year that your Rumi Alexa finally starts pulling their weight.
Alexa will help with cooking, cleaning, and even navigating from the passenger seat while
you run errands.
And now Alexa will be sharing your bed.
Let's go where the magic happens.
So right here we have a bed powered by Alexa.
What does that mean?
The Docs bed is a family owned Swedish company, 93 years old, some of the best beds in the
world.
So what we've done is we actually put an Alexa unit built into the mattress itself.
So it sits under the bed and uses the frame to work with the psychoacoustics of the
sound as in the room.
Safety features such as glass, breakage, baby crying, CO2 warnings, it's just the beginning
what you can do.
You're now sleeping with Alexa, don't tell your partner.
Okay, now I'm hungry, let's head to the kitchen.
Hey, welcome to the kitchen.
Check out this June oven right here.
The June smart oven has a comprehensive touch screen.
This enables you to scroll through the device's various options.
This range from standard oven functions to cooking recommendations on products that you may
have purchased at Whole Foods, which is owned by you guessed it, Amazon.
Love that for me.
Top.
Well, I made a mess.
Let's fix that.
Right over here, we have a really cool vacuum at the iRobot Roomba.
This one's even cooler because what it will do is, after it's a vacuum, it will come here
and dock and empty itself into this compartment right here.
It's full.
Just take this thing out, throw it out and put it in the new one.
There you go.
Hold on.
Did I just use my last vacuum bag?
Time to restock.
So what we have right here is the dash of smart shelves.
So what's really cool about this is that you put your products on these shelves and you scan
what the skew is and then the shelf knows what product it is and when it gets low, it's connected
to your Amazon account and it will order the product to restock.
So right here we have some printer paper and I guess low, it will order you some new printer
paper.
Alexa is also coming to a place they've never been before, your garage.
Amazon just announced a partnership with General Motors to bring Alexa to your car.
So we have Alexa who I shouldn't say that's allowed in the car so can you tell me what you have
going on today?
This is an integration with General Motors that will be launched in the first half of 2020 and we
are really focused on what helps drivers the most.
So I'll give you a quick demo here, we're tied into the vehicle with the push to talk
but it can be reassigned to Alexa and say Alexa find coffee shops in Las Vegas.
Alexa call the fourth one, so you're able to tap into all of your normal Alexa interactions.
My controller lights, I can read my oven, I can open my garage door all from using voice
in my car.
So it seems Alexa is taking over in all aspects of life and I'm okay with it.
Why don't you guys subscribe right down here for more CES content coming your way this week.
Give it a like if you enjoyed it, I'm Justin, Alexa, turn off this video.