Hey everyone it's Justin and today is a big day because I have my Oculus Quest or it's in here at least it's it's in this Amazon box and I'm going to unbox it
I'm so excited
here it is it is the Oculus Quest so the Oculus Quest comes in two versions the 64GB and the
128GB I had to go with the 128GB because I didn't want to worry about space this one was
499 as opposed to the 399 for the 64GB all right so let's unbox this thing let's unbox
this thing okay I swear I'm gonna do it I'm gonna do it my favorite technique for unboxing
things is to use your fingernail just back and forth so I'm gonna go in there and I'm just gonna go
back and forth right that like that ah it actually didn't hurt I don't think oh my god
be gone all right one more time that is the Oculus Quest right there I got the Oculus Quest it's
right in my hand a Quest is to open it before I even open up this thing definitely subscribe to my
channel because I'm gonna have a ton of Oculus Quest content coming soon so to say up to date with that
subscribe slide this thing open set this side cute box got a nice little Oculus on it
this is beautiful look at how nicely laid they laid that in there also it's like super materialy I didn't know
I guess in the picture they saw that but it's like super like fabricy and that's the Oculus Quest
headset right there got the eye divider thing there got volume right here there are the cameras
with so cool about the Oculus Quest this is the first VR headset that can take into account your
surroundings without being connected to a PC basically I'll put this on and it will be able to see my
surroundings and be able to have depth perception to now we have the trollers I really like these
wow this feels really nice look at that right hand one thank you left hand one I didn't even have to
read that to know it just feels right I don't love this smell of it if I'm being honest but I love the
it's got a box oh it's laid in there so nicely thank you Oculus I love this for me I love this for us
I love this for Oculus get it get it we got this for glasses this divider if you were glasses and then we've got
the charger and it is USB-C oh my goodness I'm a fan of this this is a very long charging cable the
Oculus go did not have a long one like this and maybe that's because they kind of want you to be able to
play still and charge I don't know if they want you doing that probably not but you can and I did it with my
Oculus go kind of got a little warm though oh we got two double A batteries I love that and some a little
pin blip and that instructions things they don't read yeah so it says before you start
install the Oculus app I already have it so I'm going to hop into this thing I'm so pumped I'm going to
get it set up place and things please let me know what experiences or games I have to play with this thing
because I don't know which ones I should check out first let me know in the comments below stay tuned for
more content subscribe to me on YouTube if you want to be up to date on all that stuff follow me on
Instagram cousin fun and uh other than that maybe I'll see you in the VR world
Wow it's off I didn't see anything