I have to level with you.
The Samsung booth at CES was massive.
It came in around 50,000 square feet, so this video won't be covering everything.
Instead, let's keep on track with the future of smart homes from Samsung, which they have
redubbed intelligent homes.
Here I have Jason with Samsung.
What do we have back here?
What's up guys?
Right behind me, we're taking a look at Samsung's new lifestyle TV called the Sero.
Now we have the ability to connect a mobile device to our TV, and if we're watching a video
that may be better viewed in a landscape mode versus a portrait mode, I have the ability
to rotate my phone and then have my TV rotate along with it.
This is expected to launch later in 2020, and do you have any on display that we could
try out maybe?
We do.
We have a really cool display right behind me right here, and then behind that we've got
a couple more individual modular stations that we can go check out.
With the Sero, your friends will no longer be able to shame you for not filming an portrait mode.
At present, the automatic rotate function is only compatible with Galaxy devices.
Apple and others will need the Sero app to control the TV.
But think of the TikTok potential.
Oh, are you on TikTok?
Same.
It's just an underscored tech underscored talk, obviously.
That's flipping awesome.
Right back here, we have Rubin and Batschev giving off an awesome presentation, but this is all
conceptual, right?
This is conceptual, the Batschev is an AI-based kitchen assistant.
It can help you do everything from understanding what you're asking it or what you would like
to make, and it can access the database of what you have in the house in terms of inventory
of food.
They can do simple physical actions like setting the stove up and getting a pan out of
a drawer, and then it can help you prep what it is you want to make, whether it's cutting up
your produce or prepping the meats that you want to cook, like they say, everybody can use
extra set of hands in the kitchen, and that's what Batschev has.
Personally, I don't need that much help in the kitchen.
Here that voice, she cooks, but I could always use more intelligence.
Can you tell me a little bit about what an intelligent home is?
Yeah, so Samsung, we've been talking about the multi-device experience for quite some time.
It's a device that can act over a network, and they have the ability to communicate with
one another.
There are 150 different partners, Samsung is working with unsmarting certified devices.
This could be your Samsung TV and mobile device to certain manufacturers, thermostats, or door locks,
windowshades, everything else that could be in the house that could connect to one another, and
you can control from a simple device like your cell phone, or even your Samsung ULED TV.
Now for one of the coolest announcements from Samsung, Bolly, can you tell me about Bolly?
We're just going to get more intelligent than with robot personal assistance, and robots
that are able to help make your lifestyle, or your health a little bit better.
Bolly is a little ball that has the ability to move around with you or in a particular space, and
it gives you feedback as to what's going on in the room or take commands from you.
It could be literally your personal assistant.
If you walk past an area where maybe your dog or your kids made a little bit of a mess on the floor,
you can call Bolly to come over and assess the situation, and then Bolly has the ability
to command other smart connected devices in your home, like maybe your Samsung robot back, and
it can say, oh, this is a simple dirt mess, robot back, and clean it up, and Bolly can do the work
for you.
One is called Bot Air, which is a robotic air purifier.
Has the ability to move around, route a home, or a living space, and start filtering the air
until it deems it to be more breathable, or to a healthier spec.
And so are these also concepts, both of them?
These are both concepts, yes, whether or not we'll see them in 2020 is yet to be determined,
but I sure hope so, because they're pretty awesome.
Are you impressed?
Same time.
For more CES coverage, make sure you subscribe to this channel right down there, give it a like if you enjoyed
it.
I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.
Can I help you enjoy it?
No?
Same song.
You're not addressing the song.
Okay.
Same song.