Hey, I'm Justin Tech and today I'm going to show you how to set up Wi-Fi calling on your phone.
The great thing about Wi-Fi calling is you don't have to worry about that self-remorception,
basically anywhere where you have Wi-Fi. It goes right through yourself and provider,
but you're still going through Wi-Fi and you have clear phone calls. It's amazing.
So, what you do is you go to your settings from there you're going to go to phone.
And there you're going to go to Wi-Fi calling. You're going to switch that on.
Then it's going to ask you if you want to enable it and yes, you do.
And then it may ask you to update your emergency address.
And the reason it's doing this is because if you're on Wi-Fi, the emergency services,
911, kick, track you unless you give them this address.
So, this is great. If you're at home, bad news here is if you're at work on Wi-Fi,
it can call and there's some craziness happening and you need to call 911.
Well, they're going to think and you don't get through them or talk to them.
They're going to think you're at home. So that's the downside of this.
Upside is you're going to have really clear phone calls. It's really great.
But that's pretty much it. You're going to put in your address right there, up to your address.
And then you have Wi-Fi calling and you're going to have some really clear phone calls.
So that's all I've got for you on this.
Definitely subscribe below for more future videos and follow me on Instagram.
Lots going on over there.
Until next time, I'll see you later.