Hey guys, so Philips, you just announced a ton of new products and I got to get a first look and I was really surprised. Let's check them out.
Philips, you invited me over to check out a bunch of new products coming out this fall and I've got to say it was lit.
Let's start with my favorite new bulbs, the filament light bulbs. They are beautiful and look great in lighting fixtures with an exposed bulb.
All three will be available in October. Besides light bulbs, Philips use also coming out with some other smartphone gadgets.
So here's one of them. It is the Philips Hue button.
There it goes. It has a magnet. It gets magnetized right there and then it stays. I was not ready for that.
The button may look simple but it can do a lot. With one press, you can control your lights however you like.
Or you can press and hold to brighten or dim the lights.
When connected to a bridge, you can also configure the button so that it turns your lights to a preset shade of white light and brightness.
That suits that time of day.
I'm really excited that Philips is decided to come out with their own smartphone.
We've been wanting this for a while. I just a simple button like this and we got it. It comes with a piece of 3M tape that you can then put on it and then you can stick this thing anywhere under a table.
Anywhere other than that.
The button will be available in October.
Another one I'm super excited about is the Philips Hue Go.
So the original came out in 2015 and now it is even better because for a few reasons they brought the Bluetooth technology to it.
So it literally is a Hue Go. You can go anywhere with it. I only go camping with it.
It will connect to your Hue Bridget home but also you take it anywhere you want and you have that Philips Hue Bluetooth out and you can control it from there.
It's got a great button on the bottom that you can program and put it to a bunch of different settings.
This thing can last anywhere up to 18 hours depending on its use. Pretty awesome.
The Hue Go will be out for all of your camping needs in November.
Last but not least we have the Philips Hue Smart Club.
Finally Philips Hue has come out with their own Smart Club.
That way you can keep all of your lights even those ones that aren't Philips Hue bulbs in the ecosystem.
So you can connect any lamp with this thing and it will be in that Philips Hue home.
Super excited about that.
Along with these, Philips has also announced the each 12 candle bulbs and the GU10 Spotlights.
These are available this month.
The best part is that all of these products besides the button have Bluetooth.
Meaning you won't need a bridge to start out but don't fret the button will work without a bridge using Zigbee.
I'll be testing out and reviewing these products soon.
So if you're sure to hit that subscribe button and press the bell for alerts.
Also if you liked this video why don't you give me a thumbs up and let me know in the comments which products you are most excited about.
Philips Hue they're coming out with the ton of new products all the time.
They really care and I love that.
I also care about you guys and that's why I'm doing a cute little giveaway of the Philips Hue Go.
If you want one, head over to my Instagram and check out the giveaway.
I'm Justin and I'll take you later.
Justin and I'll take you later.
I'll be able to check on that out.
Thanks for watching.