Hey guys, welcome to my channel, this is a very special episode because I am announcing that
I have partnered up with Magic Leap to create a series of six videos I am elated to be working
with such an awesome company that has the Magic Leap 1 Creator Edition. This is the headset
or Lightware's Magic Leap calls it. And this is the light pack, the computer powering the device.
It is a spatial computing device that takes in your entire surroundings, tracks your hands,
your eye movement, where your eyes are focused. Today's episodes all about their brand new Spotify
app on this. Spotify is bringing music streaming to spatial computing. This is a first for Spotify,
and then this is also a first for Magic Leap having an app that can play music with their
background music service. So without further ado, let's take a hop, skip, and a Magic Leap
into this video.
So I got my main menu right here, and as you can see it's just levitating in my living room,
and I'm going to open up the Spotify app. So the first thing Spotify is going to have me do is
place it somewhere in my room. It wants to be on a surface on the ground. Once the app is placed, Spotify
comes alive in a life-size layout, right in your living space. On top you have your recently played songs,
playlists, and artists. In the middle is a cube-like Spotify player, and that the bottom are
stacks of recommendations. The app is intuitive and the controls are natural. At the bottom you can hold
the trigger and move the controller side to side to search through the stacks, kind of like looking at
records at a record store. The app allows users to curate and decorate their augmented reality with their
favorite playlists, songs, and artists. I'm using a Magic Leap account for copyright issues,
so this isn't the music I listen to. I'm going to take my editing jams, right? I'm going to hold
the trigger, and I'm going to put it right by my computer. There it is right there. On the wall by my
editing station, and then it gives me the options to delete it, or I can play it. So let's play it.
And there it is. The music is playing right from the speakers right here.
And then if I want to pause it, there we go. Pause it. And there it is in the main player.
Okay, so I'm going to decorate my apartment a little more with my recently played. I got a dinner party
playlist right here. I'm going to put that right on this wall. As I placed the playlist around my apartment,
I felt like I was in a Spotify playground. Watching the artwork navigate my walls as I moved
them around was a true testament to how precise the room tracking is on the headset.
The music art also acts as your own art pieces. I could see myself creating some abstract collages.
By default, the playlist are these four square images, but if you go on to Spotify through the
computer, you can change them to any image you want. Love that for me. So now that I've decorated my
living room in my kitchen, I'm going to take this to the bedroom. I was impressed by how smooth and seamless
it was to move this Spotify player to another room. Next, I placed some artists above my bed,
so I could have some smooth jams to serenade me before bed. Artist tiles resemble vinyl records,
so you can save that trip to the record store and throw up some Spotify art. The cube-like
player is aesthetically pleasing as it rotates between songs. I never imagined I'd be Spotify running in
such a tangible way. So if you want a little more control over Spotify, you can use your phone to
control it. Right now I have the app open. You see right there, it's connected to the magically
over Bluetooth. Now that it's connected, I'm going to press play. And look, I've played my song.
In landscape mode, you can access the overtrapped, which allows you to control Spotify using the
background music service. The music will pause once you open up an immersive app.
Once you leave the immersive app, the music will start up again.
All right, so now I want to show you how you can have different apps open in landscape mode
and still have the music playing. Right here I have my overtrapped, I opened up a bunch of windows. I had my
YouTube video playing, Google open, and a gallery piece on the counter. The music would sometimes
be spotty and that's probably because I was working it really hard. I'm sure this will get better with
time. So this is really exciting. The fact that we now have the ability to have apps playing music
and then we can have them run in the background with overtrapped and the background music service.
And this spotify app really is just the beginning of what this technology's going to be. I mean, think
about it. You can put your podcast that you listen to every morning you cook breakfast, sitting in
staying in your kitchen and just click it and then it starts playing as you're cooking. If there's an
audio book you're reading, it could be in your bedroom on the wall when you're going to go to bed,
you click it and then it starts reading your book. Maybe even a corner of your home that you like to
meditate in can have some really nice ambient sounds. I mean, the potential is incredible and I can
not wait to see where this technology goes. Stay tuned for a bunch of videos coming out on magic leap.
I cannot wait to explore this innovative headset more and I have so much in store, just you wait.
So make sure you subscribe right down there, hit the bell for alerts for more. And also if you guys
found this video helpful, you should like it because that will help other people find it. I'm just in,
and I'll take you later.
Okay. Enough fun. Back to work, Justin.