Hey Facebook, it's Justin. Good to see you again. So this thought came to me. Of course, it was on the dance floor where I get most of my good ideas.
I thought to myself, social media is preventing us from having conversations with ourselves.
And this is very true to me. I found myself waking up every morning, rolling over and the first thing I would do was go on Facebook.
And then I'd scroll and scroll and scroll and scroll. And I didn't really find myself gaining anything of importance.
I just found myself going on the app at a board on. And instead of using that valuable free time that I had to honestly sit and solace and think to myself or go sit down and edit a video, I just spent it on social media, which wasn't very productive.
My timeline is full of like really sad news. And I'd kind of just see like everyone's opinion on things kind of like this video.
So I deleted the Facebook app four months ago. I didn't delete Facebook in general just the app and I do not miss it at all.
I'm not saying that social media is the devil and you need to get rid of all of it. I'm just saying that for me, it's really had a great effect on my productivity by deleting that Facebook app.
I think at the end of the day that spending a little less time on social media in general is a very very good decision for all of us.
I think spending more time with ourselves and also spending more time on that project that you've been postponing or hanging out with friends in real life.
I think that's always a little more fun than scrolling and scrolling and scrolling and scrolling and scrolling and scrolling.
If you kind of want to get a visual for how much time you are spending on these apps, if you have an iPhone, you can use this thing called screen time in the settings.
Just go to settings, scroll down and go to the search at top, put in screen time and then go to that and then you can take a look at all the time you're spending on all of your apps and see from a day or a week perspective.
You could also set limits on apps as well.
Personally, I find that just deleting the app going cold turkey is the way to go.
I've worked for smoking cigarettes too.
Weaning off cigarettes didn't work for me.
I had to cut them out.
Yes, I smoked cigarettes for like five years and it was gross.
But I've stopped smoking for eight years now and I've never felt better.
Don't smoke kids, which apps are sucking your time out of the day.
Do you want to get rid of them or no?
I definitely challenge you guys to try this out too if that's something that you're interested in.
I'm not going to push this on you but I'm just telling you kind of how it affected me.
And I'm really, really happy about it.
I find it fascinating the amount of time we spend on social media.
How we use it and also how different generations use it.
So I think it's interesting and I'd love to hear your feedback.
I kind of have an idea of like interviewing a bunch of people about their habits.
If you think that's a good idea for a video, let me know.
I think it could be fun.
So I hope you didn't scroll past this video.
I hope you watched it.
If you liked this video, give it a thumbs up.
If you care even remotely about what I say, then you should subscribe.
And I think that this is a really good thing for people to keep in mind.
It's like spend a little less time on social media and a little more time with yourself.
I don't know. Could be fun.
I have some really cool videos coming out soon.
I have a review of the Facebook portal coming out.
So yeah, I deleted the Facebook app, but I introduced the Facebook portal into my home and I love it.
So stay tuned for that. That's coming out soon.
Other than that, I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.
Anyway, it's all I have for now.
I just kind of wanted to...
Ooh, there's something like that.
I kind of just...
Anyway, it's all I have.
Oh, it's still my eye.
Oh.
Do I look like I was crying?
I wasn't.