Hey everyone, just in tech here, are you finding that your computer is basically shutting down
when it's in sleep mode? Well, you are not alone and you are not crazy. You're probably
getting this error message and you're not sure what's wrong, whether it's an installed app or
it's a hard drive or your computer's freaking out and you're calling Apple. Anyway, this is
a flaw in the software right now. Apple is aware of it and there is a workaround. So this
video is gonna show you how to fix that. So here it goes. Again, this is a temporary
issue until Apple fixes it. I will let you know as soon as Apple fixes that in a pinned
comment below. So if there's a pinned comment saying it's done, then you could just update
your software. So here it is. First, you want to go to System Preferences, then go to Energy
Saber. Energy Saber basically dictates when your computer screen goes to sleep. So right
now I have it on about an hour and a half. You're gonna need to put that to never. It does
say never letting your display go to sleep, make sure it's light, which is true. But temporarily,
this will be just fine. And again, Apple is going to fix this eventually. This is just a temporary
fix. So how many times can I say a temporary in this video? Anyway, one way to balance this out
is to go back into your settings and then go to Desktop and Screen Saber. And then just make sure you
have a screen table on. I have my screen table come on every 20 minutes of inactivity. And I have
this fun one that's like my super favorite. It's really pretty. Okay. Really pretty. Anyway, that will
help kind of just save your lifespan of your computer screen. There you have it. That is the fix. Again,
it is temporary. But there is going to be hopefully a fix soon from Apple and I will let you know as soon
as that comes out. Anyway, I hope this video helped you out. And if it did, why don't you give me
a big old like? That way, other people can find it and solve it for themselves. I have got lots
more videos coming your way. See those, want you guys subscribe right down there. Click that bell for
alerts. I'm Justin and I'll take you later.