Hey guys, welcome back to my channel. I'm so excited to show off this brand new product.
It is the Phillips U smart plug. What's so great about this smart plug is that it actually has
Bluetooth. So you don't need a smart bridge in order to use this thing. You really could just have this
and use your phone with the Bluetooth Phillips U app, which is a separate app from the Phillips U app.
So again, you do not need a bridge, but if you have one, that's great. I've been wanting a
smart plug for a long time from Phillips U so that I can mix it into my Phillips U ecosystem that I already
have with my lights. It just makes it easier now to control all of my lighting, including the
lights that can't take bulbs. For example, how am I going to use this with that smiley face back there,
that neon sign. Funny story. I actually got that sign when I went to the museum of neon art with a
bunch of my friends. We were so excited if we drove an hour we get there and the museum was closed. So
we walked around the gift shop for two hours and I was so severely under the influence of art that I bought
that for $400. Did I regret it? Maybe a teeny bit, but you know what? Now I don't because that's my
face truly represents who I am. I'm pretty happy guy. What can I say? Anyway, back to the smart plug,
right? Let's do this. Now it's plugged in and how do we get it to work? Well, I've got an app for you. Yes,
the Phillips U app. Let's open it up. I'm going to open up the Phillips U Bluetooth app. There it is right there.
And I'm going to set things lights and I'm going to click that plus sign, right? So it's now searching
for lights. There we go. So it says Hugh Lamp. No, that's not the one I want. How to connect your lights. No,
I don't want the Hugh Lamp. Okay, smart plug. Remove the smart plug from the wall socket. Then plug it back in.
Make sure you are within three feet of the smart plug. Okay. Well, this isn't working out as planned.
There it is. Hugh plug, got it. See, you just got to adapt in this business, adapt in it,
and it works out easily. Okay, Hugh plug. So you're going to click that and I'm going to call it
smile because it's what it is. And I believe that's it. Let's see how this works. So I'm going to go to my
lights and cross my fingers. I'm going to click smile. It works. Yeah, smile.
So now if I wanted to, I could connect this also, which I will to my Phillips U ecosystem on the Phillips
U app. But I just wanted to show that to you guys so that you know that the Bluetooth one works really well.
You can also go a step further if you have a Google Nest or an Alexa. You can use those to control
these lights and plugs as well. So definitely do that if you have those. I know I will. So that's all I have for the
Phillips U smart plug. I'm really excited about it. Thank you Phillips for creating it for us. Also,
really exciting is that Phillips U and I have actually teamed up so we're going to be doing a giveaway for one of these.
So to find out the rules for that, go ahead over to my Instagram. And you know what, I have a lot of
filled two videos coming out. So you should subscribe to this channel and click that bell for alerts.
Anyway, that's all I've got for you guys today. I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.
Hmm. It's so good. Nice, so good.