Hey, it's Justin Tech, and I'm at the Panasonic Gooth at CES, where I got to get a
sleep peak into the future with their VR glasses.
One of the most unexpected announcements at CES 2020 was Panasonic's VR glasses.
Panasonic has developed the world's first high dynamic range capable, ultra HD virtual reality
glasses.
That's right, eyeglasses.
These bad boys are smaller than any VR headset I've ever worn.
Not only are they incredibly small, but they've got a cool steam punk design.
The devices equipped with a micro OLED panel and earbuds capable of rich and dynamic
sound.
The glasses weren't on display at the booth, but I somehow managed to go behind the scenes
and try them out.
Look at me, I was overcome with joy and dancing all the way there.
Right now, I'm about to try out the Panasonic VR glasses, not many people have had their hands
on these and lucky enough to try them out, so here it goes.
The pair I tried were a prototype.
They looked the same as these, but they were tethered to a computer and a little front heavy.
The micro OLED panels were smaller than I expected, and displayed a square image with a much smaller
field of view at 70 degrees.
Panasonic says they can eventually get this to 100 degrees with larger panels.
I tried a couple experiences.
First was a video trailer, and the video was incredibly crisp.
Next I took a tour of a Japanese temple.
As I slowly moved around the temple and looked around, I was encapsulated by the most vivid
colors and taken it back as light beautifully reflected off the golden environment.
Trying out these glasses was a peek into the future.
Panasonic isn't likely to sell these anytime soon, but they design them in anticipation
for the 5G network.
They say the glasses will offer anything from VR sports viewing to virtual travel experiences.
When it comes to size, these glasses have me so excited for the future of VR, AR, and special computing
headsets.
Hopefully headsets like the Oculus Quest and magically will get smaller over time.
If you want to see more of my VR videos, I threw some links in the description, and for
more VR, AR, and special computing, be sure to hit that subscribe button below, and click
the bell for alerts.
Oh, and if you enjoyed the video, why don't you give me a like?
I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.