Hey everyone, welcome to my channel, I'm Justin Tech, and today I want to tell you
all about the best cross-platform multiplayer games available on Oculus Quest.
I have been playing my Oculus Quest a ton lately, and I want to let you know the best
games and also the easiest games to meet up with your friends who have all the different
systems, whether it be Oculus Rink S, HTC Vive, PSVR, etc., with your Oculus Quest.
So, here it goes.
The first game, it's definitely my favorite, it's Star Trek Bridge crew. This game is amazing,
so basically what it is is you and up to three other people are on the bridge of a spaceship.
There are lots of missions to set off on, somewhere you're fighting other ships,
fighting and transporting people onto your ship, exploring galaxies, and retrieving data.
There's lots of replayability here.
And you all have different jobs, whether you're the helm, driving the ship,
or tactical, you're scanning other ships around for life-signs, or enemy ships to take down their
weapons and shields and shooting phasers and torpedoes, or you can be engineering where you're
repairing the ship or allocating a certain amount of power to each area of the ship.
And lastly, one of the most important jobs is the captain. So, as captain, you're basically
looking at all the missions, looking at the maps, and delegating different tasks to everyone,
having everyone work together. When playing online, you'll meet other players in a briefing room,
where you can choose your positions and levels. Sometimes, my friends and I just hang out in there
for a while waiting for friends to log on. And the game stays very true to the Star Trek universe.
I'm a big next-generation fan, and everything just makes more sense to me, like warping and
impulsing, and engines going down, and the warp core being in critical condition, like everything just
really makes more sense now that I'm living it. So, you guys have to play this game. It is the best
game available on Oculus Quest right now for multiplayer. And you can also play single player. Also,
one annoying thing with honestly most of the social apps on Quest is you have to create an account
externally through the Ubisoft club account. So, you'll need to make an account there, add your friends,
and then you'll have the friends in the game. Also, if you're in an Oculus party on the system,
you have to make sure you exit that before you enter the game and then create a room because you're
Mike won't work. So, just make sure that you're logged out of any parties before you do that,
and then you can invite your friends in. Bridge Cruise, 29, 99 on the Oculus Quest, and free on the
Rift. Next game is Recroom. And I've got a lot to say about this one, because there's so much you can do on here.
Oh, and it's free. It's kind of like an online chat room where you can create your avatar,
and meet up with friends in different rooms. So, you can play Disc Golf, which I highly recommend you try out.
There's also Paintballing, and then there's Laser Tag. I was playing a bunch of Laser Tag last night,
and it was so much fun. It was basically four of us four. You were two different colors,
and then in the Laser Tag Arena, there were also these robots that were on your side,
and then you could shoot the other robots and get points, and whoever got to 400 points first wins.
There's a bunch of different guns and grenades you can pick up, and a power weapon that spawns
like every three minutes. You're seriously not going to want to stop playing. And then Disc Golf was also
really cool. So, it's like Frisbee mini golf, and basically you're throwing these Frisbee's to get the
hole. It's such a great time. I've had friends from the Oculus Rift. Ask and the Quest come in,
and just hang out in there. So you definitely have to check out Recroom. There's way more than what I just
said. There's a lot of different activities. There's bowling, charades, murder mystery parties,
and it's super easy to invite all of your friends to play in a private room. And there's still
feels like every day there's something to explore. Oh, and the best part, people can join you in Recroom
using their smartphones, just have them download the Recroom app, and add you as a friend. Then you
can play with them anywhere you want. Next up is my favorite, Akron Attack of the Squirrels. This one's
a little different than the others, but I think it's the coolest. And that's because it's both a local
and online multiplayer game. In this game, one person is wearing a VR headset while others play against
them from their smartphones, so it's great for game nights, or even on video chats like Zoom and
FaceTime. The person wearing the headset is a big tree guarding four golden acorns. The other two
to eight players on their phones are squirrels running around trying to steal them. The tree can throw
projectiles at them, and pick up the squirrels and throw them. I think any time you include others who
don't have VR headsets to join in on the fun is an amazing idea, and this game executed incredibly well.
And we'll have you and your friends yelling, laughing, and screaming. The more players there are,
the crazier it gets. And what's great is the app on the phone is free, so the only person who
has to buy it is the person with the headset. The good news there is that the game is currently on sale
for 1499 on Oculus and Steam. And the next one is Alt Space VR. So this is kind of similar to
recroom in a sense where it's kind of like online chat rooms. It's less about games and it's more about
socializing. And it's also free to play. So the way it works is you have kind of like your own
apartment, but you can go to different venues. So last night I actually went to an open mic night
with like 40 other people, and everyone was muted. That way no one could like boo or be mean to like
who was on stage. It was a very interesting experience. I went with my friend Connor. We met up at the
venue, and we just listened to these people on stage. There were people doing comedy. There were people
doing karaoke. They weren't amazing. It was interesting. It was cool. I definitely highly recommend
checking that app out. And also what I'm going to do is I'm planning a VR happy hour social. So basically
I'm going to invite all of my VR friends. I think I have like six or seven people who have VR headsets
that are like close to me. And we're all going to meet up in my apartment and all space VR and just
have a drink in our hand and hang out, walk around, socialize, and kind of feel like we're at a party.
We'll see how that goes and I will let you know absolutely. I've really pumped for that.
Next is Swords of Gargantua, a sword fighting game. You can play the single player campaign,
or join up to three others in online co-op and fight waves of enemies. I highly recommend the latter.
There was recently an update bringing a brand new adventure mode. This has definitely enhanced the game,
so if you've played it before, I recommend you try it out again. You can improve your abilities and
strengthen your weapons over time, and it's good to know updates are being worked on. The graphics are
an amazing on the quest, but it's great to meet up with friends in this hack and slash game.
The game is available on Steam and Oculus for 1999. Next is Orbis VR Reborn. This is the only
MMORPG available in VR, and while the graphics seem pretty simplistic, the game is actually pretty sophisticated.
Think of it as the first ever World of Warcraft of VR, but it's not as well fleshed out.
You're going to be a little on your own here. There isn't a lot of explaining and there isn't really a
good tutorial. In Orbis VR Reborn, you create a character from an assortment of options,
from tanks to distance fighters. You'll complete quests, play in 5 player group dungeons,
and up to 10 player raids. Along the way you'll get new armor, weapons, and spells.
MMORPGs are way more fun with friends, and that's a true here. You'll either want to make friends in the
game or get some friends to install the game and join you on quests and raids. I think this game
has me more excited for the future of MMORPGs rather than excited about the game, but I
had to include it in this video because it's a start of something really incredible.
If you're a fan of MMORPGs, I suggest you try it out. As I'm posting this video,
the game is on sale for 1499, and is available on Oculus and Steam platforms.
Another game I really love is Path of the Warrior. It's kind of like a first-person shooter,
meets Street Fighter kind of game. You can play the single player campaign, or even better,
jump into the game with a friend on co-op mode. They're only like 5 or 6 levels, but each one
is packing a punch. Pun intended. There are a bunch of combo moves and fun mechanics that keep the
game interesting at every moment. I highly recommend this game for both playing alone and with friends.
Oh, and you'll also get a really great workout playing this game, so if they're on some workout
close, then kill two birds with one stone. The game is now available on the Oculus store for 1999,
and the last one I say for you guys is Echo Quest VR. Now, this game isn't out yet, but I'm
so excited about it, and I know many other people are. I actually got to play it up to this
connect 6. I made a video about it, so if you want to check that out, I'll put that video right in the corner
there, and in the description. This game is amazing, so it's basically ultimate for his beyond steroids.
You're playing ultimate for his V in zero gravity in its space, obstacle course. You can grab on to
different obstacles, and thrust yourself forward. You'll actually have thrusters on your arms,
and it's kind of like quiddaged to. So you're throwing the Frisbee to your teammates, and then you
have to get it through the goal. It's really awesome. It entered Alpha this week, and it should hopefully
be coming into beta, and then being released real soon. It was supposed to be released at the end of last year,
and it still hasn't been released, and I'm dying for it. This is probably going to be the game that
like goes on top of all the other VR social games for me, so super pumped for this. That's all I've
got for you guys today. Please let me know if any VR games or social apps that like I need to try
or anyone else needs to try in the comments below. I've really been wanting to try out once. Have you
guys played that? Let me know how it is down there before I buy it. Are there any other first person
shooters that could be fun? I need more games to play online with my friends, so let me know more that
you guys recommend right down there. I definitely play it on coming out with more VR videos because this is
like what's taking over my life right now, so stay tuned for those, want you guys to subscribe right
down there and click the bell for alerts, and if you guys enjoy this video, keep it alike. All right,
that's all I've got for you guys today. I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.