Explain to us what Glucotrack looks like.
The device is housed in a titanium housing.
Again, design just like an implantable loop recorder.
And so the length of that device, about two thirds of that length,
is actually battery to give us, you know,
three-year longevity out of that remaining one-third,
you know, half of that is electronics.
And then the other half, which is the clear plastic part,
you know, at one side of the device,
that is where we connect the lead.
And then the lead is kind of like that little sensor filament
that comes out of the sensor, or the, you know,
and it has, you know, wires that go down a connects
into the device, as wires go go down to electrodes,
as constructive, very similar to a cardiac pacemaker lead.
It goes into the actual vein, which is sort of near the armpit area.
And then it's advanced to inches or five centimeters
into the subclavian vein.
And the lead goes there, and then it is, you know,
sutured down and connected to the electronic device,
which is placed effectively under the skin.
If I'll go as well, you know, our target is, you know,
commercial approval in, you know, second half of, uh,
2028.