Oh, hey guys, how's it going?
It's Justin and if you know anything about me,
it is that I am obsessed with Fitbit.
I've been sporting the charge three for a while now,
but I wanted it up great.
So I got the Fitbit Versa.
I have a ton to say about both of these,
so I had to come out with a comparison video.
And there is a twist to this video
and it's not just that I'm taking my shirt off.
Also, did you know that you could subscribe to my channel
at any moment during this video, pressing that button down there?
Yeah, you can do it.
And you should do it.
Anyway, here's my comparison video.
You can take a look at this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this, this.
Real quick, the charge three goes for 149 and the Versa goes for $199,
but for Father's Day, both bands are on sale.
And that charge three is looking real cheap.
They both have a special edition,
which adds an NFC chip for credit card payments,
as well as an extra band.
And the Versa also comes in a light version for $159,
which I'll go into later.
The design of the charge three stains true to its predecessor.
It's a simple sleek watch with the tactical bands
you can easily switch out to dress it up or make it sporty.
The charge three has a small touchscreen,
and that's the perfect size to show off all the stats you want to see.
This is the first charge to not have a physical button,
but instead an inductive button.
The Fitbit Versa looks more like a smart watch.
It's got a super responsive and vibrant touchscreen
and three buttons, allowing for more options and commands.
You can also remove and replace the Versa's bands for new ones.
I definitely recommend going over to Amazon
and checking out the bands there
because they're cheaper and there's some cool ones.
Unfortunately, both of these watches
come with proprietary chargers.
This has always been one of my complaints with Fitbit
because the odds of someone else having the charger you need
is extremely rare.
Why can't we charge these with USB-C?
Money.
Also, I've gotta say the Versa chargers a little bit overkill.
It's huge and it's kind of loppy.
And most importantly, both watches are swift proof.
Ah!
Oh!
Holy!
Both the charge 3 and Versa are water-resisted up to 50 meters
and they automatically track your swims.
The charge 3 is very straight forward and simple,
and that's why I love it.
The touchscreen works seamlessly and smoothly,
and I was very impressed.
You swipe down for notifications and swipe up for stats.
I love how quickly and easily I can read off all my days
information and get back to my day.
There are multiple watch faces to choose from.
I chose this one because I love how I can tap
through every stat quickly and easily.
To log in exercise, you swipe to the left
and choose an exercise you want to start.
The Versa screen it feels just as smooth
and seamless as the charge 3.
There are a bunch of watch faces,
some of which you need to pay for.
Fitbit allows third parties to create and sell watch faces.
Swiping down displays notifications,
clicking the top right button start to work out,
and the bottom right one sets alarms
that you can program right on the watch.
On the charge 3, you'll need to pre-program the alarms on the app.
Holding down the left button allows you
to access music controls for your phone
and music stored on the device.
That's right, the Versa allows you to put music
right onto the device, but more on that later.
Just like the charge 3, when you swipe up,
you can view all your stats.
I've got to say, the loading time on this has me a little put off.
Because if it's larger screen,
the Versa can show off a bunch more information.
It dives deeper into heart rate stats,
or average steps that we in details of last night's sleep.
But honestly, I don't really need all that information on my wrist.
If I want to get that information,
I'll take a deep dive into the app.
One of my favorite things about the Versa
is using it for exercise.
When I finish it gives me this great receipt of the workout.
The charge 3 also gives you a little receipt of your workout,
which is not as pretty.
Both watches also display calls,
texts, and other alerts very well,
and both watches automatically log to exercise,
which is my favorite feature.
The charge 3 gets an average battery life of up to seven days,
and the Versa has an average battery life of up to four days.
The watches have other apps,
and this is where we can see a lot of differences between the two.
Let's start with the charge 3 because it's much more limited.
There's relax, which helps you, you guessed it, relax,
with breathing exercises, a weather app, the timer, and alarms.
Now, the Versa has a much larger screen,
and with this great power comes great fitness tracker responsibility.
The Versa's got a bunch of apps.
There's the coach app, which provides on-screen workouts.
I try to couple out and I like it.
You'll need to pay for a subscription to fit bit coach
in order to access more than the three on the watch.
There's also a weather app, Starbucks app,
where you can put your rewards card, a timer, and an alarm.
You also have access to an app store
with apps like the New York Times, or Philips you,
so you can control your lights.
So one of the main things that sets the Versa apart
from the charge 3 is that you can put music on the watch
and connect it to your Bluetooth headphones.
Now it's gone around.
Now this was definitely one of the downfalls for the Versa,
because putting music on the watch
was a very disappointing and frustrating experience.
There's a music app which allows you to store 300 of your own songs,
but I don't own music.
I have a Spotify subscription.
I know a lot of people also have Apple Music.
This watch does not support either,
but there is a Pandora app.
So I signed up for a free month to try it out.
This was also a disappointment.
You could only put three stations on your watch at a time.
Not a playlist, but a random assortment of songs
based off of a station.
On top of all of this, it took the watch an hour
to load up on all the songs.
It like took me back to the first time I got an iPod,
but in a bad way.
Once the music finally loaded onto my watch,
I connected them to my power beats pro 3,
wireless headphones, and it worked pretty seamlessly.
And the music controls were great.
So I've gotta say, it's performing really well
playing music right from the watch.
I really like it, but I can't just in fine.
Getting this just for the music capabilities, right?
If it had Apple Music or Spotify, then I'd be all in.
I personally wear a fitness tracker
because I just wanna get some quick stats
and then go on with my day.
The charge 3 is simple and sleek
and I'm able to view and log all of my exercises quickly and easily.
It lacks the ability to program alarms and hold music,
but these are things that I'm able to sacrifice
with my fitness tracker.
The verse has a beautiful screen showing off
a ton of information, but it's a little slow
when it comes to loading times.
And as a bunch of apps and stores music,
but the lack of Spotify and Apple Music
is definitely noticeable.
If you subscribe to Pandora and don't mind waiting
an hour to load new music on the watch,
then I definitely recommend the verse up.
But like I said earlier, there's a twist.
There is a verse of light
and it's only $10 more than the charge 3.
And with that one, you're sacrificing just a few things.
You can't store music on the watch.
It doesn't have floors climb, swim map tracking,
and it doesn't have on-screen workouts.
So I feel like if it's between the charge 3
and a verse of, I'd go with the light version.
If the music is a non-issue for you,
then go for the verse up.
I've said this before, and I'll say it again,
but the true winner here is the Fitbit app.
It is amazing.
And ultimately, it's what prevents me from wanting
to get an Apple watch.
The graphs, statistics, and charts on this app are awesome.
I can see all of my workouts, zoom into each,
and get detailed stats on them,
and then compare them to others.
And because the Fitbits have such great battery life,
I can track and monitor my sleep patterns as well,
which is a lovely ability.
On top of it all, because I have the Fitbit Arias scale,
I'm able to map the progress on my weight
and body fat percentage.
Fitbit has some awesome software,
and honestly, the dream would be for the decree
now for the Apple watch.
Fitbit, listen to me, I will pay you $5 a month
for an Fitbit app on an Apple watch.
Please.
So I wanna hear your thoughts on Fitbit.
Which Fitbit do you have?
Which Fitbit do you love?
Also, which other smart watches do you like?
I wanna know because I wanna try them,
and then I wanna compare them.
So please let me know in the comments below,
which ones you're using.
Also, subscribe to this channel
if you wanna see some more fun tech videos
and I have some giveaways coming,
so follow me on Instagram for those.
Other than that, I've gotta go on another 500 mile run.
So, I'm Justin, I'll take you later.
Oh, so nice.