Holy crap! Apple's worldwide developer conference just ended and I am stunned. So much was said,
but here are the top 10 things you need to know.
First thing is Apple announced a new show called for all mankind on their Apple TV plus platform.
It's from the creators of Star Trek and Battlestar Galactica and it's a show that imagines a world
where the Soviets are the first to land on the moon. It's basically about the space race and
a push to get to Mars. This show looks really awesome with a very large budget.
Also Tim Cook said he saw an early sneak peek of the entire first season and he loves it. So
why wouldn't we? Next up is Watch OS. There is now an app store right on your wrist. So
you can download and install apps right on the watch. Next up is iOS 13 a few things here.
Just like the last Mac update we are now getting a dark mode for iOS and it looks
Also the photos app is getting a much needed facelift. Your phone always has all these pictures
because you took 15 of them. It now condenses them to show you days, months and years and it's really
really pretty. Okay this one has me ridiculously excited and it's AirPods audio sharing. So what that
means is if you have AirPods and a friend has AirPods and maybe a few other ones you can all be listening
to the same thing at the same time. This is something I've like fantasized about since college.
Now you can like go on a stroll with all your friends with AirPods and not even talk to each other
and just listen to the same music. Also really excited about this one. I think I'm just excited about
everything. It's CarPlay multitasking. I've been waiting for this and it's finally here. You can now have
split screen on CarPlay and Siri won't take up the whole screen when you talk to him or her. Can't wait for it.
Okay this one is big Apple announced iPad OS today. Yeah so what that means is the iPad is officially
breaking apart from the iPhone and it's becoming its own thing. iPad OS is widget a f. This new
OS is going to have amazing multitasking. You're going to have notes next to notes. You can have
word documents next to word documents. You can take pictures and put them in other things and you can
now plug in flash drives. All right Apple, thanks for the flash drive support but why don't we move to
USB-C instead this lightning cable thing okay and what Apple basically did today was say hey listen we're
going to make your iPad a Mac without making it a Mac so you'll need a Mac. Why? Because many we want
you to have an iPad and a Mac. Hashtag Apple but I'm kind of okay with it and I kind of want to
iPad now. I don't have one. Okay so this one came out of left field for me. A Mac pro was announced today
or should I say a cheese grater. So Apple is going back to their roots of being able to customize things.
Yay finally we can customize our Mac pros. This thing is a powerful freaking beast. I'm not going
to get into the nitty gritty of this thing. Let's just say it's freaking powerful. This thing starts at
$6,000 and this is what you're getting for that. Which brings me to my next one. This is the brand new
display by Apple called the Pro Display XDR and it is beautiful. This thing is super powerful. It is a 6k
retina display. I also really appreciate that super audible throne as the Apple was like oh by the
way this screen doesn't actually come with a stand you have to pay for that. This starts at $5,000 and
I don't got no money from Apple. Help me I'm poor. Next is Mac OS Catalina which I've actually never
been to and I really want to go. So you have me tips let me know. Anyway not a ton here but basically we
are going to get some revamp apps. There's new reminders and new notes and that new photos app.
One thing that's really great with the new Mac OS is voice control. So they're making a huge emphasis on
being able to talk to your Mac and this actually works across all the OS's. People will now be able to
speak to their devices using numbers or being like do you correct that for me? This is really amazing and
I think this is a really good push for accessibility. Also at this time we are finally saying goodbye
to iTunes. After 18 years iTunes is officially dead and it's being replaced by three apps a podcast
app and Apple TV app and an Apple music app. Don't ask me why we couldn't just do this in one app and
have three different sections. They decided to make three apps. Let's take a moment of silence to
remember iTunes. And lastly this is something that's got me really excited for the future and it is
AR augmented reality on iOS. A couple of people from Minecraft came on stage and they showed us how
AR is going to work and it is fascinating. They were able to not only play with two devices and see
each other interacting in the game but they were able to inject themselves in the game. And this is
really just the beginning and it's not something we're really going to be doing who wants to really
hold an iPad and do AR. No Apple is going to eventually come out with some glasses that you put on
and that's how you interact in the AR world. We're not there yet but that's the future implications of this
and I'm ready for it. So those are my top 10 takeaways just some little snippets but I had to let you know
what's going on in the Apple world because my mind is blown. As Apple releases some of these
data I will be covering knows as well so definitely subscribe to my channel for more of those videos and
follow me on the social media. Other than that I'm Justin I'll take you later.
Did I do that?