Hey VR enthusiasts, I am back at the Void for a private press event.
That's right.
Justin Tech is here to check out Jumonji Reverse The Curse.
I'm also interviewing the co-founder and chief creative officer Curtis Eggman.
I think it's time to go.
Let's do it.
Out of all the movies you could have chosen, why did Jumonji fit so well on the Void?
I know it's funny.
A lot of people describe our Void experiences as stepping into a game, which is not necessarily
our goal, which is trying to create experiences for people to have, but in this particular
case, if it is a game, you're dropping into a game, and what more could you ask for out of
an IP for the Void?
In this game, you and up to three friends are dropped into the world of Jumonji, where
the evil Hakaar has stolen the sector of Sephayu.
This experience builds upon all of the past Void experiences and takes them 10 steps further,
adding new elements and features that immerse you deeper than ever.
There's so much that's different about this experience than what we've done before.
You actually walk further than you do in any other experience.
Everyone has their own special skill that comes into play so you realize the attention
of what your character is good at.
Some people will see things, other characters can't see, and some will hear things, other characters
can't hear.
You know, you've never known to lose a life before, in an experience.
But again, since this is a game, as Jumonji is, there's peril.
I mean, you can lose a life, which creates for some really interesting moments as well.
It was time for me and my friends to hop in the game.
We got to choose from four player cards.
I chose the monkey and was super happy with my decision.
My character could talk to animals and had a weakness for cake.
It's like his character in the movie, trust me, don't touch the cake.
It's time to roll those dice.
Every stage of the game is full of dangerous traps and obstacles.
My friend Max died five times in it was hilarious.
The part where I died came out of surprise, so be careful and tread lightly.
What I love so much is that our characters each had their own abilities, and that just makes
me want to hop right back in there and be another character, and then another character.
The amount of choice also that we'd have throughout this game to choose either A or B, that
was also a really great addition to this, and something that I look forward to seeing
and other void experiences.
Can we expect more partnerships like this in the future?
Absolutely.
We love working with Sony, we've been working with Sony since we did Ghostbusters back in 2016.
There's a lot of fun on its name, building this with them.
I think we can expect to see more of that relationship in the future that we love working with
Sony.
So this experience really takes the cake, but wait, don't take the cake, take the sector, otherwise
you will die a horrible death.
The jumanji is my favorite experience at the void so far, but the other ones are also
really awesome.
So definitely, if you want to check out those experiences, why don't you watch that video right
up there, because I've got some other videos on those.
And if you want to see more VR videos, hit that subscribe button down there and click the bell
for alerts, and if you enjoy the video, give it a like that will help people see it.
Also what your favorite VR experience you've ever been to.
Let me know in the comments below, because I want to visit it.
Next thing, I am doing a giveaway.
Head over to my Instagram for that.
I'm giving away two gift cards, each good for four guests.
Gotta do that.
Gotta be here.
You gotta check it out.
Okay?
Jumanji.
It's great.
Love it.
All right.
I'm Justin.
I'll take you later.
That didn't mind, but that.