I am at AT&T Shape on the Warner Brothers Lops where AT&T is showing off their 5G network
and now it's going to completely revolutionize entertainment and our lives with its incredible
speeds. They have a lot of exhibits explaining their technology and how it's going to be used.
So let's go check them out. AT&T Shape was packed with emerging tech. But what it all came
down to was AT&T's upcoming 5G network, which will completely change the way we understand
and interact with technology. This new internet tech will not only allow us to transfer data
at unbelievable speeds, it will also cut latency to allow for faster reactions. 5G will be
about 10 milliseconds, average latency time. Your 4G network right now around 100 milliseconds.
It's always like a tenfold improvement. The demo behind us had a motor working to keep a
pendulum balance over the 5G network. There was a sensor at the base of the stick reading
its angle and over the network the motor quickly decided how to move to keep it balanced. This was
all happening at about 8 milliseconds latency. Now if you pull the lever back, go ahead and pull it all
the way back, that's going to artificially increase the latency and you can see the thing can barely
stay stabilized. If it was 35 milliseconds, it would follow. So how is this going to affect you?
Well think about it when an autonomous car is driving 60 miles per hour. It will need this short
latency in order to react quickly. Also streaming capabilities of VR and AR content will be greatly
increased. Over wireless networks you could never do that for anything other than 5G. And this is actual
like an actual 5G network that's doing this. It's not a doctor's demo. We've really set up a 5G
network here that's going to get access. Not yet, it's it. Yeah, I don't. I don't think that's
given out the world up for the password for that one. Next I went to 18T's StoryBee to experience
the 5G network for myself. 5G StoryBee, what is that? We've basically taken a volumetric 3D capture station
where participants can walk in there and get their cells captured while telling their story. And that
content is a 3D volumetric content which gets processed in real time. You get sent over the 5G
network which the tablets are able to access and download this hundreds of megabytes of content.
Traditionally this type of interaction took minutes. Over 18T's 5G network, that interaction
is happening in matter of seconds. Okay so now I'm going to go watch myself as a small little person
in augmented reality. Let's check it out. Oh my goodness, look at me. I'm so small. Oh my god,
there I am. I'm fine. It's with this type of technology. Having a 3D volumetric phone call with your
love when I cross the country across the continent is in near future. You can see this and have a
transcontinental conversation with your loved ones with just super sense cameras and the power of 5G
with low latency and high better. Has Obi-Wan Kenobi come today at all or if you want Kenobi
has been reference tens of fines and I'm sure yet the hologram Luke has been reference more than that.
18T's 5G network is available in 19 cities across the US and it's slowly rolling out to more. Unfortunately
there's no data now for my hometown of Los Angeles. 18T's shape has shaped out to be an awesome event
18T's 5G network cannot get your soon enough. So pump for it. If you want some more details on their
5G network I'm going to throw it in the description below. Subscribe to the channel for more tech news
follow me on social media. I'm Justin. I'll take you later.