Tell me about this diabetes educational app level one.
The game is super simple. You come in and there's a nurse and she just talks you through everything.
You come in and you're high. You got a dose insulin to bring it down.
There's an insulin needle to bottom screen. You tap it, drag over. I think to like two units or something.
Goes in. You watch the insulin go in. You watch it activate the cells. It's like great.
Now you just learn how to dose insulin. Now you have to deal with a few highs and how to correct.
Then food starts appearing. Then you have to start learning about pre-bolicing.
Initially the foods just tell you, oh, for this food you're going to need right now a
unit of insulin or two units of insulin, just a little tag above the food. But eventually that goes
away. And it just shows you the carb count. So there's 60 levels. There's food that's just moving in
on a conveyor belt, dropping into your digestive system, getting broken down to these gorgeous
glucose particles. You inject insulin. It comes in off the side. Activates the cells and just sucks
in the glucose. And you just play the game for two hours and you've mastered every major topic that you need for the
first six months of MDI.