Hey YouTube, I have some huge news.
I just hit 2000 subscribers.
I am inlated.
I want to thank you guys because you guys are supporting my dreams.
I want to give you some stuff.
Okay. How about that?
All right.
This is not a sponsored ad.
I had reached out to this company called My Sticker Faced.
What do they do?
They make stickers of your face.
Kind of like this.
Took that out.
My Sticker Faced sent me.
Basically, a lifetime supply of stickers of my face.
And also my nephew, baby Kevin, who is the cutest dog ever.
Oh, she's such a good boy.
I have partnered up with my Sticker Faced to give you the chance to win some stickers for yourself.
We're giving away five gift cards for $30 each.
So head over to my Instagram for that.
And you know what, even if you don't win the giveaway,
we are all winners because you get to use my discount code right there.
Just in tech, and you'll get 20% off your purchase.
I had this really sweet letter that the My Sticker Faced sent me.
It says that they can't wait to see what I create.
This is what I'm creating.
And then we have the team right there.
That's the team. I love that.
There's a sticker for it.
One in a little puppy.
That's so cute.
They're actually based on Long Island,
which is where I'm proud to think that's awesome.
So I know it may seem super vain to have a bunch of stickers of your face on it.
But it's not like I have a shirt like that, too.
Anyway, I have written this segment to show you guys the top five ways to stick your
your face.
First way to stick your your face.
Mark your things.
Stick your items specifically that are often taken by people because they think it's there.
Stick your your pens, your pencils, your phone case, your phone charger.
That's a good one.
Everyone always thinks it's theirs.
No, it's not because you face this on me.
Second way.
Stick your face.
Goody bag.
That's actually how I found my sticker face.
It's my awesome friend Julie, made goody bags for all my friends.
I'm like a weekend getaway for my birthday.
Every goody bag had a booklet of stickers of my face and also had like these little big lighters because
my friends love lighting candles, both recreational and prescription.
Third way.
This is really my favorite way to use the stickers, writing a letter.
So if you're writing a letter to someone, when you sign your name, also put a sticker your face.
And you know what, when you're sealing up that envelope, say it you spit and use a stick
to seal it fourth way.
Dishware, you know what I have right here?
An enviable coffee mug that keeps my coffee warm.
And you know what, I don't want you touching it.
So I'm going to put a sticker of my face on it.
You can use these stickers on dishware because they're microwave state and dishwasher safe.
And there you go.
No one's ever going to take you thermos.
It's mine.
Goody bag.
Now for the final and fifth way.
But nine graffiti.
You're going to be putting your face on your friend's things.
So next time your friend goes to brush their teeth, they're going to see a cute little picture
of you on it vibrating around their mouth.
Oh, do they have some really cute conditioner?
Make sure it's even cuter with your face on it.
And don't worry, they have this great vinyl material for easy application and removal.
What if a friend passes out of the party?
Don't put a sharpie on their face.
Put a sticker of your face on their face.
I hope you guys enjoyed this video.
I want to thank you so much for subscribing to my channel.
And if you guys enjoyed this video, why don't you give it a like?
Because that will help the video get found.
And while you're there, feel free to hit that subscribe button and click the bell for alerts.
And I also want to thank my sticker face for teaming up with me to offer these awesome stickers to you guys.
Yeah, we're doing that giveaway.
So head over to my Instagram to get the rules on that.
Also, I do have that discount code just in tech right here.
You can use that for 20% off your purchase on their website.
And I guess that's all I've got for you guys.
We're Justin.
And we'll take you later.