Hey guys, today I'm at AT&T to check out the Magic Leap 1 Creator Edition.
So this is basically a spatial awareness technology.
They're not calling it VR or AR because it can do both.
They're starting to throw them into some AT&T stores around the country and luckily I live
right by one.
So let's go check it out.
So I am here to try out the Dead Mustai, a Magic Leap experience by Game of Thrones and HBO
and I'm pretty f***ing f***ing f***ing.
And I'm really pumped, so let's go do it.
Here is everyone.
It's the Magic Leap 1.
I am so ready to put this on.
Let's go for it.
Wow.
All right, so I'm going to jump on in.
The Dead Mustai, a Magic Leap encounter.
Now loading.
That's what I see over you right now.
I hear there's a white walker in it that I get to kill.
All right.
I'm going to look this way and there's a ring I have to look at and it's freezing.
All right, okay, now it wants to be going this way.
There it is.
It's all the way over there.
Move closer to the ring.
Okay.
Hopefully I can.
Okay, there we go.
I'll point it here, preferred wall and press trigger.
Okay, here it goes.
I think this is like the big one.
So I'm choosing this wall right now.
It knows there's a wall there.
That's really cool.
Grab the dagger.
Okay.
I don't think that was supposed to happen.
This is definitely the Valerian Steel dagger that RIA used and I'm about to go grab it.
Okay, I have a dagger and it is snowing now and there's ice on the wall.
That is heartbreaking.
Okay, and it's coming toward me.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, no you didn't.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
There's a white walker.
Yeah, yeah.
Holy, oh, he just died.
I killed him.
Well, I just killed a white walker and I feel really productive about the day, so I think it's
time to go.
As I was leaving, I bumped into Tim Johnson, the VP of Sales at Magic League.
He explained everything about the device and what it's capable of.
There are four world cameras, basically, or recording everything you see.
There are depth sensors and all kinds of other sensors that are basically making sure that
they can measure the space and know how you're moving through it.
There are two eye tracking cameras that are basically watching what you're looking at.
Obviously, with your eyes, you can also get biomarkers, so obviously, long-term you wouldn't
log into this, you put it on, it would recognize that it was you, and then it would work.
Otherwise, it wouldn't work for anybody else if that's what you decided.
We can tell a lot about your health, your heart rate, your cholesterol levels, all of those
kinds of things we can tell from your eyes, so it's pretty amazing what it can do.
There is so much more to this interview, and I was thoroughly impressed, so I'm coming
out with a video next Thursday with more.
So, subscribe to my channel and make sure you click the bell to get alerts.
In that video, I'll have this full interview, and I'll play a bunch of games.
So stay tuned.
There's a hologram of C3PO right now, talking to me.
There's corgs.
There you go.
Oh my goodness, that was unbelievable.
This is unlike any device I've ever used.
It's not VR or AR, it's a spatial awareness computer.
It does so much more than any other device I've tried.
The Magic Leaf One is $2300, so I know it's not for everyone out there, but you have to check
it out.
Go to one of your AT&T stores right now, it's only at five stores in these cities below, but they
are going to be rolling it out around the country throughout 2019.
So definitely keep an eye on what stores it's available at, because you need to try this.
I've got some other tech videos to do, so until then, follow me on Instagram, Facebook,
subscribe to my channel.
Yes, I'm talking to you before you close out of this browser, subscribe.
Anyway, I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.