Have fun at your sleep over, right?
Mommy's not looking at numbers.
It's tonight off.
It's Daniel's mom's night.
The kids are gone.
I'm tuning out levels, except for right now.
Okay.
Hi, Donna, how are you?
Yeah, he's at his friend's house.
She's having a sleep over.
It's my night off.
I'm doing spa day.
I got cute covers on my face.
What do you mean they don't do anything?
Then why are they on my face?
Well, they're called for you.
I know what we're got to purchase it all.
Who's low?
This is very nice.
I feel very relaxed.
Done.
No news is good news.
It's fine.
I'm just going to call, I'm just going to call.
Hi, Angela.
How are you?
Yeah, it's friend.
I just wanted to check in.
How are things?
They're not there yet.
Oh, they left 10 minutes ago.
Wow.
Since I have you here, I packed sour patch kids in the bag.
If you want, you can put them out in a bowl.
Just remove the yellows and greens.
I find the flavor is offensive.
Please, nothing over, please you 13.
And just do not show them, steal their nollias.
I made that mistake already.
And also not mad on web.
I'll make a lot of mistakes.