People don't know how to take one beautiful perfect great-head room great-lighting kind of picture and that's a really sad thing
So I went to Coachella and asked someone on the street. I'd be like, oh, you need me to take a picture really guys
They'd be like, oh sure, and I'll be like all right. Well now you gotta take a picture and we jump took a picture of them
I gave them the beautiful picture they get my camera and they take 15 pictures. Oh, oh
Don't that that that that that that they make a gift. I'm like listen
I didn't ask for a gift or a gift. I asked for a picture. We've gotten into this horrible
habit instead of taking one picture, we take a bajillion, 15 to be more accurate. Now my challenge
to you guys out there, if someone comes over to you and asks you for a picture, I want you to take
that camera, walk 10 feet away, roughly, make sure they found their light, maybe tap on their face
to make them pop and I want you to take a picture. Because you know what people, one picture can
speak a thousand words, but a thousand pictures sometimes doesn't even speak one word.