you know, so many people are jaded that there will ever be a cure. Many of them are listening.
What would you say to them that as to why there is hope?
Yeah. I mean, well, let's start with why they're jaded. They think that all the big
pharma companies are making their bajillions of insulin. At this point, they're not making
very much money off insulin. And they would make money off a cure. Let's say next week, a cure
for type one diabetes is FDA approved. We're not going to all have our hands on that cure,
even within the next five years. You know what I mean? Like, it's going to take a while to get around
30 million people in the US who have type two diabetes. Type ones make up like last I saw
is 1.7 million in the US. The pharma companies can survive without us. Because they have a future
50 million people. Type two diabetes. Many of whom are going to continue to need insulin.
They don't need us. And they have all these GOP one medications and many more coming down the pipeline
that are making them the big box. Stop with the money thing. That's just silly. Once you understand
the deeper workings. I mean, the CEOs and the lead researchers in these organizations that are driving
cure research, Doug Melton, for example, is not going to be bought out by a big pharma to hide
his cure in his pocket. He wants to cure his son and his story is not unique.