Hello and welcome to Diabetic. I'm Justin and today I'm doing a tandem mobile site change
If you're new here, welcome on here. I talk all things diabetes tech tips and research and I'm doing a bunch of mobile content
I've been wearing it for just over two months now and I was using omnipotte for the last few years
I wanted to try a tube pump. So today we're doing a site change and I've got a lot more coming for you
So stay tuned to the end where I'm gonna get into all the content coming out
And this video just like my others is not medical advice and is for educational purposes only
Always consult with your physician before making changes to your health care
Good that little pump. It is a tube pump and right here
I've got everything we need for the site change. We have a cartridge which holds up to 200 units of insulin and
And an infusion set. There are a couple options with mobile 23 inches or five inches today
We're putting on a five inch which is nice because you can just have the mobile clip or even at here to the body
Like right near the infusion site and it's a very small tube. Actually go on right here
Look at that. That is the five inch tube. It's super small and you can just you know kind of have it
Stay all together. So let's do this. I've already
Removed the cartridge from it. So this is what it looks like is out of cartridge. This is where all the brains are
I've got the app open up on my phone and it says to remove the cartridge did that already
And you use face ID to continue and next it wants us to open next. We've got to fill up the cartridge. So let's do that
Right, so the first thing we want to do is put some insulin into the cartridge. I'm gonna take this
wipe clean up the insulin vial
Put the vial on top of here and then here. I'll just pull out
Insulin
And then what I
To get the air out. I tap on here a little bit push it up
Try to get all those champagne bubbles out
And then don't have much left in this vial, but I think I can get exactly how much I need
We go sweet
We have got the insulin in the cartridge. So take this off and then
Take this out take this a little piece out
That's all garbage
On twist this little top part and there you go. That is the cartridge right now. I'll take this cartridge and I'll put it right on the pump
Twist it in and there you go. Next we've got to
Connect the tubing to the pump
To the cartridge now we've got to connect the infusion set the tube
This is short little five inch tube to the pump
Like so
There we go
We've got the pump and the tube and then the next thing you have to do is you have to get insulin through the tube
Just hold that here and then that you use the app for so once that's connected
You want to continue and then you're what you're gonna do is you're gonna hold the button on the pump
And it's going to work to get insulin through the tube. I usually find that I have to do this a couple times
You don't want to keep your eye off of the
little needle here because that's where the insulin's gonna come up and as soon as you see
Drops no drops yet. That's when you stop. So note
Let's do it again. I'm sure we're gonna see them and he's second now
Interesting I didn't see it again, so I'm gonna do it one more time
Usually I feel like I get it in that second time
Oh, I see it from there. There you go. You can actually see it through go through the tube and into this little piece right here
So there you go. There's a little drop of insulin and we are ready to go. I feel like when I first started doing site changes
But maybe it felt like a lot, but the more I've done it the more simple it's become
so
That's going through great so now I just have to put it on so next what you want to do is you want to
Take off this little blue safety cap. So you don't want to do it. I just did which was pull it up and luckily
I was able to get it back down. So I almost want to hold this down as I'm hold down on this like piece as I'm taking off the blue
cap
Then
You rip off this
Then you take that off which will reveal the sticky part look at that so you can see that
The actual needle and surrounding that is the cannula and then you've got a sticky part as well
That's what's going to stick to my body
Next you want to take off this back piece of paper
This will unveil the
Contraption to put it on and then from here there are ridges on either side you kind of hold onto those
So you're going to pull up on these ridges and pull this back there we go
There we go. I got it and now I have this piece that is ready to be
Put into my skin so you can see the needle sticking through again and then there's these little ridges which is where the tube goes
So I want the tube to go downward. So I'm going to
Put it in like this so that the tube is sticking down
So before I actually use that I'm going to get this piece
This alcohol swab
So I'm going to have it go right here. I'm going to let it dry first and then also what I'm going to do it
I'm going to take this clip. This is the clip for mobile. I'm actually going to clip this and I think
And then
Clip the mobile so that I'm not like having it way down on me. I feel like after going from tubeless with omnipot to mobile
That switch has been tough for me. It's just been a lot of
The dangling parts that I'm not used to because with omnipot you could just put the pump on and then it does it itself
I have a video of my how to do an infusion site change with omnipot on this YouTube channel if you want to check that up. So anyway
Let's do this
So I'll put the pump there
Clip down and then this is where I clean it so there's a little ridge here
So I'm going to put that ridge down and then this is where I'm going to have the pump go
Now there's two little hand pieces on either side or finger pieces that you're going to push in so ready
I'm going to push these in
And it's in then I push down on this to make sure that the adhesive is sticking and then just pull this up
And there you go. I've got a new site
You can see the little kneel
in there
and
Yeah, that is a tandem mobile site change
I've got a lot of tandem mobile content that's already out coming out on my social and diabet underscore tech
And also here on YouTube I've got a video that's all about like going from the tubeless omnipot to tube and
All of the
Interesting things and the frustration things that have come out of that. Oh, I guess I should finish this on the app
And a review for tandem mobile coming out
And there we go. I am good
And then I'm also you always want to make sure that automation's back on it usually asks in my case it is
I'm just going to give myself a little insulin because I need it
I was high I did not want to film this
But I was highly at night and I needed to film my next site change and that's right now anyway
I hope you enjoyed this video. I hope you learned something if you want to learn more about mobile
Make sure you subscribe to this channel watch my stuff on social media and give this video a like if you enjoyed it
I'm Justin and I'll take you later