So, a few months ago, I showed you this awesome VR music experience, and I had to come out with more.
So, prepared to be amazed by Red Pill VR.
Imagine if Coachella, the Sims and Virtual Reality, were all morphed together.
That's what you get with Red Pill VR.
Red Pill VR allowed visitors to enter an interactive electric garden dance club in virtual reality.
We are essentially building the future of social music experiences.
We believe that music is one of the most driving things that brings people together.
So, we invented a technology that allows for infinite scalability for an artist to be able to reach a larger fanbase than just the number of tickets that's torn at a door.
We're creating worlds and environments in which artists can perform
and connect to their fanbase.
And we as consumers of the music, can have these social experiences with our friends
from different cities all over the world, sharing this experience together.
I'm about to jump into Red Pill VR.
I'm going to be transported into a club dancing with the other people here.
The DJ is going to be there.
The dancer over there is going to be there.
Let's go clubbing.
It was time for me to join the party.
So I threw on an Oculus Rift S and a subpack and entered the club.
The inside was a real DJ playing music and a giant sized dancer.
Both are at the booths with me injected into the game.
The dancer was wearing body trackers to fully encapsulate her movements.
Red Pill VR has invented a technology that allows them to take a stereo signal of sound
and break it down to its core components and apply the audio to react to objects in the club.
So you may notice that a mushroom is beating to the bass or a flurry in the air is moving to the keyboard.
I could interact with the world and dance with other people.
Hey, Tina.
I even walked up a spiral staircase and I shrunk in size as I went up.
Are you seeing this on the TV right now?
I'm getting small.
I'm like an owl.
This is literally Alice in Wonderland right now.
Then I teleported to the VIP section where I was literally standing on the DJ's desk.
Isaiah says this is just the beginning.
Right now, it's a location-based solution.
In other words, what you see here?
We will show up and create and do as an immersive event experience.
So that's our sort of phase one launch.
But ultimately Red Pill is a platform.
You as an artist can come in to our platform, build your nightclub, or your venue, or your space.
Invite your friends to come here you play.
Terri virtual ticket, or have a subscription, or make it free, or make it sponsor.
And show your music with the world.
You're a attractive team, huh?
To sexual assault count if it's in a video game.
Sorry.
Hey, I have a app.
These are things that the government need to start thinking about now.
So what I was just told is that in the future,
they're going to start implementing the ability to push people away.
Yeah, if someone comes up to you and they give you the worst pickup line,
and then VR slap your butt, you can push them away and tell them to go.
They go.
themselves.
Thank you so much.
I am in shock right now.
And there were so many possibilities.
I could get smaller.
I could go up an elevator.
I could see the entire club from a, like, this beautiful vantage point.
I was feeling the music.
And not to mention the first time there, I made it to the VIP section.
Red Pill VR is just the beginning.
With Oculus coming out with Facebook horizon,
I can't wait to see what other worlds I can visit and create in virtual reality.
There's the Aurora Ballet Ruralis.
There's the Northern Lights.
How did this technology make you feel?
Is this the beginning of Ready Player One?
Tell me what you think in the comments.
Also, don't forget people.
It's important to dance and real life too.
I am so incredibly excited about the future of this technology and the future of virtual reality.
If you want to be there on this journey with me,
subscribe to this channel and follow me on social media,
because it's going to be an amazing adventure.
Until next time, I'm Justin.
And I'm a techie later.
One last question.
What happens if you take the blue pill?
You wake up and believe whatever you want to believe.
All right. Well, thank you so much.