I am here at Sequel Medtech Headquarters in Manchester, New Hampshire, where eight employees
are starting on the Twist Insulin Pump.
Let's check it out.
Employees gathered to celebrate the launch of the new pump, including the CEO, Alan Loppin,
and Pump inventor, Dean Cayman, almost 30 employees around the country started the system
today.
And I spoke with Jen LeBlanc, one of the first people to use twist.
You've been wearing this pump for four hours now.
Four hours.
How's it feel?
It's absolutely incredible.
I've never had a pump like this, and so you can see my glucose alert.
Look at that.
What are they coming in?
Bulletin on the watch.
That's something I haven't had a chance to do on my other systems before.
So I can't tell you how excited I am.
Everybody's here from every single person.
That's going to be answering calls for people with diabetes.
That's going to be working on the product.
It's going to be training.
Everybody's thrilled.
In just two years, the company was built, brought on over 250 employees, and launched twist.
And sequel says it's just the beginning.
Their motto is never settle.
Support for two continuous glucose monitors has already been announced.
A second infusion set is with the FDA, and more updates are planned.
The twist pump is coming.
Sequel Medtech is cranking these out.
I went over to the production line, and they are hard at work.
If you or so many know, has Type 1 diabetes, and you want to learn more, head over to twist.com slash Justin and sign up for notifications.