we call this our cell-pote technology and it literally is a poach and it's made from implantable
pliable surgical mesh. So what the physician does right now in our clinical trial is the physician
will surgically implant this beneath the skin of your abdomen but above the muscle fascia of your
abdomen then what happens your blood vessels grow around this they grow in it and they grow through it
so it literally turns into what we call a biohybrid organ but you can see these horizontal channels
there are plastic rods essentially so when this has become vascularized the surgeon will go into
under your skin again they will pull these rods out leaving these cylindrical cylinders into which
he will then or she will then impregnate this with functional eyelet cells. That's the technology
and we've been working on this for several years now and we are partly through the phase one
to clinical trial which means your evaluating principle is safety and also you're looking for efficacy
and the efficacy that we've been looking for is patients becoming insulin independent.