In preparation for my review of the Philips Hue HD My Sync Fox coming next week, I thought
I'd go back and show you guys my interview with Philips Hue a few months ago, where
they showed off Hugh Sync on the computer.
Yeah, so Hugh Sync is our entertainment package, so a lot of people don't realize this
with smart lighting, you can now actually have great interactions with all of your entertainment
music, movies, TV, video games, and we'll showcase some of that stuff now.
Hugh Sync is an app that runs on both Mac and Windows PCs, and syncs all of your
hue color capable lights with the content on your computer.
It creates an immersive experience when you're playing games, listening to music, or
watching videos, and it works with any media you throw up on the screen.
Even me.
You can actually set it up to do a couple of different things in an rack, right?
So you have full control of your lighting, so your normal hue scenes, right?
Your read, your relaxed, I can adjust the intensity, I can turn my lights on and off, so
you have that functionality, and then of course, you can have some fun with colors.
The controls are simple, sleek, and easy to use.
First, I checked out gaming.
So now you can see, as I move around, and as I rotate in real time, the lights are actually
interacting with what's going on the screen, and it's really bringing that immersive experience
out.
So you can actually see, so as it starts to flash because my health is getting low, the lights
are actually flashing, giving me that anxiety that I'm actually dying over here, and then
that's great demo to show, right?
As I'm just as I'm dead, then he should off music.
So I'll turn on something like Pandora, and then what it's doing is it's picking up the music
and the intensity and the beat and the actual genre of music, and then it's now going to mix
the music that's going along with that.
So you'll notice as the music gets louder, the lights will get more intense, as the music
kind of dims down and gets more relaxed, and you can have some fun with some preset scenes,
so if you really want to have different color palettes, you can pick and choose, and then
set the intensity as well.
So if you didn't want it as intense, you just wanted more kind of gradual light changes, you
can do moderate all the way up to that.
Again, that full and tense where it's on and off on the beat of the music.
Then he showed me a concert on YouTube.
So the light setting is going on, and you're getting your lights are interacting in real time,
what's going on in the screen, and you can pick whatever you want, your lights are going
to interact.
So whatever, whatever's on your PC, that's kind of what's going on there.
Hucing is free to download on your Mac or PC, but you will need a bridge and some lights to
get started.
Everything is running off of the huge bridge, still.
And realistically, Hucing can work with any of your headlights.
We're showcasing here, of course, our full color range of lights, and then two products that
are designed specifically for kind of entertainment in mind.
So we have our Hucines, which is our table lamp.
We have a table version and a floor version, and then we have our Hucines, which are actually
mounted on the back of the monitor.
So they're really mounted here, and then the idea is to give that ambiance around the wall
and to kind of create that big splash effect.
Philips Hue has also teamed up with Razer to make the PC gaming experience even more immersive,
with Razer Chroma.
Unlike Hucing, which basically takes what's on the screen, Razer Chroma allows video game
developers to program lighting effects within their code.
And so you can kind of see that just level of integration that you can do.
And this, again, fully up to the game designer for whatever whatever they want to do with it.
So as you get, like, some of the combos, as you land the big combos, the lights will actually
flash and a rat, kind of give you that feel that you're really kind of there.
I played some mortal combat and was pulled into the game.
I'd say this is the closest you're going to get to VR without putting a headset on.
If you thought this was cool, wait until you see my review of the Philips Hue play HD MySyncBox
coming next week.
Philips Hue has brought the Hucing technology to our home entertainment system with this device.
Make sure you subscribe to this channel and hit that bell for alerts so you know when the video
comes out.
Also, if you enjoyed this video, give it a like, it helps it get found.
As always, I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.
Thank you so much.