Now I'm last day.
I'm at the Philp Q Suite at the area at CES and they have a bunch of products and new features
to show off today.
You know, I'm feeling pretty zen, it's time to get intense.
Let's do this.
First let's start with one of my favorite Philips Q products and that is the Hugh Syncbox.
Right back here I have the Maleficent trailer playing and now you can control the Syncbox
with a remote through infrared.
So there it is playing and I'm going to press the button right on this remote.
While the Syncbox is going, I didn't have to take out my phone and turn it on.
Look at that.
You can also use voice commands to control it.
So I'm going to switch this now to the Xbox using my voice.
OK Google switch Hugh Sync to Xbox.
Sure switching into a Xbox on the Syncbox.
Thanks girl.
There you go my Xbox is on and I'm ready to gain.
OK my mom said I've been playing too much Xbox so she wants me to play outside.
Welcome to the Philips Hugh Garden.
Let me show you some of the new outdoor lighting they have for us.
So right over here we have the up here.
This has a really nice light coming from both ends creating like a triangle shape.
Love these?
They track.
We have the e-connect.
These are a pathway lighting solution.
These also go really well with the sconces that they sell.
The e-connect.
They're iconic.
And this is the Lily XL.
Over there we have the Lily Spot.
That's been around for a little bit and this one I'm really excited to throw it at the smart
home in Palm Springs.
I'm building and we're going to shoot it up on a big palm tree.
And right over here we have the Resonate and I'd say they resonate with me.
Oh yes yes there's more.
Philips Hugh for a while now has had a 40 watt power supply but they're introducing a 100 watt
supply.
That means you can connect not just five lights but 12 now.
Your outdoor lighting is going to be ever more larger.
Philips has also introduced the ability to control zones with your Hugh accessories.
Now you can connect your accessories to lights all around your home no matter the room.
And this one I'm most excited about so up until now Philips has had Resonate lighting
in light but guess what now they're making in color.
This just makes me want to go like that.
A lot of great announcements today I cannot wait to get my hands on these products and when I do
you will be the first ones to know about it.
I also have a lot more for Hugh to be excited about this week so make sure you subscribe right
down there.
Give it a like if you enjoyed it.
I'm Justin and I'll take you later.
The future right over here these are called the Resonate and Resonate with me.
I've been a one take man all week this is my wife.
Just a nap.