Hey everyone in case you didn't know there is a pandemic going on COVID-19 also known as the coronavirus
It's going around freaking everyone out freaking me out little anxious. It's raining outside in LA. The world is over
Just kidding. Everything's gonna be fine, but I wanted to come out with some videos that are gonna help us all get through this pandemic together because
This is scary
So one thing that we all need to make sure we're doing is wash our hands thoroughly
We've all been doing that I think, but you know what you know what it's not being washed
Our phones. Yeah, we're all about washing our hands, but then you go to trade or jose and you get to pick up the cereal and then
You pick up your phone and then you put in your pocket and then you wash your hands and you're like I'm good
Take out your phone, put it to your face talking to your mom, and then it's ever weird germs are everywhere
You're nasty
Little nasty. Thanks, Raven. So I've done some research and here's what I found. A toilet seat has
1200 bacteria per square inch a kitchen counter has
1700 and 36 a pet food dish has
2,110 a door knob. You know that's gotta be dirty a door knob has
Well, you know what your phone has 25,000 bacteria on it
That is gross. That's why I made this video
I'm gonna tell you different ways to clean your phone right here we go
So the first tech tip which is actually super high tech and I'm really excited about it
And I want to get one myself are these UV sanitizers
So there's one called phone soap UV C sanitizer and basically what you do is you can put your phone inside of that and it will charge it
And it takes about 10 minutes, but it will use UV rays to clean your phone
They say that this kills 99.99% of germs
But I do know that it's not necessarily proven to kill the coronavirus. They haven't I don't think they tested for that
But I think that you know what while we're on this like germ a germ a foe
Moment I don't know why not a get a UV ray sanitizer and clean your phones the nasty
Second way to do it is a DIY way to do it and this is something that anyone can do if you have 70%
Ice a propel alcohol. I think I'm saying that correctly basically rubbing alcohol. You have to mix 60% rubbing alcohol with 40% water
No, that's wrong. You got to mix 40% ice a propel alcohol with 60% water
Make sure that's what you do. So you mix those together
I actually went to CVS to go get some and they are completely sold out
So I don't have any show you you're gonna put those together and then you can dip any
Micro cloth I think I actually have one of those
I do it's just not easily accessible at the moment. So what you're gonna do is you're gonna get that
You're gonna mix those two together and then you're gonna use one of those micro cloths
Basically you don't want anything with the lint and you can rub it all over your phone
Just make sure you don't hit any of like the porous areas those holes or the charging port or speakers
Try to go around that and then the last way Apple just updated their guidelines for how to clean
Your phone and you can use 70% ice propel alcohol white or a clorox white
18 t basically says the same thing but by spraying it onto a cloth and
Samsung hasn't said anything and again don't do it over the speakers and the charging port and also that your part
Where you listen to it's also a speaker. So there you guys have it
I hope you guys found that helpful if you did want to give it a like right down there and for more
COVID-19 content coming your way hit that subscribe button right down there click that belt for alerts
I'm gonna tell you the best tech to have on you to get through this pandemic especially if you're quarantined
So I hope you're not and I definitely am not but I'm under like super self quarantine
We're like I just am not gonna leave my house
No reason to that means I will be making a lot of videos from right here. So stay tuned for that
I'm Justin
And I'll take you later
Stay safe