Hello and welcome to my fourth episode of my Magic Leap series.
Today I partnered up with Magic Leap to show you the office of the future using spatial computing.
This technology has already transformed the way we see a typical office, replacing our physical tools with projections.
One day we're going to look back at our old offices and desks and be like,
do we really use to look at all those monitors and notes and calendars?
Oh grandma, what clutter you had. In this episode I'm going to build the ultimate
ad home office using spatial computing and show you some of the possibilities we have at our disposal.
And this home office is even more appealing right now when travel for work is difficult
or when you'd rather work from home than risk office germs. Oh, when I put that there,
make sure you guys do this. Like this video if you enjoyed it and subscribe to my channel for more videos
like this and click that bell right down there for alerts. Let's head over to my new and improved office.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, hello, welcome to my spatial computing office. Before I hop on in and show you
what I'm seeing, I do want to show you this Logitech K600 keyboard that allows me to type and search
the web quickly and easily on the Magic Leap headset and there's a built-in track pad which allows
me to control the mouse on whatever browser I'm looking at. It will automatically switch between
the windows. You know what, I've been all talk, but I want to be all tech. So let's hop on it.
I build a home office that caters to all of my needs, whether it's photo editing,
planning out my Instagram feed, referencing YouTube videos, or writing a script. This home office
will fulfill everything I need. First off, one of the very cool things about working in Helio on
Magic Leap is having the ability of connecting to a desktop. Here I'm using Nutanix frame to log
into a desktop environment, and I can use the resize option to set this desktop window to any size.
It really helps this feel like a computer of your dreams sitting right in front of you,
especially in the age of giant curved screens. These are really compelling ways to uplevel your home
office using spatial computing. I have access to the entire Adobe Creative Suite, but for now,
I'll open Photoshop. In addition to this, I've got a script over here on writing. It's actually
this script, and then I also have music playing in the background with Spotify, and I have my drop
box open where I'm looking at pictures I want to post on Instagram. I also have a huge monitor over there
with my YouTube video playing, so I can reference it for the script I'm working on. With the next software
update, you'll be able to download the desktop companion app, where you can easily move files or images
from your laptop to your device. I uploaded some photos and I created a vision board for what I want my
Instagram feed to look like over the next few weeks. I can totally imagine people putting pictures
of their friends and family all over their desk. Look at all my friends and family I have. It's funny,
they all look the same. I've only concentrated on one workflow with this setup, but it's really just
scratching the surface. You can imagine how this setup lends itself to use in finance, being able to
have stock data present, have new services streaming while also being able to access a dozen or so monitors
laid out around you, and all with simpler tasks switching between screens. You can also imagine how
designers can use this to have persistent data like models and reference images present or provide
context around them for other designs will live in the physical world. And you can imagine how really
anyone at home can use it to switch between research like planning a trip, shopping, or news, and music.
And with the growth of co-working spaces, think of the potential for devices like this to enable
a broad set of functionality while also keeping the physical setup needs ultra minimal.
Also, do you have a co-worker that you just can't stand? I have a hack for that. Hey Justin, um, so there
was a yogurt in the fridge that had your name written on it, but I eat it. Also, I think in the start
kind of gym, the gym, the gym. Also, is reading a nasterological news article in it. Justin, it's
snacks from work. The future of the workplace is bright. So this is really just the early stages of
spatial computing, and what we can do already is really amazing. The home office is definitely limited
by the number of apps, but since there's a fully functioning browser with Helio and Magic Leaf,
there's plenty you can do in your home office today. There's actually a really cool app coming out soon
called Bar. It's basically a customizable search bar where you can quickly access website bookmarks.
When I think of the future of what apps we're going to have, I think of like a weather app where you put
a window on your wall, and you can see outside to what the weather is, or putting a projection of a
calculator on your desk and typing it with your fingers. There are so many possibilities, and we've
really just scratched the surface. But what I can tell you is that the future of the home office is
three dimensional, clutter free, ever evolving, and powered by spatial computing. What apps do you want
to see in your home office with spatial computing? Let me know in the comments below. And guess what
guys, more magically videos are coming your way. Stay tuned for that. How do you do that? You
subscribe right down there. Click the bell for alerts. And if you enjoyed the video, you can give it a
like. I'd love that. That's all I've got for you guys today. I'm Justin, and I'll take you later.
Glad I put that there. Don't make sure to do that. Make sure you guys do this.