Today, I am in Burbank at Jet Suite X where I'm about to, for the first time, fly on a semi-private jet,
fly over to San Francisco. Let's check it out.
Jet Suite X is a private air service that sells public charter tickets at competitive prices,
and I was so ready to try it out, so I walked inside and waited on a short line to check it.
The process only took a few minutes, and I was done. Besides the lady swapping my bag for the clock,
there was no security. I got to keep my comfortable, but stylus shields on the entire time.
It was slightly unsettling, but at the same time it don't so right, so I have my ticket right here. There is a slight delay, but you know what?
I don't care because they have a lot of natural sunlight, and that is really the key to my heart.
So let's chill in the lounge, or in the hangar, and see what this place is all about.
The Jet Suite hanger had fused ball, cornhole, and couches for people to spread out, and there were rooms with tables and chairs for getting work done.
Oh, in my favorite part, there were snacks, so obviously I chose my space, ate the business woman special, and connected to the free Wi-Fi.
The plainlanded right outside the hanger, and the arrivals descended the stairs, grabbing their luggage.
The cleaning process happened so quickly, I didn't even realize my flights started boarding.
I was so busy filming, and apparently everyone else had boarded, that I had to run almost 100 feet and board the plane.
I mean, I was in my seat in a minute, but I was winded it.
The one and two seat layout was new to me. There were only 30 people on the flight.
The seats were simple, spacious, had great lag room, and refined. There was no entertainment system, but it wasn't really missed on such a short flight.
After the standard safety instructions, we were in the air, and it was smooth sailing.
Oh, except for the fact that the bathroom is out of service, luckily they told us this before we boarded the plane.
There was one flight attendant who came around and asked for drink orders, and to my surprise, alcohol was included.
She came around with a variety of snacks including waffles and pretzels.
I was impressed with the service, and the flight attendant seemed peppy.
That's probably because we were all living our best luxury lives.
Once we landed, I was off the plane in the jiffy.
Oh my god, that was awesome!
Jet sweet X! That was great!
I've got to say, flying jet sweet X was a very cool travel experience.
The fact that I could arrive to the terminal only 30 minutes before my flight was unreal,
and the laid-back hanger with very few passengers was a refreshing change from typical airports.
Let's just not talk about my carbon footprint.
Jet sweet X offers flights in these cities, starting as low as $59 each way.
And also, you can redeem your tickets for Jet Blue True Blue miles.
At the end of my trip, I was lucky enough to fly back from Oakland to Burbank, and I was even more impressed.
Oh, and I also ordered delivery to the terminal.
So I just ordered door dash that's what one of the employees recommended I use, because I was hungry,
and I thought to get my food, and then pick it into the lobby area, and now down before I get on the plane.
Wow! Jet sweet X was definitely the sweetest way I've ever flown before.
You'll have to check it out. There's more information in the description below.
As always, subscribe to the channel for more tech journeys, follow me on social media for giveaways, and really great deals.
I'm Justin, and I'll jet you later.