Dexcom's 15-day continuous glucose monitor just got cleared by the FDA, but there are
high odds that that CGM won't even last you 15 days. You have to hear this. So many people
have been reporting on Dexcom's new CGM, including myself, but there is fine print at the bottom
of their PR release that shocked me. It says that a study was conducted to assess the sensor life
where 73.9% of sensors lasted the full 15 days, and 26% didn't reach 15 days. I reached out
to Dexcom for comments on this, and I also asked how many applicators and sensors people will get
each month. Right now we get three because they last 10 days, that's 30 days. They said that we will
be getting two a month. However, Dexcom did not respond to my question regarding sensor life.
What if 25% of our sensors aren't lasting enough time? We will obviously need to get replacements.
Right now, Dexcom has a limit for three replacements a year. Well, this means according to their
study that we will need six replacements a year. What do you think of this? Let me know in the comments
what is your current experience with Dexcom G7? My experience with the 10-day G7 is that they last
the full 10 days. Very rarely will they not. So, I'm a little worried about this 15 day in the fact
that 26% won't last that long? Yeah, interesting.