Hey everyone, it's Justin and I just got my VR cover in the mail and I'm super excited about it
and I want to show it to you guys and I want to try it for the first time. I had to get the VR cover
because I had a lot of friends coming over that want to try out my quest and they be sweating on my VR headset.
And I don't want that. So I got the VR cover. Let's check this thing out.
So here it is. We got the VR cover right here and it has a nice padding.
Very sturdy padding, I love that. So this is the main VR cover right here that is an insert
that I can take my insert out and put this one in. It's basically a second one right here and what's
so cool about this is that it's actually on with Velcro, right? So right there I'm able to take this off
and then if I want to put the other one on, put that one on. So I had two of these and then here come the
elastic band covers, right? So this is what I'm going to put over these things to protect my precious
pores from all of your sweat. So let me read the instructions which I'm really bad at doing.
So it looks like. So now I'm going to put one of these covers onto the facial
interface that they have here. And then there are these elastic bands that I then all I have to
do is just band it right there. There you have it. I now have the VR cover over that facial interface
and on there pretty nicely. So what's so great is that the insert that it comes with comes right out. So
I can easily change it out. There you have it and then here is the VR cover one. I'm going to
pop this in and now there you have it. My Oculus Quest now has a VR cover on it. I'm going to put it out
lovely and then there's their logo right there. It is hot in LA right now. So I am sweating and I'm going
to put this on and not have to worry about mine getting all the sweat on it.
And there it is. Wow nice and comfy. It's actually more comfortable than the one that it came with.
They also found that sometimes I would have like a little rash using mine for a while and I feel like
this material which is cotton will feel better on my face over long periods of time. So I'm pretty
pumped for that. So that is the VR cover. I definitely can just in by getting this device.
They make VR covers for a ton of headsets. So check out their website. I have the link below. You can
find one for just about every VR headset. So definitely check that out because you're not going to want
your friends using your face mask. You're going to want to use a VR cover to keep their sweat off of
your face. Not cool. For more VR accessories and more VR videos, definitely subscribe to this channel
and follow me on social media. Sometimes I have giveaways other than that. I'm Justin and I'll
take you later. I definitely recommend checking out these VR covers.
Oh, it is hot in here.