So, Philips you just announced their Philips Hue Syncbox and I got to get a first look at how it worked
completely transforming your entertainment system with their beautiful lighting. Let's check it out.
A few months ago, I checked out the Philips Hue Sync on PC and was amazed at how immersive gaming music and video playback was
using the software with Philips Hue lights. I asked about the possibility of this technology coming to our entertainment system
and they couldn't tell me anything. Until now, meet the Philips Hue play HDMI Syncbox.
It may be a lot of words but it does one epic thing. It syncs your lights with your entertainment system.
I got to demo it to the Avengers trailer and I have to say I was impressed. I had a
grain on my face the entire time I watched it because it looked that good. I was surprised by how
comfortable and in sync it felt and how smoothly it transitioned. Now here's a bit about the device.
You can connect up to 4 HDMI devices to the box, watch any content and the box will create the surround
sound of lighting. It will also automatically switch between the devices depending on which one is being used
which helps for seamless switching. You can link up to 10 color capable Philips Hue lights through the app
and it works with all of your current bulbs. The lights they used in the demo were awesome so I
threw links in the description below. They also added a couple slots in the power cord to connect
lights near the TV so you can save on an outlet space. This is a nice little touch and you can tell
how much thought they put it into it. The Hue Syncbox will release on October 15th and you can pre-order it
now on the Philips Hue website. I've put a link in the description. So that is a little tease at the Philips
Hue Syncbox. I will have one soon in my home and I'm going to be playing with it even more and making
another video so stay tuned for that. So be sure to hit that subscribe button and press the bell for alerts.
Also, if you liked this video, why don't you give me a thumbs up? I'm Justin. I'll take it later.
Wow. Are you recording? Yes. Okay.