Hey guys, welcome to my review of the Soulguard Carry-On Closet 2.0.
In this video, I'm going to pack the suitcase, take it all around Europe, show you how
I used it, and maybe I'll give you a just-in-tech promo code.
Let's go!
I am going to Europe, literally tomorrow, and I was in the market for a new carry-on, because
I'm going to be going on a ton of flights, and I really don't want the hassle of checking
it back.
Then I saw this, this is the Soulguard Carry-On, sold on Instagram, and it really caught my eyes.
Why did it catch my eyes?
This is why.
It has this, a clothing divider, and for someone who's super OCD, this is really exciting.
If you can tell, I'm pretty OCD.
Just got this in the mail, thank you Soulguard.
The carry-on closet 2.0 is super sleek, light and is guaranteed to be accepted by all international
airlines.
This is why I chose it.
There's also the carry-on closet plus, which is 20% larger, and is accepted on almost all domestic
flights.
The inside is made from 100% recycled material, and each suitcase sold pulls five pounds of plastic
from the ocean.
Love that.
There's a TSA approved 3-digit lock, and an easy access USB port for charging on the go.
But you'll need to provide your own battery pack.
The suitcase has a delightful, one-pinch opening mechanism, and a somewhat addicting
plusch grip handle.
I literally couldn't stop touching it, and it's most important feature is this removable
shelving system that has six compartments and easily attaches to the handle.
It may seem like a gimmick, but wait until you see how I used it on my trip.
It definitely surprised me.
The carry-on retails for $225, just like it's main competitor, The Away, but just for you guys
by Awesome Subscribers, I'm giving you the promo code just intact for 15% off sold
arts entire website.
I threw a link to their website in the description below.
I'm going to Europe for 13 days, but I'm going to have washing machines at my disposal, so
I'm only bringing enough clothes for 7 days, and then I'm just going to wash them.
Let's see if I can cram these 7 outfits into this carry-on suitcase.
I threw in three pairs of shorts, six pairs of underwear, three bathing suits, six pairs
of socks, three tank tops, and a pair of gym clothes, and five shirts.
I'm going to take this thing off now, I'll scrunch that thing up, I'm going to put some shoes
in this compartment right here, I'm going to put my tall white socks, which are kind of like
my vibe.
I'm going for in Europe, white socks, and white sneakers, super pumped about it, I'm going
to put these in the crevasses.
Now I can put the clothing divider in here.
I put my toiletries into these two bags, and I'm able to fit these right in this area.
So I'm going to have to put a little pressure onto this, like that, and it closed.
Thank goodness.
Otherwise I couldn't go to Europe.
So there you have it, my trip is now packed, and I'm ready to go here, I'm so excited, I can't
wait, check out my trip with salt guard.
And we were off, navigating around Europe from Airport to Airport was so much easier using
this small carry-on suitcase, and again, the grip was just so delightful to hang on to.
My trip was awesome, I went to the gorge of Verdong, oxymprovolts for some wine, oh, and I
met this really cool chicken.
I also saw this beautiful sunset, oh wait, right, this is a review, back to Soulguard.
So I've got to say I was a little skeptical when I first got the suitcase.
There was a high probability that the clothing divider was a gimmick, but I've got to say I was
thoroughly impressed.
So it's just a personal one, I can't wait to get out there and explore, but I had to unpack for a second
and we're really grown here for one day, so I was like, I'm not gonna unpack, you know what?
Yeah, I had because check this out, look what I was able to do, I literally unpacked and
all sorted, just by taking that out and hanging out, this was perfect, I'm super pumped
about this, yeah, let's go explore.
And I found myself easily throwing up the clothing divider in every hotel I went to.
So funny enough, I was traveling with three other friends who all had a way suit cases.
This was the perfect moment for me to compare and contrast the suit cases, here's what I think.
I'll say one downside of the Soulguard is that it was difficult to quickly and easily access
something from the Pax suitcase, when we landed in a new country that was warm, I wanted
to get a pair of shorts, but I just didn't bother, but the upside was unpacking.
All of my friends luggage literally looked like a bomb went off, while mine was nicely hung
in the corner.
Unlike the away which includes a removable battery pack, with the Soulguard, you'll need your
own battery pack, and you'll need one that activates when the device is connected through
its charging port.
Soulguard sells a couple battery packs that do this on their website, one which doubles as
a Bluetooth speaker.
One other thing I noticed was this, it looks like the clothing divider was being strained.
I'm not sure how long that's going to last, but Soulguard did tell me this is covered under
the 10-year warranty, I feel like this could have been easily avoided if the band was looped
through the hard plastic inside the outer material.
So here's what I think.
The carrying on closet 2.0 is the most innovative suitcase I have ever used, for someone
that's organized as me, it was perfect.
I was able to pack an unpack a ton of outfits, unpacked quickly, and I had my very own closet.
Not to mention when I'm not traveling, I haven't organized her at home, even with its minor
flaws I highly recommend this suitcase.
You should check it out with the link in the description below, and you better not forget
that promo code.
So if you liked this video, I'm going to give it a thumbs up.
Also if you want to see more of my tech reviews and adventures, hit that subscribe button and
click the bell for alerts.
What is your go-to travel tech?
What is that one device that you need to take on every trip?
Let me know in the comments below, as always, I'm Justin and I'll take you later.
So the first, let's do this, all right, so first, all right.