I feel like with adult friendships, you at least,
you pretty much know right away
whether it's someone that you're going to be close with.
It doesn't take 20 hangouts to get there.
And you're also not like drinking at a bar,
not really talking about life.
Yeah, like you're having deep conversations
pretty much up front.
Hey everyone, welcome back.
Hello, hello, and happy new week.
Happy new week, guys.
We're so excited that you're joining us again
and we're gonna do a little catch-up
and then get into our topic for the day.
Sounds good, let's do it.
Alex, why don't you tell us, how is your week going?
It's going a lot better now.
At the beginning of the week,
I definitely was having a really hard time
with prednisone, just like batting anxiety,
not sleeping well.
And so I just kind of like took a couple of days
to be not on my phone as much, hello, Knox.
Do some re-nox-ing.
Be outside.
And I think that that's helped a lot,
just having some quiet time.
Yeah, and still on a flare-up waiting for IV,
or waiting for Rotexin to get approved and start that.
So anxious to start that, but ready.
I feel ready to go.
Yeah, so for people that don't know,
so prednisone is a steroid.
It has really gnarly side effects.
I have heard when I was taking it,
it's called like the devil's tic-tac or devil's candy.
It just makes you feel kind of nutty.
Like actually psychotic.
Yeah, and not like yourself.
Does that resonate with you?
Like you're feeling out of sorts.
Very out of sorts, heightened anxiety,
heightened emotional-ness and sensitivity.
I get like kind of paranoid, honestly, when I'm on it,
where I think like everyone's upset with me,
or that like I'm dropping the ball on,
just like hyper self-critical.
And then you don't sleep, which exacerbates all of that.
You get really hungry, you gain weight,
it makes your body swell.
Yeah.
I mean, it helps.
It works.
It works, it just, it comes out of bit cost.
Yeah, when I was on it, I gained a ton of weight.
Like I was eating ice cream on the daily,
and not just like regular ice cream,
like a whole like ice cream sundae with like syrup
and nuts and all this stuff on it.
Whipped cream on it.
So I totally get it.
You have to treat yourself
when you're on that medication, you know?
Yeah, I feel like at that point,
you're like anything that makes you feel better,
you'll have it.
I think so.
How long do you have to stay on it?
Probably a couple months.
So like for autoimmune stuff,
you can go on, there's a couple of different things
that you can do for steroids.
You can get like IV-solumedrol,
which is usually like if you're inpatient
or in the ER, they'll give you that.
So when I was in my last hospitalization, I did that.
You can get intramuscular like IM shots of it
or shots directly into like nodules or vasculitis.
Those I prefer because it's in your body
and out really quick.
And then you have like the oral prednisone,
which is systemic for flare ups
that can range anywhere between like 20 to 80 milligrams
per day.
I'm at 40, which is like a pretty hefty dose.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's, I think you're just gonna have to let it
ride out and see.
And hopefully, I mean, I think more than anything,
it's just going to be, you know,
the fact that it's like effective
and that you end up internally healing.
Yeah.
How, what else is going on?
Do you feel like you're getting support
the way you need?
How is that going?
Yeah, I think this has been like,
I'm really grateful for Cooper
because he is so calming to me during this period.
Maybe like a funny little trick
that we do with prednisone.
When I am in like a heightened state
and I start to become kind of snippy
or like my tone is not great,
we have a code word and it's Victor,
he goes, hey, Victoria.
And that is me recognizing that my alter ego,
my prednisone ego is out and being feisty.
That's so funny.
And it kind of like lightens the mood.
It allows, it lets me know that he's giving me grace
right now and to like check myself.
And then I'm just like trying to be more communicative
with like my friends and family saying like,
I'm super anxious right now.
I need extra like love and support and like patience.
And I feel like that's been super helpful to you.
Good.
Yeah.
Do you feel like you get a lot of people asking you like,
so like, are you better now?
Like, how are you feeling?
Are you like, are you out of the slump of this?
Yeah.
And I'm like kind of split on how I feel about that.
Half of it, and maybe this is the prednisone,
half of it, I get like super frustrated, sad, angry of like,
no, like I haven't started my new medicine yet.
Yeah.
Like I still feel like, shit, this is a chronic illness.
Like I'm never going to be a hundred percent better.
And then the other part of me is like,
oh, like my circle cares about me
and like they want me to be feeling better.
And I have to like really remind myself
that people have good intent.
It's not to be like,
that they don't understand chronic illnesses
or autoimmune diseases and how they ebb and flow.
It's them caring and checking in,
but just asking in a way that on a certain hour or day,
might rub me the wrong way.
Yeah.
What about you?
How do you deal with that?
I think it's a tough one, right?
Because I think people are coming from a good place,
but I think when people say like, are you better now?
I think that one bothers me.
I think I'm more so just like the questions
that are like, how's today going?
Yeah, open-ended.
Yeah, like leave it open-ended and then let me be like,
yeah, like it's better than yesterday
or no, I'm feeling worse.
Like kind of just like a comparing day-to-day
versus like comparing like I'm better overall.
I totally agree.
Cause I think when you say like, are you better?
It doesn't give us space to actually tell the person
how we're feeling and whether intended or not,
it kind of shuts down the conversation of like,
this person only wants me to be better.
Like maybe that's the only version of me
they can interact with.
And I think that can be really disappointing and tough.
Yeah, I agree.
And I think a simple thing that I just realized
like a yes or no question is really tough
and can feel triggering.
And a open-ended question feels a lot more welcoming
for us to share how we're feeling.
I totally agree.
My mom once told me this like,
I love when people say, walk me through your day.
Cause then you like can really open up
and like let yourself be vulnerable
with that friend, person, whatever.
And it's better for both parties.
Yeah, I like that.
I also like walk me through your week, right?
Because it's like maybe like today was hard,
but like yesterday was good.
So I feel like when I, when people ask me like,
how's your week been?
That's easier for me to be like, yeah, like Monday, Tuesday,
I wasn't feeling well, I was really low.
And then like, then I was up and about.
So it makes me feel a lot more,
like it seems like the week is a more comprehensive way
to describe how I'm doing versus the day-to-day.
I love that.
And then you don't have the pressure of like,
man, am I complaining again that today's been a bad one?
Yeah.
Which we all hate having to do and say,
even if that is the reality.
Yeah, totally.
Yeah.
How about you?
How's everything been since coming back from your retreat?
I got back just like a couple of days ago
and I'm headed back out in a couple of days.
That being said, I'm really like enjoying
these few days at home.
So like I went to the farmer's market and then I cooked
and I've been just like kind of nesting at home,
but also busy like running some errands,
getting all my doctor's appointments
and getting all of my refills for my medicines,
making sure I have everything for my trip coming up.
So important.
And, but also I think one of the big things I've been doing
since I've been home is like continuing to meditate,
continuing to like employ the teachings from the retreat.
And so that's been really nice.
I feel like my couple of days at home,
like pre-retreat would have felt a lot more stressful.
And now I'm kind of just in this like Zen state
and just like filled with gratitude,
not to sound cheesy, but I feel-
No, that's amazing.
I feel like just grateful and happy, which is really nice.
That's amazing.
What has been the easiest part of like the things
that you learned to reintegrate
and what has been like more effort
or a little bit more challenging
than you would have anticipated?
I think one of the easier things, which is interesting
because I would think it's harder to incorporate
is like getting up early
and meditating first thing in the morning.
We learned at the retreat, like you're more,
like you're most likely to be in like that theta brain state
that you, brainwave that you need to be in for meditation
in the morning hours of like four to five AM.
That makes sense.
And it's so theta brainwaves, just a reminder.
It's like, you have those like right before you fall asleep
and then right after you're waking up.
So it's like that kind of in between state
of like consciousness and consciousness.
Got it.
And so it's easier to get your mind into theta
when you're in those early hours.
So incorporating that has actually been the easiest
because I'm just like, okay, like I know
that's like when it's optimal.
And I'm just going to set an alarm and get up
and do my meditations.
And then I can always take a nap later.
That's been the easiest.
The hardest has actually been doing my gratitude journal,
which I normally do.
I think I'm like, I wake up and I'm so excited
to do the meditation that I skip that part.
And I think that's important to keep still doing
because I think that also brings a lot of benefits.
Totally.
And it helps guide my day.
And I think I'm gonna,
I just need to prioritize doing that first thing.
Yeah.
I wonder if it would be good to do like after your meditation.
Like that's how you end your transition
from meditative state into normal day.
Yeah.
I can try that.
Don't put too much pressure on yourself.
You're doing great.
Like the fact that you're waking up early and meditating,
that's truly goals, sick chick goals.
Yeah.
It's really nice.
The afternoon or late morning naps are also really nice.
I'm gonna try to take a page out of your book
next week and like do one day, see how it goes.
Yeah.
I mean, hell, I'm on prednisone.
So Lord knows when I'm awake, I'm awake.
Yeah.
Okay.
So last week we sent out like a Q and A to you guys
and said, what topics are you guys interested in?
Biz and I exploring a bit more.
And we got great feedback.
We're super excited to talk about each of the things
that you guys want us to.
One of the main ones was all things relationships
be that family, friends, coworkers, dating, marriage.
So this week we thought we'd dive in
and focus on friendships and social life as a sick chick.
Yes.
Let's do it.
Okay.
So maybe let's set the stage as we do.
Socializing before, what was your social life, Biz?
Or were you introverted, extroverted,
kind of describe that aspect?
Yeah.
So when I used to take those like personality tests
that we would do in business school
and like in the workplace,
like Meyer Briggs is one of them
that you can do like a shorter version online of.
But I was like literally like the most extreme extrovert.
Like there was, it was like 100% on the E
of that four letter acronym.
And so I would say it was probably
in that high extrovert stage from like ages like 20 to like 30.
Actually, no, that's not true.
Probably up until like last year or so.
Yeah.
Like I would say for the last like 15 years or so,
I've definitely been like high extrovert
and super social, like you could invite me to anything
and I would come, I wouldn't even ask like
who's gonna be there, what are we doing?
Yes, girl.
I would just show up and then I'd be like
the last person to leave, which is so ridiculous
now that I've think back about it.
But I just had this like social battery
that everything was fun.
And I just wanted to be around people all the time.
Yeah, that's so true.
Like when we would hang out,
it would be until four in the morning.
We'd just stay up talking.
There was no off.
People would message me and be like, oh, I'm really tired.
Like how do you, how do you like do that all the time?
I'm like, oh, I'm fine.
It recharges your battery.
Yeah, exactly.
So yeah, I would say highly social, highly outgoing
and ready like down to do, to go anywhere and do anything.
Yeah, I think that that is definitely true for you.
How is it for you?
I would say pre-college, I was more introverted.
I'd like doing like one or two social things a week,
but being involved in like clubs and activities
from college through investment banking.
I was also a yes girl, like always wanted to go out,
wanted to travel, whatever it was, like count me out there.
And then after banking, when I started getting sick,
that's when my transition kind of back
to being more introverted started, I think.
And like I get charged up definitely from like a long time,
but I am also very extroverted or can be really extroverted.
So I'm kind of like a split person, I would say.
Do you think that's true?
Yeah, I think that's true.
I think like around certain people,
like I think when, when we hang out,
like we will still have like our full hangouts.
Yes, but I can't do that with everyone.
That's pretty, I'm sure.
I agree.
I think that's definitely like that split part.
But I think, I mean, so kind of like pivoting into like,
like how did we, or like what was the switch for us?
Like I think one thing is like,
it's kind of that like when you're straddling that in between
of like, okay, like I can do certain things
with certain people, but then like, you know,
certain other things.
I'm like, oh, I don't know if I have enough
like social battery for that.
Yes, absolutely.
And part of that is just like,
I think there's lots of different aspects
of why that happens.
Yeah.
One of those is like your identity is shifting
and it's harder, it gets harder and harder
to relate to people that can't step
into that new space with you, I think.
Yeah.
And so, you know, if you're like,
Biz and I are very like high empaths
and being disingenuine or like trying to put on a mask
or be this other person is really challenging
and very socially draining.
Yeah.
So I think that was like one of the main sticking points
is I remember like this as I got more sick
and as I started identifying as being sick,
I stopped being able to relate
to some of my friends at the time.
And we've talked about this before,
but like I was so young when I got diagnosed,
like with vasculitis at least,
that my friend group hadn't shifted
or evolved from my college drinking friends.
So there were, it was like kind of this compounded time period
in my life.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah.
I think for me, like when I, so when I got diagnosed
and I was in the hospital for that month-ish,
that was like, like that in itself like
was a resetting period, right?
So it was like, okay, I'm not gonna be going out
doing the things I was normally doing.
Yes.
And then I think when I got discharged,
like that's where it started for me.
I started noticing that being around the people,
like when they would come visit me,
like it just felt very different.
And then when I did start like going out
and doing, you know, more things again,
I just felt kind of like, like quiet.
I felt more isolated.
I felt like I couldn't contribute
to the conversations as much anymore.
And that was like kind of the circle of like,
okay, like I go to something, I'm kind of quiet.
Then it like makes me not want to go to something again.
And then I started like becoming a little bit isolated.
Yeah.
And I think to your point,
it's like just having different priorities
or like it's like,
I don't want to go out to a loud restaurant anymore.
Like I don't want to be going out,
staying out till like midnight, 1 a.m.
And, you know, the friends that do that
and still, you know, live their life like that.
Like I think that's great, but I just can't,
it's just not something that like I really can do anymore.
Absolutely.
And I think out of that group,
there's only select people that are willing
and like want to make that shift for you and be like,
okay, well, since you don't want to go and do this
or you slash you can't,
how can we hang out in a different way?
And those are like,
those are the real people that we love.
Those are awesome human beings.
And totally, like not knocking anybody
for like socializing like that at all.
It's just like we physically cannot.
I have also learned that like the friends
that like did show up in like the more like
home settings for me, they've all kind of said,
they're like, oh, like we like this.
Like we actually like to like do things like this.
So that's been really nice that, you know,
they were like, look,
they were looking for like a way out as well.
Yeah.
And this kind of gave them like a way out to be like,
okay, like let's hang out at home more.
I totally agree with that.
And, and like what you're saying,
those are probably the split people anyway that.
Yeah.
We're putting on the mask to be able to go out still
and do the all the happy hours
or go to a loud restaurant till late in the night.
And they really were just craving something like this.
So that's totally a silver lining.
We get to be the out for a lot of people.
Yeah, totally.
How did you internally feel when you had to start
like turning down plans or making that shift
in your identity?
So guilty.
Oh my God.
And that was not just internal, but external too.
Like I had two or three friends in Austin that, you know,
maybe I would cancel morning of something
and they were never for like one on one thing.
So it's usually for like group hangouts.
Right.
Which should be an easy out anyways.
Agreed.
And these people just were really tough on me
and would say like, you're such a flake,
you're a bad friend because you don't show up
to this stuff for us and XYZ.
So it was, I had this already internal pressure of,
am I being a bad friend?
Granted, I also was on prednisone.
So like double whammy of internalizing being hard
on myself and then I had these voices external
echoing that.
And so I was really like down and sad and out
for about a year where I didn't have new friends
that were stepping in as much.
And I was essentially breaking up with this group of friends
that not only we're not showing up for my health,
but we're making me feel bad about my health.
And it extended beyond just you're not showing up,
but giving me a hard time about like how,
who I was as a person, which was tough.
I think that's really tough.
And just hearing you even say that it's just,
it's like you weren't showing up to like a happy hour
or like going out to eat or like going out for drinks.
Like you weren't like,
it wasn't something serious that you weren't there for.
It was just like the socializing.
And so I think that in itself is just, I think wrong.
If you aren't able to make it to a social event,
like it's totally okay to be like,
hey, I can't come because of X, Y and Z.
And like you actually have a legit reason.
It's not like you're canceling because you're hanging out
with other friends or you're doing something else
that's using that energy.
You're literally trying to like stay at home
and rest and recuperate.
And it's just, I think it's wrong to shame someone
or make them feel guilty when they're sick
and they can't come to something.
I agree.
And at that point, I didn't have a diagnosis yet either,
which I think further exacerbated it
because people would think like, are you being lazy?
Like what's wrong with you?
And being chronically ill.
I had days where I looked and felt normal.
And then days where I wouldn't.
And that like dichotomy there was really hard
for my friends at that time to understand,
which looking back, I'm like, that's really lame.
Google, just Google something, read something
because that's not just me.
Or ask me, yeah.
And they never asked.
They wouldn't check in on me, wouldn't anything.
Looking back, like they were just super immature
and not great friends or just were more focused on socializing.
Yeah.
And I think like what you, like there are friends
that are just there for like the good times
and they're not there for you really.
And it of course sucks when you realize that.
It's not to say like those people
you have to cut out of your life,
but that was my main friend group.
And so it was either I'm gonna be mentally beat up
and emotionally beat up all the time by this group
or I'm gonna make changes in my life
and maybe be lonely and not have that many friends
for a while and make new friends.
And that's the direction that I ended up going.
Yeah.
I also will say like, there's nothing more isolating
and feeling lonely than like being in like a group hangout
and feeling like no one's getting it.
Like no one's getting what you're going through.
Yeah.
Have you had experiences like that?
Yeah, actually I feel like, I mean,
I feel like I still have them,
but definitely like more so in the beginning
when I like really wasn't feeling well
and I wasn't sure how to manage not feeling well.
I would still like, or like when people had come over
or like we'd go out somewhere,
I just felt like I couldn't relate.
And I felt like, they were all carrying on and having fun.
And I think on, I think their intent was like,
well, we want this to be fun for you.
So we don't wanna talk about what's happening.
Like we want this to be a distraction for you.
Absolutely.
Which I don't think is like a bad thing,
but I think what I was needing at that time
was people to talk about it with me.
And I think even now, I think the people,
the friends that I'm the closest to
are the people who really talk to me
about what I'm going through
and not just try to distract me.
Absolutely.
I think I don't,
I just don't think I'm this type of person
who needs distractions.
Like I wanna be real and authentic
and I wanna talk about all the things.
And you'll say when you want a distraction.
I think that is like one of the hardest parts
or like maybe the like tipping point
of all of this friendship conversation is communication.
And so like if, at the beginning,
we might not have the words to be able to express
or say what we need.
And so just asking,
hey, do you want a distraction?
If you wanna talk about this is a game changer and huge.
Yeah.
Versus trying to think like,
oh, what would I want in this situation?
Because we're all different.
Like what you want might not be what we want.
Right.
I totally agree.
I think it's like being able to like communicate
to your friends and your family.
And like even if like,
let's say they're being supportive
and they're talking about it with you,
but you hit a point where you're like,
okay, now I'm done talking about it.
I wanna just like hang out now.
It's totally fine, thanks guys.
I'm so glad we talked about that.
Like let's kind of just like talk about this now.
Yeah, totally.
And I think when I've done that in the past,
like people are like, okay, great.
Like let's, you know,
they're really honestly like down for whatever.
You just have to let them know for the most part.
And it feels so awkward at the start when you do that,
but the benefits are 10 fold.
You get more comfortable doing it
and people are super receptive to it.
So at the end of the day, it's a benefit for everybody.
Yeah.
I think a lot of people don't know what to do.
And so I think guidance is nice.
And you know, just help them out a little bit.
Yeah.
Nobody can read our minds.
It sucks having to be the one that educates,
but it's for your best interests
to put in the time and to do that.
Totally.
Okay, let's talk about like how making plans
and canceling plans and the friendship game
is when you're chronically sick.
I think for me, for the most part,
people have been understanding.
I think what's, I think the canceling plans
is still awkward for some reason.
Some people still feel like entitled to your time
if you've committed to something.
Yes.
And so it's, you know, it's like we,
like I could wake up in the morning
and know that like by the evening,
I'm not going to be feeling well.
Yes.
But I could also wake up in the morning and be okay
and think that when 7 p.m. rolls around, I'll be okay.
But things change throughout the day.
Yes.
It's, I think a last minute canceling should be respected
and okay from someone who's chronically ill.
Yeah.
I want to say like the buffers like two hours before,
like before someone leaves their house,
it's probably good to give them a heads up.
Totally.
Yeah, I think like before someone starts like getting ready
for whatever you're doing, give them a heads up.
And I think at that point, like you're giving them
enough of a notice that it should be okay.
Like they should be able to survive their evening
or hang out without you.
Yeah.
And if they don't have plans then for the night,
like is that worse or is it worse
that your friend who's chronically sick,
you want them to push through everything,
be in pain, be uncomfortable and hang out with you?
Yeah.
I think that's what's important
to keep in the back of the mind that like,
yeah, canceling sucks for everybody,
but there's a reason why that sick person is canceling.
And I don't think you wanna see
what that reason looks like probably.
I think another thing with canceling for me,
I find it less stressful when the person doesn't respond
with like, okay, let's reschedule.
I think that's also hard.
It's like, I couldn't make it today.
I don't exactly know when I'm gonna be feeling better.
And so I think just leaving it open ended
and just being like, okay,
we'll figure something out another time.
Like just, it's probably not the right time
to nail down another hangout.
I totally agree.
And maybe it's the right time to be like,
I'm so sorry, like, is there anything I can do?
It seems like you're going through something right now.
Yeah.
Or like just like a totally understand,
no worries at all.
Take care of yourself.
Hope you feel better soon.
I'm here for you.
Absolutely.
I think that that's like the perfect way to do it.
The perfect way to do it.
I think less questions and more just like loving statements.
Yeah.
We just wanna be loved.
Oh, but it is tricky and it is sad.
And being a sick trick,
like you do miss out on a lot of things,
be that travel, weddings, baby showers, stuff like that.
I think at this point,
I've missed 10 of my friends' weddings.
And it doesn't get easier anytime.
It's still heartbreaking that you're missing out
on these like big life moments,
not even just like the Friday night or Saturday night hang.
Yeah.
And I think when like those invades come in,
that's when the anxiety starts of,
damn, I really hope I'm gonna be able to do this
in six months in a year.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's tough.
I luckily haven't had to miss like major things like that.
I think that would feel a lot more disheartening.
That being said, I mean, I can probably look back now
and be like, oh, I probably shouldn't have gone
to that big event.
Yes.
So maybe I should have probably missed out on those things,
but I think, I don't know,
there's something about like pushing yourself a little bit
when it is something important,
but just kind of understand like,
I'm probably not gonna feel good after this,
but I'm willing to like take that risk
because this is so important to me.
And then I think on the flip side,
like if you do have to miss like your friend's wedding,
et cetera, like hopefully that friend's like a good enough
friend that understands it and doesn't hold it against you.
A hundred percent.
And I've had split.
I know you've had,
I know you've had a split experience with that.
I've had the best experience of week of,
hey, I'm not gonna be able to make this.
I'm in a really bad spot.
If I get on that plane,
I'm gonna be in the hospital.
And like I will 10 times out of 10,
choose stay home versus hospitalization,
setting myself up for that.
Because either way you're missing the event.
Yeah, yeah.
Right?
And so the friends that respond with,
oh my gosh, I love you.
I'm so sorry.
Of course, like do what's right for you.
That feels really good.
And then the friend, like I just had to miss my friend's
wedding in Cabo because I was in the hospital.
And when they came back,
they like drove to our house.
They brought me flowers for being in the hospital.
And then like we looked through all of their wedding photos,
watched their first dance,
like made us be able to relive those moments with them.
And still we're like, we love you.
You're sick right now.
And like we also care about that.
It was really, really special.
Exactly.
And it's like, let's say like,
you didn't hear from that friend again.
It's like, well, why were you,
like why were you sacrificing your health
to go to this person's wedding who doesn't care?
Doesn't even care about you actually.
Yeah.
Maybe I'll share that story.
Should I do it?
Yeah, let's do it.
Okay.
This is the bad one.
I mean, it's good for us listening.
It is.
So this is like truly the worst case scenario
of what can happen.
I was friends with this girl.
She was in my wedding.
I was going to be in her wedding.
And throughout her engagement year,
I started to get sick again.
And, you know, I think it was like that fall,
I had two bachelorette parties I was supposed to go to.
The first one I missed and I was really sad.
I sent champagne to the group and whatnot.
That also impacted that friendship,
kind of has fizzled out a bit.
I think it was because like I could do other things
that weekend, but couldn't fly.
And there was a misunderstanding of like why I couldn't fly.
But the, was there some sort of question,
like you were able to fly for this
and now you can't fly for this?
Exactly.
Yeah, exactly.
So when I went to this other girl's bachelorette party,
then I think it made the other girl mad
that I couldn't come to hers.
Which is understandable, but from an outsider's perspective,
but from a sick chick perspective, it's like duh,
I didn't feel good that weekend.
And I felt better by the other weekend.
And they were months apart.
Yeah, it's kind of consistent.
No, so for the really bad story,
I go to this girl's bachelorette party.
I push through, I don't use my cane during it.
I have like two or three glasses of wine
throughout the weekend.
By the end of the weekend, I was so fucking tired.
I almost missed the last dinner.
I got home and slept for a week.
I started prednisone again
and I could just feel like, shit,
I think a hospitalization might be imminent.
Right.
But I kept trying to push through and push through.
And then it was her wedding coming up to her wedding.
Yeah.
And I had lost probably, when I bought my dress
to wear for her wedding, I was losing prednisone weight.
So I was probably like 30, 40 pounds heavier.
Yep.
At the point of her wedding, I was tiny
and the dress did not fit.
And she would text me every single week,
like, hey, have you gotten your dress hemmed?
Hey, have you gotten your dress hemmed?
This was a very expensive dress.
And so at that point, I was like,
I'm not gonna hem this dress.
I'm just going to sell it
and buy something that actually fits.
Sure.
So I was kind of punting that ball.
Maybe I should have been more communicative or whatnot.
But that was annoying her.
And then we were talking about, you know,
what the wedding weekend would look like.
And I had lost my hair during Cytoxin pretty heavily
and it was growing back in.
Yep.
I did have a wig.
And she said, are you gonna wear your wig
for the wedding or do hair extensions?
And I said, no, I don't think so.
And the fact that-
I don't like that question.
I don't like that question either.
It's like that, you don't get to have any opinion
if I do that.
And asking that's super inappropriate.
Yeah.
So that was the beginning of me being like,
why am I, why are you making me feel bad about being sick?
And also like after her Bachelorette party,
she did not text me and say like,
hey, I know that you're having a hard time.
Thanks for pushing through and showing up.
It was, that was expected next story.
The worst part was I said,
hey, I'm having to use my cane more and more
and wheelchairs right now.
I just wanted to give you the heads up,
which I should not have to give someone a heads up
if I'm using a cane or a wheelchair in the first place.
Right.
Her response was, well, you didn't use a cane
at my Bachelorette party,
so I don't think you're gonna have to use one at my wedding.
And it was very apparent that all of these things
that she cared about were for the aesthetic
and the photos and whatnot.
The look.
The look and not, hey, one of my best friends
who I invited to be a bridesmaid
is going through a hard time.
How do I make this easier for her?
It was like all these questions
that made me feel like shit for being sick.
Yeah.
So come the week of her wedding,
I'm being incredibly overly communicative with her,
letting her know like things are going worse,
things are getting worse, things are getting worse.
I end up in the hospital.
And she's like, hey, if you can make the wedding,
like I don't care, you can just like sit in the church
and like watch the wedding.
You don't have to like sit, be a part of the wedding party.
You don't have to do anything just like,
if you can just show up like that, that's fine.
And I was like, okay, that sounds great.
Which is nice of her.
I think finally like, I mean, a little bit,
I think it was rooted in like,
I don't know if I want you in my pictures.
That being said, she gave you an out at least of,
you know, being able to attend
and not be a part of the bridal party.
Exactly.
So that's nice.
So that was super nice.
But what happened next?
So then I'm in the hospital and it's her wedding weekend.
I sent in champagne.
I am texting and I'm like,
I would love to like FaceTime you
while you guys are getting ready.
And she was like, I don't think I'm gonna have time for that.
And there goes the rest of the week.
It's not responding to me.
Not any kind of communication.
Not thank you for the champagne.
Nothing just goes radio silent.
And after her wedding, I was like,
hey, like would love to catch up
and like hear about the wedding.
I'm so sorry I missed it.
This has been a tough hospitalization, blah, blah, blah.
And she's like, I'll get back to you
when I come back for my honeymoon.
I never heard back from her
and have never talked to her since.
You literally like never heard from her again.
Never heard from her again.
That's wild.
And I know it was because I think she thought
I was making her wedding week about myself
because I had a health crisis going on.
And part of me understands that
cause like you've got a lot going on when you're the bride.
The other part of me is if one of my bridesmaids
was sick during my wedding week,
I would make time and space for them
cause they're one of my best friends.
And be like, I'm sorry.
And if you're chosen and asked to be a bridesmaid
that says a lot about your friendship.
And then it should go both ways.
Like if you're unable to partake and do all those things,
like your friends should understand.
And I get it, it's their wedding week
and they're busy and all of that.
But at some point later, there should be communication
and like we miss you so much.
And like, how are you feeling?
What's going on?
All those things.
Absolutely.
And like, I don't know.
I would also know that like my bridesmaid would be really sad
and like upset that they couldn't be there.
So I probably would do something
to make them feel a little bit better.
Like send them a picture or FaceTime them
during the wedding weekend at some point to be like,
we miss you, like we're all here.
Send them a video of that or something.
But it was just like the most selfish thing
I've ever experienced.
And it made me have a really tough time thinking
like people don't wanna be friends with me because I'm sick
and I can't show up for them in the way
that they need or want.
Which that shouldn't have been how I felt.
It should have been this girl is being really cruel
and you know, caring more about aesthetics
and pictures in herself
than about one of her quote unquote best friends.
Yeah.
I mean, I think for my vantage point,
it's like good riddance.
I think, you know, that friend was never a true friend to you.
Yeah.
Or at least like shifted into someone
who doesn't care about you.
Definitely was a shift.
And part of that too is like twofold.
When I first started getting sick,
she was awesome and would show up
and like went above and beyond to make me feel supported.
Yeah.
And that was during like my cytoxin period.
Once that ended, I think there was a disconnect of like,
I'm still sick.
I'm just not in a disease active state.
And so I think it was like, oh, I'm gonna have to keep,
I've set the bar so high of how I show up.
Do I have to continue this for the rest of my life?
I don't wanna do that.
And instead of dropping down a little bit,
still being there, she just pivoted
and changed who she was to me.
Yeah.
That's awful.
It was really sad.
Sorry.
It's okay.
And then I like, I think the next week missed your wedding
and you were like, it's okay.
I love you.
I miss you.
I wish that you could have been there too.
Like, I understand that you're sad.
You couldn't be there.
It was a really fun wedding.
So we definitely missed you.
I know.
And you looked so freaking pretty.
Oh my God.
Thank you.
The prettiest one.
I think we'll do another one.
Good.
Like another party.
I like that.
I think wedding should be celebrated annually.
Yeah.
Okay.
So why don't we talk a little bit about like,
what does socializing look for us now?
Yes.
Like, how is it different?
What are things that we, you know,
what are changes that we've made?
It's a great question.
So I think now it's a couple of things.
One is I have more confidence in my identity
as a sick person and I'm no longer embarrassed
about the things I cannot do.
Like the internalized ableism is getting lessened.
So I give myself more grace.
I also understand that some of my health
might scare other people.
And I just try to get like a good temperature check
of like how deep and personal do these people want to get.
And I don't hold that against them.
It's just like, I know who I can turn to
for different things.
And last thing is like how I socialize.
So I usually do maybe one thing a week
or one thing every other week.
Yeah.
It has, it's time bounded.
I've gotten really good at the Midwestern.
Oh, well, it looks like it's time to get going.
And that's okay.
Gotta go check on the chickens.
Cows are moving, so gotta go.
Yeah.
That's hilarious.
And just like lower spoon activity.
So instead of going bar hopping,
it's like let's go to dinner for an hour or two hours.
And then I'll go home.
What about you?
What kind of shifts have you made?
I think it's definitely just like socialized way less now.
So that in itself has been a huge shift.
Like I spent a lot more time with myself.
I spent a lot more time with close family
and my husband and my dog.
And so I think that, I think also learning for me,
like there's different like circles and tears of friends.
I think before like everyone was my best friend.
Yes.
And now I'm learning that this is like my closer circle.
These are like more acquaintances
and kind of like shifting how I communicate
because I feel like I was setting myself up for failure
in the sense like if I treat everyone like a best friend,
then they expect me to show up for things
and do those things.
And so when I can't do them, then they feel disappointed.
So kind of just having a little bit more of a
like an acquaintance relationship with some people.
Yeah.
So I don't like over promise and over commit to things.
I think that's such a wise way to say that.
Like it's kind of the great resettling
that happens when you get diagnosed.
And however painful it is at first,
it allows them for us to have,
I think deeper, more meaningful relationships
with like our close, close circle
and makes it a bit easier when you're deciding
on which activities you do and don't wanna go to
or can and can't.
Totally.
I definitely, my natural inclination though
is like if I'm having a great conversation with someone,
I'm like, oh, we should hang out, like let's go do this.
And I just get excited and I get carried away.
And I have to now like stop myself
from like throwing that out there.
Rain yourself in this.
If I can't like follow through with it.
Do you, have you pivoted to like more virtual hangs?
Like FaceTiming more, calling more versus in-person hangouts?
Yeah, I think it's been nice.
Like a few times friends have organized
like a friend hangout on FaceTime.
Oh, that's cute.
Or zoom and I feel like that's,
that makes me feel good because I can just, you know,
it feels like I'm going out to dinner with them,
but I'm on my couch and I don't have to exert
as much energy.
That is, I love that.
And I totally agree.
Like the virtual hangouts are awesome.
When I was going through cytoksin,
it was during COVID,
like during the isolation period of COVID.
And so like nobody was really hanging out.
And so I think people were more willing
to do virtual things.
And Cooper and I would do like themed zooms with our family.
So we did like when Bridgerton first came out,
we did like old English tea party on zoom.
And it was so cute, so fun, so cute.
Something to look forward to that was like dressing up
and doing something, but time bounded
and not the burden of hosting people.
And that was really, really fun.
So I love that pro tip for anybody that's like,
I miss hanging out, but I just don't,
I can't handle or can't physically do
the hangout right now.
Yeah, I think that's good.
That's a great tip.
I think another thing I was thinking is like,
when you get sick, like a lot of people will reach out
and they'll text you, they'll call you,
they want to be there for you.
But a lot of times people say things like they'll,
they'll text and be like, please know how I can help.
Like what can I do?
I'm here if you need anything.
And like the problem I have found with that is like,
it puts like the burden of coming up
with something on me.
And then I find myself like thinking like,
okay, like what do I need?
Like how, like, I don't want to just,
I don't want to just tell everyone like,
no, I don't need anything because like I do need stuff.
And it just feels awkward having to ask.
And it's like a very broad throwing something out.
So like what I've liked the most is like,
when people text and they send options,
they're like, okay, like, do you want me to drop off food?
Do you want me to make you something?
Do you want me to send you like a little care package?
And that is like so easy for me to respond to,
just like a quick like this one, like that's what I want.
And then it takes the burden off you of guessing
what that person is comfortable with.
Like is that someone that wants to cook for me
or wants to come and clean my pantry for me?
Or is that someone that just wants to like text check it?
Yes, exactly.
I love that.
I really love that actually.
How do you, like for the friends that have done that,
how do you now replicate that to other friends
or other people that will text you like,
how can I support you?
I guess like when I've gotten options,
it makes it, now I have like a bank of things
that I can like ask people to do.
But to your point, like,
I don't know what their capabilities are necessarily.
So, and it's also like awkward to be like,
can you send me a care package?
Like that just sounds like a weird thing to ask someone.
Really need a new skims row.
Do you have $150 that you want to spend on me?
But to that point, I also think one thing that's been,
like it's, for me, it's not about like,
and I know for you either.
It's not about like the price of the gift, right?
It's really the gesture.
Hell no, the gesture.
And like one of the nicest things that I've received
are when people send handwritten notes.
Yes.
Like I love that.
I've definitely gotten into the zone of like,
I don't love texting.
I find it very like burdensome
and like it just takes a lot of effort for me.
And you know, I would rather like a phone call or FaceTime
and then like a handwritten note is like the nicest thing
that I feel that people can do.
Especially when most of our mail is just endless amounts
of medical bills and still having something positive
in your mailbox is awesome.
Totally.
Or like even like if you want to just like,
I think mailing is also difficult to have had some friends
write a note for me and then like take a picture
and send it to me.
That's really cute.
And that feels like just as important honestly.
I totally, I love that.
Yes.
We should put together like a not so sick chicks
suggested support options that people can send around.
Okay.
We'll do that for y'all.
Yeah.
I love that.
Okay.
One question that I have is for the people,
like when you're first getting started
or meeting someone new that you're becoming friends with,
how do you gauge like what their comfortability is
with you sharing the most?
Like when people say, how are you?
Instead of going like, I'm good.
I'm fine versus how do I gauge?
Like this is a really hard time.
I'm super depressed.
I'm in a ton of pain without making them scared.
I think I'm like really honest up front.
So like if I get asked that,
I'll say something around the lines of like,
oh, I don't know if you know,
but like I'm diagnosed with X, Y and Z
and I'm like going through my treatments right now.
And then I'll kind of gauge their response.
If they're like, oh, I'm sorry to hear that long,
awkward pause.
I'm like, okay, see you next time.
And my dog is great.
How's your dog?
Then I usually go into like, tell me about you.
Like how are things like, how's this going on?
So there's that.
And then I feel like the people that respond with like,
I have heard, I didn't know if you wanted to talk about it.
And then I usually respond with,
no, I would love to talk about it.
And then we get into it.
And so I think just being up front,
I think it's just a quick, easy way to tell
if people want to talk about it with you or not.
And then I guess one step further than that,
for the people that we wish could do that,
how do you handle like the disappointment
of them not being able to?
I think for me, it's like understanding
that people have different capabilities, right?
So as much as they may care,
they don't necessarily have that capability
to show up in that way or like communicate
and like be emotional.
And so I think just like kind of being like, okay,
like that's not something that they're able to do.
I totally agree.
And like just reminding ourselves that like we,
we all don't know all of each other's skeletons
in the closet.
And maybe they had a family member
that had like an awful, awful health time.
And so it's more painful for them to show up.
Yeah.
And I think people are different.
Like for every person you find
that wants to talk about these things,
there's a person who doesn't.
So it just, you just don't know where people are coming from.
And there's also like a fine line of finding ways
to be understanding or, you know, quote unquote,
like make a reason for them.
And someone being a bad friend.
And those are two very different things.
Sometimes it's hard to kind of sort that out.
But I think if someone just can't show up,
that's one thing.
If someone is being mean or making you feel shitty
about not being able to be there.
That's a whole different thing.
Yeah, I think, and I think it's pretty,
it gets easier to tell which type of person
you're dealing with.
Yeah.
And I think there is like a grieving process too
of the friends that we lose or cycle out of that's normal.
But I will say like just give yourself time and grace
because that ultimately is allowing space
for new people to enter your lives.
And like I'm super grateful that I had this great resettling
because the friends that I have now
are just like amazing, amazing humans.
And the friends I had then were like honestly
more surface level.
Right, totally.
I think another important thing is like understanding
how to balance our social needs and self care
is getting comfortable with making and staying boundaries
and keeping them.
What kind of like experience have you had with that
and tips do you have about navigating that
when we're people weasers?
Yeah, I think it takes practice, right?
So I think in the beginning,
it's highly uncomfortable to say any of this.
It's not going to feel easy and that's because it's not.
So I think give yourself grace
that it's not going to feel comfortable.
And I think the way that's been the most effective to me
like if I get invited to something
because I feel guilt when I cancel,
I'll usually say upfront like I'd love to come.
You know, my health is kind of like
or the way I feel is kind of touch and go day to day.
And so I'll let you know closer to then
how I'm feeling, is that okay?
I love that.
Like from the get go, just being open.
From the get go, just being open.
And then I think when I'm at an event
or if I'm going to something, I will usually send a text
if I'm not feeling well, but I'm still going.
I'll usually send a text before and just say,
so excited to see you just FYI,
like not like a super like high energy day today
or today's like a big pain day,
but I still want to come and see you.
And that way it just takes a burden off
of staying it in person.
Because you may not find the right spot
in a conversation to throw that in.
Totally.
And it's not, yeah, I don't think for me it's like
I don't want to say it aloud to them,
but it's more just like socially finding the spot
to be like, oh, like I'm not feeling that great.
Especially if there's like other people there
that you don't know as well.
I also think like adding in, like I'm not feeling great.
So I'm going to try to come for like an hour
and time bound it is super helpful.
Time bounding is super helpful.
Totally agree.
And that way you don't,
that way when that whatever it is hour, hour
and a half rolls around, you're like, okay guys,
I'm going to head out and people already know
why you're leaving.
I get really uncomfortable when I'm leaving
and people are like, oh, like where are you going?
What's going on?
Like what do you head it to?
And you know, the answer is like my bed.
That's where I'm going.
Home, yeah.
Yeah, that's hard.
I think it's really tricky.
At this point now I'm comfortable being like,
oh, I'm going home.
Like I'm not feeling super great.
And then yeah, it's fine.
But at the beginning it is super hard to do.
Another thing that I think is challenging
or that I struggled with was when I first started
putting up boundaries, I would overindulge, over explain.
You know, I'm not feeling well today
because of blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And practicing not doing that and just saying like,
I don't feel well.
You don't owe anyone a deep explanation
of why you don't feel good
or like what symptoms are the worst today.
You can just say, I'm not feeling well.
And that should be enough.
I think in my ideal world,
I wouldn't even have to say I'm not feeling well.
I would just say I'm in a head home.
I think that, yeah.
Like people should understand and respect and just,
you know, like why do you have to say you're not,
like why is that the only reason that you are allowed
to go home?
So true.
And I think like sometimes the analogies can be helpful
without having to like go too deep.
Like I'm having a low spoon day or my stoplight is out of red.
This is a no go.
Or I'm coasting into a yellow.
We talked about spoon theory in a previous episode,
but I think the spoon analogy is really helpful.
And it's easy to explain to new people as well.
I also really like the stoplight one.
Yeah.
I think that's what the stoplights.
It's like green, yellow, red.
So like green is like, I'm good to go.
Yellow being, you know, caution,
pursuit of caution.
Like I may or may not make it throughout this whole thing.
And then red is like, I have hit my limit
and I can't do it anymore right now.
Absolutely.
That's the analogy I actually would use at work
with my coworkers.
Okay.
And it was super helpful of like,
here's how much you can expect from me in any given day.
I love a good analogy.
It makes you not have to think about the words to use.
I think they make it easier
and they make it, they make the other person more receptive
instead of feeling like, oh, I did something wrong.
Yeah.
Or, you know, like making them feel uncomfortable.
I think it just, it just makes it easier for both parties.
Absolutely agree.
Yep.
What about like hosting friends?
Cause that one is hard letting someone into your home,
having them have access to like really see you potentially
at really low points, carving out time to be like,
you're going to have to entertain yourself
for a little bit right now cause I got to go lay down.
Like how the hell do you get comfortable doing that?
I've like definitely fallen asleep when people are over.
So I think, yeah.
Like I've gotten way too comfortable
with hosting at home that I'm just like,
I'm in IPJs, I'm on the couch.
I love that.
If I knock out then, you know,
you can either be here when I wake up
or I'll feel a little uncomfortable
but also laugh about it later.
Please watch me sleep.
It depends like what the combo of meds I'm on,
what my treatments are.
Like currently knock on wood,
I'm like feeling decent amount of energy.
And so that wouldn't be happening.
But how I try to maintain that is like,
so normally when people are coming over,
I will like cook, I will have snacks out.
I will, you know,
I'll have a whole like hosting situation going on.
Now I don't do that anymore.
As much as I want to,
I just tell myself like it's just not going to go well.
I will have like negative spoons afterwards.
And I tend to order in a lot more instead of cooking.
Or if I do end up cooking,
it's like something very simple.
And it doesn't take a lot of like,
it doesn't take a lot of energy
as far as like me cutting things
and standing up for a long period of time.
So I think my limit is like a 30 minute cook time.
And if I can't keep it under 30 minutes,
then I'll order something.
I love that's a great rule to hold yourself to.
Yeah.
A really great rule.
Cause I think it is like,
it's a exercise in self-control of like,
I'm not going to be my normal me
of cleaning everything frantically
and making sure everything is making everything nice
as Durinda says on Bravo.
Like just accepting that.
Make it nice.
Just accepting that like this is good enough
because ultimately like your friends just want to see you.
Like they don't give a shit if there's shoes out
or you need a vacuum or something.
I know that one has been really hard for me
because I'm very like my house has always kind of looked
like a model house, model home, whatever they're called.
And so I have learned,
I have had to learn just let it be.
I think one other thing is like,
when you get more comfortable with your friends,
you like really can do anything.
This weekend we had one of Cooper's friends visiting
and usually if it's one of Cooper's friends,
I want to still like be very engaged
and be a part of everything,
but I gave myself permission to be like,
I'm going to let them have time together.
And I don't feel well.
So I'm going to go outside and read my book for six hours
and that's okay.
Yeah.
And what they're right friends,
they are okay with that.
Yeah.
I also feel like,
do you feel like you've gotten to a point
where you just don't really care?
Yes.
Very much so.
Yeah.
I'm like really close to getting there,
which is I'm really excited for it.
Me too.
Because I remember when you first got sick
and would host people, you'd be like,
do you think it's okay if I leave the dinner table
and I'd be like,
hell yes, go to your room, prioritize you,
but it's uncomfortable.
Like same with me when I first got sick.
It's uncomfortable to be like, bye.
Yeah.
I think the reason I feel uncomfortable
is that I associate it with like,
like when you're not sick
and you're just leaving a social hangout
because like you don't want to be there.
It feels like that.
Yeah.
And this is not bad.
This is like, you have a legit reason
to not be there.
And so to get up from a dinner table,
to get up from the living room and be like,
I'm going to go rest now guys.
If you're not welcomed with everyone,
like cheering you on basically,
like got to change up that circle a little bit
or communicate to them that I need some like excitement
when I'm leaving the room.
Yes.
Gas me up fam.
I think like one tip that's really helped me
is when I am in those situations.
And if I do start having some like negative self talk
about feeling guilt or like this internalized ableism
that I'm only leaving cause I don't want to be there.
I have, I remind myself like one,
the normal amount of pain is zero pain.
No one else at this table is in stage six pain right now.
Yeah.
Two, I run through my diagnoses in my brain
and I'm like, you have XYZ, ABC.
That's enough to not, to like,
to be able to prioritize yourself every single time.
And then the last thing that I do is, okay,
if this was be at the table and she needed to do this,
I would be encouraging her to go.
Yeah.
Completely.
And like have that same respect for yourself.
Yeah.
I also, another thing that I have found is useful
is because I usually like overdo it.
I like having time limits for myself is really good.
So I will just put an alarm or like a timer on my phone.
And be like one hour, one and a half hour, two hours,
whatever it is.
And when the timer goes off,
regardless of if I'm like still like feeling good,
it's like, I know that that tipping point is about to come.
It's for a reason.
So it's for a reason.
So I will go ahead and start saying my goodbyes and head out.
That's such a, I'm gonna, I'm gonna take that.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
I really, really like that.
Because to push yourself, yeah, like why wait until like,
you're like, okay, now I'm done.
Yeah. It's like the same with pain.
Like why wait until you're in too much pain?
Stay ahead of the spoon count.
Stay ahead of the pain.
Like we know these things.
Yeah.
Totally.
And then I also like, like you and I do this,
we'll text each other like, do you think it's okay?
And sometimes you just need the validation to be like, yeah,
you just need your friend to tell you that it's okay.
And that's also all right.
Exactly.
I've never been met with someone saying,
no, I think you should stay there longer.
Or like, no, I think someone would find that rude.
I've always been welcomed with like,
yes, of course, like you can head home.
Like you shouldn't even think twice about it.
Yeah.
But sometimes it's nice hearing it from a friend.
Your friend who wants you to go home.
Yeah.
Find your home body friend.
Okay. Maybe the last thing we talk about is like,
how do you meet new friends and like expand your friend circle
when you are sick and kind of going through this resettling?
Yeah. I think that has actually been such a surprise.
Like the new friends that I've made.
Yes.
I've made friends through joining like online support communities,
which has been really nice.
They're not necessarily in my area,
but like we're friends over FaceTime or phone calls.
And they're either, you know,
diagnosed with a cancer themselves
or they're supporting someone with cancer.
And so I have found that really beneficial.
Also like through my social networks,
like friends of friends.
Yes.
That have gone through something similar,
like getting closer to them.
And I think friends that were in my outer circles
who have family that's going through something like this,
like I've gotten closer to them too.
That totally makes sense.
It's like you can share a language with them
that you can't candidly with other people.
And it allows you to get kind of deeper
and be more authentic and honest
about like how you're really doing, I think.
Yeah, completely.
How has it been for you?
I think similar.
I was surprised that once I became okay
with saying like I am sick, I'm autoimmune.
These are my diseases.
I found it was easier to find people
that wanted to support someone like me
or wanted to share in that level.
And like the, like you were saying,
like the online support communities,
it is mind boggling to me that 15 of my like dear,
dear, dear friends, I've met one of them in person.
Wow, that's crazy.
And that's like my ladies who autoimmune friend group.
Yeah, yeah.
And they're the people that I would like turn to
for a lot of things in life and show up
and speak my language.
So I think like giving yourself the permission
to make new friends, even though that's scariest shit
when you're an adult is like really scary.
Yes.
It's so worth it.
But I feel like, I feel like with adult friendships
you at least, you pretty much know right away
whether it's someone that you're going to be close with.
It isn't 20 hangouts to get there.
No.
And you're also not like drinking at a bar,
not really talking about life.
Yeah, like you're having deep conversations
pretty much upfront.
Yeah.
I totally agree.
That's awesome.
Yeah.
Wonderful.
Well, that's kind of, it's kind of the gist with friends.
Yeah.
It's amazing.
It's fine.
Hopefully you guys found that helpful.
I think it's, I think it's just like,
it's something that you pick up over time.
You have to navigate your different friendships and.
Finding like your voice,
finding your voice on how to tell people
how you need them to show up,
how to set your boundaries.
There's a lot of like sell.
Like however much this is other people, it's also you.
Yes.
Maybe I would love for people to slide into our DMs
this week and like tell us their friendship story,
like friendship horror stories,
friendship superhero stories.
I think there's a lot of like healing that gets done
when you say like, was this a bad experience?
Like was that person a bad friend?
And people are like, yeah.
It's nice to get that validation externally.
So yeah, slide into your DMs, let us know your stories.
And we will talk to you guys next week.
Love you guys.
Bye.
Love you.
Thanks for listening to another episode
of the Not So Sick Chicks.
Remember new episodes drop every Monday.
Subscribe and rate five stars.
And of course, send this to a friend who is a sick chick
trying to be a little less sick.
We're all in this together.
Follow us on socials at the Not So Sick Chicks.
And we'll see you next week.