Hi, I'm Bysma, and you're listening to the other seabird, a podcast about all things
cancer from a stage four breast cancer warrior. We cover health and wellness, mind body and soul.
Plan to leave each episode with hopefully some new insights and inspiration.
Let's get into this week's episode.
Welcome back everyone! Today we are going to be getting the perspective of fellow
cancer warrior and driver. I'm thrilled to be joined by Alyssa Calver.
Alyssa like me is living with stage four metastatic breast cancer.
And we talk about making lemonade out of lemons. Her journey definitely comes to mind.
She is on an empowering mission to help others feel supported and comfortable during their
own cancer treatments on top of managing her own. Alyssa has founded a non-profit called
we got this, which supports cancer drivers through personalized gift-rich streets.
We'll get all into that a little bit later, but first Alyssa, welcome to the pot.
Thank you so much for being here. Thank you. So excited to meet you and chat more.
Yeah, absolutely. So I'm really happy that we're going to hear about your journey. So why don't we
start off and if you want to just give us a little intro about yourself and maybe even see it
up with like what was your life like before you got diagnosed and then I want to hear the whole
diagnosis story as well. Absolutely. So before getting diagnosed, I just celebrated 11 years
with my husband Eric and my whole career was mainly in sales and financial services. I was a
financial advisor and had a short stint of about four years running a cardio boxing gym and I
actually got really actively involved in leukemia and phoma society and team of training,
team and training the past about eight years doing marathons and triathons and really cool stuff
immersed in the cancer community, which really came back with so much love tenfold when I
ended up in this club myself and it was really interesting of course, you know, I've breast cancer
but a lot of my initial support really came from LLS and fellow friends in that in the early
stages where that was really all I knew of people having cancer so close to me. So transitioning
of it once I had the diagnosis, I feel like I've taken a lot of who I was before cancer and
channeled that into this new mission really kind of bringing in everything I've done throughout my career
and throughout my life in order to do something that really I feel so connected to now.
So I guess I was diagnosed with stage four breast cancer July of 2021 so it's just past three years now.
One day yeah I've been so I had my daughter in June of 2020 sorry July of 2020 and obviously
a lot going on at that time and after I had her I started having a lot of weird things happening
throughout my body nothing in my breasts but things like my feet going numb I was feeling really
off, achy all sorts of things as I was easing back into like normal life and I got a lot of things
checked out went to specialists and essentially you know the story unfortunately you hear a lot of
them kind of dismissing that to the fact that I had had a baby within the year. Right finally and I
had gone to every specialist and so I had had a breast exam everything felt normal a couple months
after that breast exam I had and again there was nothing near my breast it was just I was checking
every box of medical life of my body. My husband jokingly copped a fuel one morning when I was
getting dressed grateful that he he's still in love with me that much and felt something a bit off
and I hadn't felt it before we didn't feel in the breast exam and now it's when I got it checked out
and it was pretty wild that that lump we hadn't even felt before then ended up being metastatic
breast cancer that's crazy so were you breastfeeding during this time not during the time
I had been previously but hadn't been still and I'm very grateful at that time just coincidentally
then I wasn't because it very much felt like a clogged milk duct and interesting that I would have
most likely dismissed it I also would worry that the doctors would have to you know it's very hesitant
to do scans and things on breastfeeding women yeah so my initial thought was oh maybe it is like
an old clogged milk duct or assist and luckily I did just message the doctor I figured
easy enough to figure this out and when I went in I had I did not think that I had cancer like
even after they felt the lump in my breast they felt one of my armpit and in hindsight that's not
good but at the time I had no idea so they felt it in my armpit as well we did the mammogram
ultrasound biopsies and then it was after that that I got the call that both the biopsies were
malignant and then it wasn't until the pet scan that I found out it had it had also spread to my
liver and my lower spine and this was the first time of me visually seeing and understanding
that like I had breast cancer but more cancer my liver than I even had in my breast and that's where
there's just so much that I've learned in the past few years about metastatic breast cancer that
I never would have understood and it still is kind of counterintuitive to what we would think
you know that it's I don't have liver cancer I have breast cancer that had spread to my liver
right yeah there's so much confusion around that I know so when I got diagnosed they just told me
you have metastatic cancer and so they had to go back and figure out where it was originating from
and I didn't even know what the word metastatic met so I was like I thought it was a type of cancer
and so mine had spread to my spine so I was like maybe it's a cancer of the spine or like a bone
cancer so it took me like some education to understand like that just means that it's spread and you
have to figure out where it's come from but in your situation they biopsied the lump and your armpit
first and figured out it was breast cancer and then they saw the liver and the spine yeah so the
breast and the armpit so kind of knowing that it was originating from the breast and got back
then that it was her two positive ER impure negative and and with metastatic like you're saying
you know I started looking at Facebook groups and other things to start learning about
stuff that was happening and seeing people say things like I had met here met some my bone I'm like
what are met you I didn't understand what any of it was and I try to remember that as we talk
about it now because I remember I didn't know if that was three years ago most people who don't
have to know what it is probably don't either yeah I thought people were saying nets I was like I don't
know yeah I honestly was like also weird and confusing every playing basketball after or what did you
remember like how did you feel emotionally like what was going through your head at that time you
just like had your daughter and like seems like you know a brand new chapter of life like what did
you feel it was of course shocking but I had gone through this whole year of feeling like something
was wrong and so I felt not crazy anymore you know I felt like validated but I wish I wasn't validated
in that way so it was a lot of really confusing feelings when I got the phone call of the initial
biopsy results it was a really surreal because it was the radiologist who did the biopsies wasn't
in that day which it kind of knew an advance she had warned me of that that I might get the results
you know and I remember saying after the biopsies like do you have any hunches or that I mean I
really didn't think I had cancer and she was like yeah I don't like to make any assumptions
you know or say and I'm like in my head I'm like oh yeah I don't have cancer but right now looking
back it's like oh she totally knew that I did she knew I'm just kidding now I know because you know
they tell us a little bit more now that we're like more veteran cancer people yeah yeah but
at the time I remember I picked up the phone I was doing my makeup for work meeting I had at the
time and I remember just kind of looking at myself in the mirror as I'm like talking to the
radiologist and I remember him saying both the biopsies came back and unfortunately they were
malignant and I just like pause it was like so are you telling me that I have breast cancer
and he's like yes and they didn't he didn't have any other information at that time so it was
literally just getting a phone call it was a Friday so I knew that if I didn't get more information
by the end of the day I wasn't going to till Monday so I really pushed hard to find out more
luckily I have people in my family and circle of friends in the medical field who kind of told
me which questions to push and ask for so it was able to get on the phone with the surgeon
I was with Kaiser at the time and they have you meet with the surgeon before the young
collegeist okay doesn't make too much sense to me especially since I've never met her again
and I've never needed a surgeon since but yeah it was kind of odd but she was she was great and she
answered a lot of my questions and that was when I found out when she called me back a few hours later
I remember it was on speaker my mom was visiting at the time we had been running out to run an
air and when she called and it was when she said like we're going to do more tests and scans but
you know will for sure start off with about you know six to eight rounds of chemo it'll be about
you know a few months and that's when everything was like oh like I like have cancer like
not that it's not if not just like all the stereotypes that you picture and see like that started flooding
into my mind and realizing that this is something that is totally of course life changing no matter
what but then it wasn't until we saw the pet scan results and all the lights up when I'm like
am I dying you know like yeah these are things that you know and then after my initial chemo
about four months in with her septid and progetta ended up having a recurrence in my breast and in my
brain and again you're like am I dying like these are things that we hear in life and depending on
the type of cancer in the situation it's so different I've never understood how vague the word cancer is
until having yeah yeah absolutely and I think I mean honestly like you're giving me chills like saying
this like it's just really like I I can like totally picture myself and you know how you're describing
it and the scenario and it's just the word cancer is weird because like for me like what's like
before having cancer you just hear like people get cancer and people get better you hear that and
then you also hear people die from cancer right so you hear both sides of the spectrum and then
I think when you get diagnosed and you don't have an early stage diagnosis you have a late stage
diagnosis it's so scary right because like it does feel like I mean people only die from stage
for right so that is obviously a very normal natural thought is that am I going to die and I feel
like doctors try to shield you from the truth right because they want to be positive and they're like
no we've got these treatments and like we're going to do this but I mean at the end of the day they
don't know how you're going to respond to it and so I think that fear of like am I going to die
is like very normal and natural and sadly just you know it is that that's a scenario that you're in.
I think that's such a great point to that you said with you know that they're trying to like be
careful and they don't know how you're going to react so sometimes you don't know like are you
putting on kid gloves for me or is this okay and you know after having brain meds
yeah he's in the word meds but after having those and being treated so quickly for them
and having you know as much of a complete response as I could have right now on my brain it's unbelievable
to me like I didn't have brain surgery like through chemo the fact that that can be treated like
I hope that more people can know that because I think a lot of people get so scared about
getting tested because of what the results might be and having the results not be good and having
them feel like saying that I normally would have thought I would like die from but it was something
that was able to be really well treated and I very much live my life now and all that like that's
I'm one of them before yeah that's amazing I mean you're you're outlook on it is like
I followed in Instagram for a while I think probably since I got diagnosed and it's just really
inspirational I just thank you like obviously it's like such a heavy disease and diagnosis
to live with but you're attitude around it is really inspirational just really amazing
but likewise and all the conversations you have and the more that people talk you realize that
we're just it's like a fingerprint we're all so different and yeah even I mean I haven't met
anyone with like exact scenarios but even when you meet people you can relate on a lot of things
I learned so much every conversation I have with someone else yeah absolutely so a lot of so
your receptors are your estrogen progesterone negative and then her two positive right yes yeah okay so
when you and so I'm the opposite I'm estrogen progesterone positive her two negative
opposite to drag you know how does you feel when you heard that because I guess like
I don't know like people are I feel like people are like oh that's a good one and that's a bad one
and you know what did you have any thoughts like that like oh I have a targeted one or I have
not like what did you feel so initially one of the relatives that I spoke to you know because her
two positive did not have a lot of treatments not that long ago so it's kind of told I had a
really really bad one and then and then you know you start learning more in realizing that there
are a lot of targeted therapy so like I'm grateful in the bad scenario that there's targeted
therapies to have I just confused that it wasn't hormone positive I grew up with enemy triosis so
I've been on birth control and treated for enemy triosis since middle school and I was kind of
surprised like that it wasn't hormone related it didn't none of it makes sense and I also have
family history I just I don't have brakna no genetic mutation right I was more so just confused
by what all that meant and then as I learned more I think it still ends up being kind of confusing
because when people say things like this is good or this is bad and then you see someone who passes
away from the thing that someone said was the good one and you start feeling like of course we know
that it all sucks it's just even the scenarios where you feel like oh maybe this is better or this
is I think we always have to remind ourselves that we're all unique and different and having the right
care team and the people to understand that and treat us like that I think is ultimately the most
important thing to not categorize ourselves by those different categories yeah totally I think it's like
I think so many of us get caught up in the stats right so like you're like okay so I've got this type
of cancer and like the stats say this so like I'm gonna be in this bucket but like there's so many
variances within each of the categories and so you know even like my oncologist will tell me like
we just don't know you just have to kind of like stay positive and like we got to just make sure
that we're putting you in the right treatments in the right order and then you kind of just you know
do the most that you can that's in your control as well yeah my initial oncologist you know
and I pushed like I pushed to get stats so it's like because I'm again I'm like am I dying like
what is half of it and I was like can I just get an idea of like where this is at and what you're
trying to tell me and so she was kind of giving me the stats and she's like you know 20%
make it past five years while the average is 18 to 24 months that's very outdated and she
says they'll always remember she said I have patients that are six to seven years out
and I'm like I am 34 you know 37 I was 34 at the time like were you just trying to encourage me
by telling me that I'm gonna live to 40 yeah like it just it stuck with me so much and then
I'm not at Kaiser anymore and I am treated at UCLA I have unbelievable oncologists I had
Dr. Sarah Herwitz initially she went on to do more research and my oncologist now
Dr. Lipstick Sharf is wonderful and I remember when I moved over to Dr. Herwitz and her being like
no no no like you're in the golden age of her two positive breast cancer and we're going to
keep you alive so that we can keep having more treatments for you to stay alive and like yeah this
this the plan is for this to be a chronic disease not a terminal one and now like maybe
you feel like okay regardless of if we're at that point yet or not I want to be with the
care team who believes that and like is that part of figuring that out yeah totally I mean so yeah I was
35 when I got diagnosed and they told me 50% chance of making it to 40 or making it five years
and I was like and they were saying it like a good thing almost like okay so like you've got five
years probably and I was like that's only till 40 like that's so young and that's really not like
a gold post right like that's just not it's not enough life and so I've met with other oncologists
and other doctors and you know gotten told you know those are old stats like that's not the data
like we don't even we're not even quoting data anymore because like the treatments being used
now just haven't been around long enough to know how they're going to do and it's just really
it's hard because you want to like word data people right so we just I am actually I had asked
the hospital at that time I said I want to see the actual data like give me like the Excel spreadsheet
I want to see like you know obviously like blur out the names that I want to see like how old
these people are like what's their prior history and they were like no we don't give out that data
it's just not like that but I wanted to know like where do I actually fall within this data group
but not just here's an average but yeah it's really crazy so it sounds like you had a really
good support system around you can you talk to us a little bit about you know family friends and
how did that play into your support yeah absolutely I mean I'm very grateful and and lucky
to have such a great support system and I think a lot of that like your first question is
they thought about the old Alyssa and knew who I was going to be with cancer of it in terms
of my personality so when I started bringing up you know crazy ideas and things I wanted to do
throughout chemo you know the people really know me didn't bad and I knew that that's I was doing
it so they had to hop on board or I was going to do it anyway yeah and then I'm referring to you know
starting my non-profit and other things throughout but when I was first diagnosed you know the biggest
thing was everyone was asking how they can help and what they could do and it's such a special thing
to know that you have so many people want to help you and that's what I think made it feel like
something I needed to find a solution for because it shouldn't feel like this unintentional burden
like it shouldn't be a negative thing that so many people want to help us and it did feel that way
because I had so much to respond to and I didn't want to ask for help and I wanted them to know
how much I appreciated that they cared and then I thought about the year earlier when I had my daughter
and using baby lest or when I was getting married and having a wedding registry and I feel
comfortable having to go find me for myself and my good friend Amber who now works with me out
we got this she actually did a meal train for us and she put in the notes like if you really want
to make them a meal like let me know and I'll help coordinate she's like but it would really be
most helpful if you just sent gift cards because you know I couldn't taste for weeks at a time
I didn't know what diet I was going to follow all that kind of stuff right so everyone sent
gift cards which was it really was unbelievably helpful because our kitchen was gutted at the time
when I was diagnosed we were doing construction on our house so I never kitchen and it was
really from now I was like there really should be a gift registry for cancer patients a lot
happened in between that of course but it was yeah my like fifth round of chemo when I was just like
this sucks and what am I doing with it and I need to do something and that's when the idea kind
of came about to bring in the community of supporters that want to help and of course you know my
primary caregiver being my husband who that initial time and I talked talked about this before that
we were in the office when we saw the pet scan and you see visually on the screen just they explained
to you that like anything lit up could be cancer and it was just like a sea of lights and that was
when my husband just went white and he was like had to breathe into a paper bag it was like
really having a panic attack and we had no idea how to channel all of this and ever since then
he's just like he got it all out of his system and now he's just really rolled with the punches
and been a part of every step with me the way that I wanted to handle it. The biggest turning point
I think being when I did have the brain mats and I was on and hurt too and to catnip as a part
of a clinical trial and I just really lost my quality of life and it worked so well but making
that decision to make a change was saying that my husband and my parents you know people closest
to us supported and I know that that was really hard for them to support me moving off of a treatment
that was working and because of that I've gone into really live the past two years you know whereas
even though it was working it wasn't working for me in my quality of life and how the people around
you care about all of you not just them getting to be with you is something that I've learned because
I think on the flip side I would have felt like you need to just keep going you know like just keep
doing this because they need you here but being willing to take that chance with me and support
me through that was a huge part of my support team. Yeah that's amazing I totally think that
our family really just you know they they want us to be around right and so that's their biggest goal
but you know I think it's like to to what extent right if you're just miserable and you're not
really functioning then how is that you know you really being around so that's that's amazing that
your family is supportive and your husband was supportive about you getting off of that treatment
how did it go telling your oncologist that like did they take it like we're I mean did they
did they try to encourage you to stay back on it? No and actually in my head I was like why didn't
I mention the sooner because when I did finally I just got to that point you know it was like each
round my husband I would talk and I'd be like I don't know how much longer I can do this like
I couldn't wake up without throwing up that I was taking medicine to stay asleep all day like
I literally wasn't living other than maybe like up to five to seven days every three weeks
in betraying fusions so I'd brought it up a little bit earlier we couldn't lower the dose
because of the fact that I was a part of a clinical trial so even though both drugs were FDA
approved combining them for breast cancer was the trial and I really wanted to stay on that because
again that brain tumors and it was working yeah so when I finally did like say to my oncologist like
I don't know that I want to live like like this like I wake up and I think to myself like living
is too hard like I don't know that I can keep doing this and she's like well then like this isn't
working and I was like what do you mean she's like what's like working like on the cancer but like
that's only half of it like you're a human like you need to live too she's like if you feel that
drastic about this like we need to change it and I didn't realize how many options I knew
that more options existed right but I always kind of thought of it like a cat with eight lives
and you're like knocking off a life yeah it's like you'll just say my right and and that was when
she was like you know you can stay apart of the study if you want but why don't we switch drugs
and that's when I switch to what I've been on now which is Zalota to Katnib and her saptin
and that was kind of comforting that two of the drugs or things I already had and yeah I'm so
grateful that that was her reaction and then she kind of left it to me of being like this is something
you can do now so you just tell me like do you want to try doing this longer because it's working
do you want to just stop and it was towards the end of the year and I was like I'm going to start
the new year trying to take my life back and like I am forever grateful that I did I
had the past couple years what I've gotten to do and live as amazing I do have a little bit
of a potential recurrence right now my left breast but you know we're working through it and
figuring it out and knowing that there's options like that like I knew that right like we kind of
get told that but you don't really feel that until your medical team and your support system
are like on that train with you and so now that we've done that I'm like okay I do believe now
that I have options yeah now that's great I think I always kind of have this
I mean I'm just an anxious person in general but I think I definitely with this like my anxiety
peaks in the sense like I want to know how many options like I'm eye on option like
three of five or is it three of 30 like what's the number and like you don't really get a clear answer
but like there are so many options there's so many different combinations of drugs that you
can take and so I think you know where we are like where medicine is with metastatic breast cancer
right now like there are there are a lot of options and so I think the goal is really to stay
hopeful and also I think to your point it's like if something's not working for you like you should
talk to your cancer care team and let them know that you're miserable because I don't think
like that really isn't the goal like what you're in college just said like it's just because
it's working on the cancer doesn't mean it's working overall for you and if she had said to me like
Alyssa you might die if we stop like if she was really concerned I would have reevaluated maybe
the way I looked at it you know maybe if I knew that that was my only option maybe I would have
been grateful for that five to seven days every three weeks that I lived you know and you
reset maybe what you think that bar is but knowing that she didn't like didn't even hesitate
that this isn't how I had to live you know think that I spoke up and I think that's the the
biggest thing you know she just didn't fully get how much I was struggling and you know and that's
also because I I try not to like I want to be happy and live but yes speaking up is important just
like speaking up if you feel something that's all yeah do you ever feel like I've gotten better
about this but I think initially I was not scared of my oncologist but a little bit like okay like
I want to be a really good patient and like you know listen to everything they're saying but I think
I've kind of learned that you know we're on a team together me and the oncologist it's not
them you know telling me what to do it's them telling me options of what I can do and then it's my you
know it's my decision at the end of the day what I want to do with it yeah my oncologist Dr
Herbert at the time was director of clinical trials from UCLA and so every time I'd be offered
something I would always have the option of a clinical trial like after I got off of in her to
into catnip I was offered to be on a clinical trial for something else and reviewing it it didn't
feel like as good of a fit for me so I chose not to do it but yeah having those options really
I felt like in general having a medical team where they recommend something or they give you
those options and while I always still have more conversations and do more research in general
I like really trust my team so initially I didn't and when they would say things or other things
I'd kind of feel like I'd need to do so much more research because not like it didn't trust them but
I didn't feel like I had all the resources at my disposal and now that I do it makes it a lot easier
to feel like okay I want to be the good patient I want them to love me but also want to like
make the choice that feels best and having the choices laid out for you already give you the confidence
that like who's giving them really cares and understands the full spectrum what's available
has like changed that perception for me yeah I think that's really important when you were at Kaiser
did you ask like you know are you guys part of any clinical trials do you have any connections to them
or was that not something that was on your radar at that point so the initial chemo felt really
straightforward to me so it didn't feel like that was necessary but even given that so like I started
out with TCHP so it was taxiture carbo plan her sets an impurgent and then when I got I didn't
get a second opinion at first I also I mean I did like I made phone calls and things but what
happened being in the heat of COVID and so much else going on I actually started chemo before
I met my oncologist it was very out of the ordinary but if I wanted to wait to meet the oncologist
I was going to have to wait in additional month for chemo and I just wasn't willing to do that so I
started the first year rounds with TCHP and then once the dust kind of settled I actually got a
second opinion within Kaiser and I ended up switching oncologists within Kaiser and I really liked
my second oncologist if I didn't have the opportunity at UCLA to switch I would have been happy
with her okay she immediately switched my chemo to THP she's like you don't need carbo plan
and you know your cancer is not curative like we don't need to blast you harder than necessary
and it's not like adding in the carbo plan and it was like gonna kill me but I was
getting I was throwing up more I was having a lot more severe symptoms and like even that little
tweak made me realize early on like this matters like who's helping you matters that my
original oncologist wasn't up to speed on like the current golden standard of care
right but she's prescribed me was fine it wasn't like malpractice or anything it's just it wasn't
necessary I also think that the initial oncologist took my direction as a patient
like too much like didn't educate me so I go in right like I'm a former athlete you know and
all it like hit me with whatever we got like take my breath do whatever you have to do like let's go
as aggressive as possible and then you learn like oh removing my breasts isn't going to benefit
me for metastatic breast cancer and yeah all that but I think that she took so literally my
like willingness that she made it as aggressive as it could be and I think she said that after
and I did switch is like why do we add that I've not actually you said you wanted to be aggressive
and I felt like I wasn't given the full information the lay of the land yeah I think that's like
one I mean I get I'm sure you do too I get asked so many questions like on constant or on repeat
one of them is definitely like you know why don't they take the original lump out like why don't
you have surgery like since mine is hormone driven I'm on hormone targeted treatment and said I
just like IV chemo overall right now and so I get a lot of those questions and it's a lot of educating
people and you know that's on how it's done but it also you know it's those are valid questions
and it's still hard to grasp that with metastatic you know you taking out the original source
is not going to overall like systemically help your cancer if it's already spread you have to
treat the body as a whole um did you grasp like have trouble grasping that concept yourself
initially that you weren't going to have a surgery to remove the tumor yeah such a good
question yeah I can so relate to everything that you're saying and initially when it was explained
to me I was like okay understand like we can't remove part of my spine we can't remove my whole
liver yeah that piece made sense and then recently like just a few months ago when we found
more tumors in my left breast that ended up being the same cancer that's when I was like okay
so do we remove my breast now like it's contained should we remove it and even my oncologist was like
let's let's have you meet with the surgeon and let's talk it out and so I did and she was like
she was like again from your scans like there's a lot of little tumors in there like so if we
did a lump back to me what are we taking out are we taking out all of those like we can't
do you want to do biopsies and all those like you know and then as a whole can we just remove them
and she's like if we remove them the amount of time that you're going to have to pause your
chemo right now is so much more dangerous than cancer in your breast right it was such a good reminder
of um and I did uh I messaged Dr. De Plinsky about this if you follow her as well
love her and I was like can you help me articulate this because I'm answering it so much
to do like as well as I did a post together about it and yeah even watching her explain it which again
I was the one who reached out to ask her to explain like I still needed that reminder and like I still
do I sometimes look back to it because I'm like yes that's why like we can't remove my brain
you know right at the end of the day if I'm not going to die from cancer my brows then
why risk the rest of my body getting infiltrated yeah now I think that's an important point so it's like
if you're listening and the clarification I think is like so when you have a surgery you have to
stop your chemo or your hormone treatments whatever other treatments you're on because your
your immune system needs that time to recover from the surgery and you can't double up on doing
chemo and a surgery at the same time so you would be off of your systemic treatment while you're
recovering from surgery and a lot of times the thought process there is like that time off of your
treatment is more problematic and more you know bad for your body than taking out that tumor and so
it's you know it's just something I have to remind myself of of as well yeah me too like even
saying it I'm like yeah don't do that I remember seeing you posted about having back pain I
know a message to you about that and that's been on an often issue for me throughout treatment and
it's something most recently that I mean we did like I was in MRIs for like three hours to do
all the parts my back we just wanted to make sure like hundred percent there's no cancer there and
there's not yeah um that's all it's it which is great greatness but it's still like a debilitating
symptom which I think might have to do with my enemy triosis growing back now that I'm not treating
that and so I am voluntarily scheduling a hysterectomy leaving my ovaries since I don't need to go
through early metapause since I'm not hormone positive okay and that's something that I wanted to
do a couple years ago that with the brain tumors they're like let's not do electrosurgies but that's
really like weighing things out so like the hysterectomy would be just a couple weeks off of you know
probably just missing the two catnip wouldn't even maybe even have to miss my chemo pill I wouldn't
have to miss receptin but that's where like having those conversations that was something we said
wouldn't make sense a couple years ago I brought up again and we kind of talked it through and it
could make sense now so like also not being afraid to ask those questions like even me asking again
like should I just do a dull mastectomy now what did it take off our time right in extra appointment
for me to totally understand it and feel comfortable again yeah absolutely so do you have
you made a decision yet on do you want to go forward with the hysterectomy or you still considering
that I I have decided to go forward with it it's just a timing thing trying to do it sooner than
later because we're also waiting to do another breast MRI to I'm on like pause with we don't want
to change my treatment because everything else is working like my brain might start growing back
there's nothing in my liver anywhere else so there honestly it's a little confused like why
more grew my breast and I think that they were kind of expecting it to look different maybe
it would be fine positive or different breast cancer right and since it's also her too positive
it's confusing and my options were like that we could do a breast MRI guided biopsies
or wait and the surgeon was like honestly I really don't want to put you through the
breast MRI biopsies for us to probably just find out the same info again so in a month I'm
getting another breast MRI so I think once we do that we'll just evaluate the timing and
make sure I don't need to be like urgently switch to something but for now I'm continuing on my
current chemo and it's working everywhere else so they feel comfortable that like other than this
one weird question mark that like I am mostly stable and it's working good that's awesome
one thing I just popped in so for my back so I have metastasis all like all over my spine
all over my pelvic bones my ribcage sternum it's like literally my entire yeah so when you talk
about scans lighting up like when I get mine and the screens there it's just like all lit up
but one thing I do get on a monthly basis is this injection called XGPA have you heard of that?
no I'm not familiar with that okay so it's like this bone strengthening agent and it helps
like if there is like weakness like fracture or like fractures possibly coming or metastasis in
your bone so I wonder for you if that's an option yeah so look into that what's the other
um infusion brain I'm you sorry bone medicine um oh my god I'm blanking I get it like that
few months is it Zometa or Zometa yeah Zometa yeah it's got similar a different injection
it's similar I think it's the same like base ingredient so yeah if you're getting that it has that
do you have have you noticed any difference in your bones from that or no I've been getting it the whole
so yeah so the the pain I'm getting I don't know it feels more muscular like it but I know
the difference like and I was doing physical therapy for so long and all that it wasn't fixing it
but yeah I'll definitely ask about that too thank you yeah so you um so you're I also used to work
out of time before I got diagnosed it's something that I missed doing because I used to go to like
high intensity classes and do like boxing and do all of that so I've had to you know change how I
do my workouts now but I like really do believe like to help with that bone pain if you can like
strengthen the muscles around it that can really help alleviate like the weight that goes on your
bones have you found like any like particular types of workouts that you have found beneficial
yeah I mean definitely boxing um because it also helps of course like strengthening my core and
all that from my back um and I just I've always like boxing and a boxing gym and also I just feel
like it's such a low risk unless you're actually fighting but it's a low risk workout you know
like you're getting cardio with strength training you know from the resistance um I also have gone
really into golf since being diagnosed I used to play tennis a lot and I still play tennis but it was
very high impact like well really well starting chemo and getting used to all that it's still kind of
is but um with golf like really moving my body and being outdoors for a long time and all that
I've found to be really helpful as well oh okay awesome my husband's a big golfer so maybe I'll
join him yeah let me know I'll come up north and uh we can all be happy awesome so one thing that
I've like seen on your social media is like you you use them or you use the word driver instead of
like living with or like just surviving I want to hear a little bit about like your mindset
what makes you want to use that word and like embrace the cancer versus and treat it like
more like a chronic illness than just being like a terminal diagnosis. I first heard the term
driver being like through metaviver and metastatic patients you know talking about it and I thought
about the word survivor and driver together and before having cancer someone would like ask how
your day's going or something like that you'd be like oh it's all right like I'm surviving
I never felt like survival was my goal as a human without cancer and so I felt like making that
the accomplishment with cancer was minimizing us as humans like I don't think there's anything wrong
with them not offended by the word survivor anything like that it's just not my goal like it wasn't
my goal before cancer it's not my goal now like I hope that I'm alive like that's bare minimum
but to actually live life that's where I feel like that's where I identify more worth
arriving because I feel then I really felt that when I was on and her too and I felt like I didn't know
how I could continue to live I knew that I wasn't dying because it was working so well in my
cancer but I also was really in touch with the fact that I wasn't living and being in touch with
thought and embracing the fact that that is just as important was so important for me to get to live
again so that's why I really just think that living with cancer, thriving, not just staying
alive and surviving is really the goal there definitely days where I'm just surviving right like we
all are so like I always try to stress like you don't have to start a non-profit during chemo like
you don't have you know like it would have been fine if I just wanted to learn how to golf and golf
every day you know like yeah do what makes sense and feels good for you but I hope that people you
value themselves enough to not take you know other people's pressure or perception of cancer
and minimize whatever it is that they want to live in their life. Yeah totally I think it's like
it's such a personal journey I know like the first year I had met a static I was just I would say
I was just like trying to survive I was just trying to get through and I didn't really want
cancer to define me like I didn't really see myself as being someone that was going to be like
I've got cancer and like I'm doing you know X, Y and Z I just didn't think that was like a part of
my personality and then something hit around like the one year mark where I was just I don't know
if it was like this real fear set in I've like I don't know if I'm gonna make it I already switched
treatments a couple of times and I think I just had this like wake up moment where I was like
I have to do something I have to do something beyond just like the minimum to get by it's it's
it was more than just like doing my treatments like I needed to just take a little bit of control
and be more proactive in my healing journey and that's where I started doing a lot more like
I started meditating a lot I started looking a lot more until like my diet nutrition
exercises and you know doing more advocacy stuff and connecting with people in the community and I
think that shift of the last like this past year and now it's like I feel like I'm thriving now
because I'm just more you know a part of it I'm embracing it and I'm not just trying to get by any more
yeah I love that are there any terms that like you don't like in particular or like more than
others in in that realm of the thriving surviving stuff so I think yeah thriving so like those are
fine I think one thing that really always works mean I don't know if you feel this way is that when
people are like be strong like I just don't really to me it's like a really silly thing to say
it's like we don't really have a choice like I have to just get through this and so I think
people like stay strong be strong or um I also don't really love when people like keep fighting
I think that one for some reason or excuse me as well what about for you or doing it those
resonate yeah I mean for the most part I've kind of taken this lens of like I feel like not everything
has to be a teaching moment so like I've had people say some pretty messed up things you know
like especially when you're bald and you don't have a choice of whether or not people know you have
cancer yeah and in a lot of people when like friends they'll tell it to they'll be like why
didn't you say sign I'm like because I didn't want to like I didn't want to have that conversation
so like I was gonna do to myself but um the biggest thing is like I've made this whole thing
around the mission of we got this so I do think it's funny and if anyone do this it's like not a big
deal nothing offense me but it's funny when people will still comment sometimes on some of my posts
or say to me in person like you're so strong you got this and that like to me is just funny because
yeah especially when it's like very well-intentioned people and people who are morally really
support what I'm doing in my mission but like that's the biggest thing with we got this is like you
know it's not meant to be corny it like I truly feel it wholeheartedly that yeah I would always say
I got this like when I was diagnosed and I was telling like when I had to tell my husband at first
I got the call like by myself and I'm like it's okay like I got this like I'll do whatever I have to do
and it felt so weird saying that and then people saying you got this it's like kind of removing
themselves like you got it you know yeah so it's okay not everyone like has to be actively on my team
but I really I think it's a we thing to me it just feels much better so I just think it's funny
because like that's been my thing so when people best it's like um when people reply to an email
and they spell your name wrong which I'm sure you like it does to me it's like no it's right there
like my email literally you literally right I don't think like it depends like what what
day or like what time of the day you catch me like it maybe just be like a well-intentioned comment
but like if I'm not feeling good and someone's like says something like that to me that I'm just like
like that's not what I want to hear right now but like another day where I'm like feeling fine and like
out and about I'll be like oh yes like I can do this too so it just really it depends and I think
it's always important to remember like people are well-intentioned and so um you know just don't always
know the right thing to say at the right time yeah I think that were really conditioned to feel like
we need cures for things and that's saying that I really feel a lot is like I don't mind you know
opinions on nutrition and fitness like that's been a huge part of my life like forever but what
what does bother me is seeing things like posts or like when celebrities come out with certain
alternative things some can be good some not and it's very misleading on that like not everything
has to cure cancer like we don't just need to eat healthy because it'll prevent your cancer
like there's also things we can do because we want to like live comfortably and like you know like
if like you don't have to do cardio to have fat loss but you might want to do cardio to like have
a healthy heart so that like finding the end not the or like I you know I do chemo I take
meds if I need them but I also go to acupuncture regularly from my back too you know it doesn't
have to be one or the other like we can do multiple things and both can be true yeah absolutely I
mean I'm like big into like juicing right like I have a blender full of like juice like throughout
the day and people then you read some posts and people like oh like that's all like garbage like
it's not gonna cure cancer and I'm like I I don't think it's curing my cancer but I know it's making
me feel better and like if my immune system is stronger I think that overall is gonna help me
fight whatever disease it is that I have and so I think it's like you don't have to look for the
cure quote unquote but just find things that make you feel good and if you're physically feeling
better and mentally feeling better that's overall gonna help you with whatever's going on your body
yeah I couldn't agree more my I love juicing too um yeah I'm not gonna like quit chemo and only
juice just like personally that's not what I think will keep me alive but I definitely love having
juice and make me feel good absolutely okay so I want to get into your nonprofit um tell us like
you spoke a little bit about like when you were going through chemo and you were thinking through like
what would be helpful for you what was kind of like that pivotal point that you were like I'm
gonna actually start an organization and get this out there. I started looking into everything
that already existed so it's like if something like this exists I don't want to recreate the
wheel I don't want to cause any competition or anything I'll just help with that and when I realized
that nothing like it did exist that's when I felt like really mission driven like okay this should
and how often do we really find something that we see such a need for that there's nothing like it
there was something similar at the time that doesn't exist anymore but it was like a registry
for cancer patients for profit run by doctors selling stuff in their own inventory for like medical
supplies and it was really seeing that that I was like this really needs to exist because that
platform the way that they did it which again doesn't even exist anymore because it didn't work
it felt so predatory to me like you know trying to sell things in the perception of
all this stuff and so I looked at a lot of research into it and there are lots of great for
profit companies that are so mission driven and that was saying I explored was in my mind I was like
I just want this to start as soon as it can I just wanted to exist so what's the path
the least resistance that I can do and so I looked into like venture funding and other things
if it were a for profit I looked into how I would fundraise if you were nonprofit and ultimately
I was like well I can have the most control and I can just go figure this out if I make the nonprofit
and that felt good to me and that everyone could feel like there was no company or people trying
to profit off of their symptoms and their side effects like really making it whole you know it's
my life's mission it's what I feel I wish I had so I started to go fund me for it so that's when
I did use go fund me and yeah enough friend of mine out here you know luckily I'm in LA and I have
a lot of really talented film friends and all that and my friend Alicia came over and we just I
just started talking I didn't script any of it I just heard like spitballing this idea and we made
the go fund me video out of it and I was gonna make the goal like 10 to 20 thousand which I thought was
a lot of money and start talking to friends like in tech and in web design all stuff and they're like
a list of like you can't do a gift registry for that amount of money and they're like you need
at least like 50 to 100 thousand to like get started on something this robust because it was
really important to me that you could register for anything so like we weren't just gonna have like
one API set up or one vendor we weren't doing it in house like you can register for literally
anything on the internet okay yeah so yeah so I so I was gonna do 10 thousand and my friend Brian
jokes now because he was like yeah I think you should do that and add a zero to it and so it was like
okay but I was like fair warning I'm not in a position right now to be able to fail like it will
kill me if I fail right so I'm like I'm going for it but like if we come short of that like give me
raise 30 40 thousand I would have felt like oh I got so much money but I would have been like we
missed the goal by so much yeah me let's just say we launched it we ended up raising 105 thousand off
the go find me and it was what was so unbelievable about it was of course that like instantly we
got started you know we've created this I feel in record time whereas if I had gone the investment
route maybe in five years something would have existed if it ever existed at all yeah and the proof
of of concepts like of course there's a certain amount of people who would just donate because
they care about me and believe in what I'm trying to do but there were a lot of people who
started donating that I didn't know who like sought from other people and I started realizing like
okay it's not just me like it's and it's not just cancer patients or survivors or thrivers
it's people who support them that want this too and that's when it all kind of changed me of like
that's why this is so important and so we've been fully funded up until now through peer to
peer fundraising fundraisers and all that I have more of a team now and it's not sustainable for
me to run so many events per year so we're starting to apply for more grants and trying to get
more larger donors and things but the way it's come together has been so bootstrapped like
community driven that it feels so good because I know that every like it is the we like everyone
is a part of it absolutely I was like I mean I worked in like many corporate jobs and I've always
just found like there's you know there's there's always like a mission statement at companies right
and so you read those mission statements but I never actually like felt aligned with them and I think
what you're doing for example like it sounds like everyone that's working there is like so into your
mission and that's exactly what you want right you want everyone there to be like this is what my
life's calling is and this is why I want to be here and I think to your point it's like it's not just
about if you yourself have cancer like so many other people are touched by it like whether it's family
or friends and I think all of us like if you don't have cancer yourself like you know someone who
has cancer and so there's such a like wide group of people that are like mostly everyone is affected
by this in some way definitely and yeah it makes me so grateful that I took the leap to get it
started still a leap I mean I don't pay myself and I've really prioritized just growing it and you
know like like you said I mean my team now Amber Sarah and Jillian who work with me they care as much
as I do and that's so rare to find and then the amount of endless volunteers and people involved
we did not dead yet fast if you saw that with Chelsea from all your so tough and you know so many
other nonprofits that we partner with that's like what I was saying earlier my career was
always about partnerships you know mainly sold 401k which you know it's important but this is
way more fun but when I did 401k all of my clients came through other financial advisors referral
CPAs things like that and it's essentially what you know I'm still doing now is partnering
with other nonprofits like for not dead yet fast leukemia lymphoma society where partners
teen cancer America you know all these other great non-profits that we can like team up
and do great things because we all do different things and we all of the same mission of helping
the cancer community yeah so all that has made it just like I can't believe I get to work on it each
day yeah you know I feel so grateful that it's what I get to do that's awesome tell me a little bit
about like the user site so someone listening in wants to set up a gift registry like what is
that process look like for them if you go to we got this data work right on the home page you
can either find a registry or start one if you scroll the bottom there's like videos walking
through it but it's very intuitive if you want to start one you just hit start a registry you sign
up and there's a couple ways that you can pull things in from websites you could literally just
copy and paste in the URL to the product that you want there's also a grabber tool it'll
explain how to use but essentially that set up so that like I said any online retailer you can
register for a big thing that I've heard that I try to really reinforce and I feel like is something
we need to normalize is a lot of people feel really comfortable registering for things like
wigs or wheelchairs or barf bags right like things that fall into the stereotypes the cancer
but like people want to help us and I think it's really important that people also register for
like date nights and hunter tickets and you know if you need funds for babysitters you can
utilize it just like a go find me too so you can link your checking account to get donations directly
to you so it's kind of like everything in one spot that money doesn't come to us at all it goes
directly to their account so register for anything you need I highly encourage people to do
all the things that will like make them more comfortable bring them or joy like that's what
keeps us living and then if you're on the supporter side or if you're starring your own
registry and you want to see what others look like if you click find a registry you can look
into different areas like we could look near us in California you know things like that you can
also search names or if you select let us find a driver for you it will randomly populate 20 registries
every time that's clicked so it's not an alphabetical order anything like that because we don't
want a favor any registry over another but as long as your registry's public you'll pop up and
you can see other scenarios like I've had my friend Jill from colleges with her recently and she was
like yeah I looked on and like this girl live not too far away from me had like a handful of
things in her registry so I just like bought it all for her and she's like she's like I felt like
so good you know and she got to like make you know the few things that that she needed so
yeah I think that's crazy I love that you're that you're also encouraging it's it doesn't
have to be something specifically for cancer it can just be something in your life that you know
that would make you happy or that would be additive to your day to day so I think that's really
that's really great so I want to know a little bit about like where do you like what's the future like
where do you see this like expanding into like how big do you want this to be?
Yeah I'm not one to do you think small but yeah I see a big I see you know big picture
it being a registry for the hard times you know not just cancer I try to remind myself that Amazon
started selling books so you know let's like perfect something and and move forward with it I just
almost done with my book we finished the first draft of the manuscript for it some really excited
about that I have personal thank you so I'm actually launching pre-sales for that and October
I bet you can guess why it's a good month for people to listen so I figured that was a good
timing I'm really really passionate on a personal level of really my own personal mission of redefining
success so I really feel like redefining what it means to beat cancer is what I'm really
living to do and if we don't have a cure for metastatic breast cancer in our lifetime getting to do
what we do and live life and make the impact that we make like we're beating cancer every day and
I hope that people know that you know and not people having it's not just cancer right cancer
plug that in with any other thing that we go through in life so the book and speaking and really
spreading that message is a huge goal of mine over you know this time I'm really doing that too
so that I don't need to pay myself through the non-profit you know rather have the corporations
fund me so I can give everything back yeah and then with the non-profit and with we got this we
from not dead yet fast since then we've doubled in registries and we have a thousand registries now
I hope that that exponentially grows my next goal is 10,000 you know not going like one two five
or join 10 and I hope that I hope that people don't have to use it but I know that a lot of people
unfortunately do and I really hope that this becomes the norm like you get diagnosed and while
your husband's there breathing into a paper bag you get this resource you know that at least
can like make your lives a little bit easier and more comfortable and not make you feel alone
and the mission statement like you mentioned you know our mission is building a community of
giving and receiving that helps cancer drivers and their supporters live their best lives and it's
not just about the gift giving it's what that does absolutely I think that's amazing and I think
you know if you're listening in and like you're looking for a way to support someone like
go find me obviously it's great but like this is a really unique and specific opportunity to be able
to help in this way and I think that's really something that you know people should look into
and something that's a little unique about us versus like if you have a go find me I mean if you do
you can utilize the same features on our site so you can take donations but you can also register
for any products and services you need but also reach out to us and we'd be happy to promote your
so we do registries of the week we promote them through our newsletters a lot of times non-profits
and other companies can't do that it's just there's so many go find me is but it's our thing so we
can do it so you know feel free to email us anytime you know info at we got this dot org or
message us on Instagram and we would love to showcase there's a friend Megan who I actually met her
because I was doing a little giveaway for the magic castle and it was for a child's
a cancer awareness month which we're in and we had a child thrive or win and she messaged me and
she's like I know she's like I'm the one with cancer I have melanoma and I was diagnosed the day
that I found out I was pregnant and she's like my son's been with me a hundred percent of the way
he would love to go the castle and so I mean I get chills talking about like how was I
saying that we had a blast we went her and her husband and her son it was amazing and unfortunately
she's dealing with some new brain mats now and recurrence and you know we helped her out with
setting up the registry and helped her her husband did it with her and in her friend Katie and
who's my melanoma world if you follow her on Instagram she's great has great info and we set that up
we put as a registry the week we promoted it and within the week she got over seven thousand
dollars donated and all the things in the registry and it's just letting people know you know
those times are so important yeah absolutely that's awesome well thank you so much for sharing
all those stories with us and thank you so much a list that we're being here you're strength and
drive is honestly so inspiring and I'm so grateful for you for sharing your knowledge and
insights of us today well likewise thanks much for having me and for doing what you're doing
and spreading awareness it matters a lot thanks for listening to the other C word hosted by
Bismal Alji new episodes drop my days connect with me on socials at Bismalji and let's all learn
grow and inspire each other