What's your ism? I'm K. Monday at Communications Coach and I want to help you find your ism.
When I was young, a catiasm was a term used by my family when I got a word wrong.
Now being dyslexic, this used to make me feel really embarrassed and I used to shy away from speaking up,
afraid that I'd say another catiasm. If only I knew then that actually my ism was my quirk,
my uniqueness and my superpower that would later become my career.
I believe life is about finding our ism, the thing that makes us unique.
And now these isms are often found in the stories we shy away from,
but actually are ones that we should probably lean more into.
I found my ism through my challenges, my journey and my story.
Now let me help you find yours.